<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="6"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Unit




                1






           Lesson


                5






          Spark The Challenge!


          Spinning into Inclusion











                                         Ready, Set, Learn!



                                         You will be able to:

                                            •  Build a simple circuit to power a motor and make the
                                               merry-go-round move.

                                            •  Describe how their motorized merry-go-round works
                                               using the ideas of motion and electricity.
                                            •  Identify problems they faced while building and explain
                                               how they solved them.

                                            •  Design a safe and inclusive merry-go-round that can be
                                               used by all children, including those with disabilities.
                                            •  Use graphs and data to compare how fast the merry-go-
                                               round moves and how safe it is.



















                                                                                                            31]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Laila: “The merry-go-round is hard to push. How can we make it move easier?”

          Adam: “What if something pushes it for us?”

          Khaled: “Like a machine?”

          Ms. Sara: “Great idea! What kind of machine?”

          Adam: “Maybe one that uses electricity?”

          Laila: “Like a motor!”

          Ms. Sara: “Great idea! Now let’s think—how can we make it easy and safe for Khaled to ride
          too?”


            Let’s

            Think!



          Why should the merry-go-round move on its own?

                 Because it’s more fun to ride!
                 Because it would be too hard to push if someone in a wheelchair is on it.

                 Because it can spin faster by itself!









          32]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[What can we add to the merry-go-round so all kids can play — even kids who use
          wheelchairs?

























                                  Figure 17: A red and blue merry-go-round with yellow
                                            bars for kids to hold while playing.
                 A ramp so they can get on easily

                 A seat with a seatbelt to stay safe

                 Just bright lights
                 A safe spot to rest their feet

                 A space where a wheelchair can fit

            Explorer’s

            Toolkit





                DIY Lab

          Let’s build a tiny electric path! Use a battery, some wires, a small motor, and a switch.
          Watch what happens when you connect them — can you make the motor spin?








                                                                              Battery


                                                                                     Wires




                              Dc Motor                                              Switch





                                                Figure 18: Electric circuit.


                                                                                                            33]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Screen Lessons

          Watch the video to learn more about how electric circuits work.
                https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HOFp8bHTN30





                                                  Hey flriends
                                                  let’s wrap up!




          An electric circuit is like a little road that helps
          electricity travel from the battery to other parts like
          lights or motors.
          When the electricity moves through the wires,
          it helps the motor turn and make things move — like
          our merry-go-round!

          So, the motor is what makes the merry-go-round spin
          all by itself, without someone pushing it!



            Assessment






                   Apprentice

          Draw something at school that uses a motor. Tell how the motor helps it move or work.







































          34]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Builder

          Make a motor and button circuit on smart pad.


                               1              2             3              4             5


                                      A
                                                                               BUSH BUTTON
                               6             7              8             9              10
                                                                        SHORT CIRCUIT

                                                                               DC MOTOR
                               11            12             13            14             15
                                      C                                           D
                               Figure 19: Motor and button circuit displayed on a smart pad.



                Showcase

          Let's make an electric merry-go-round so all kids can play!

          Make sure to:
            •  Leave wide space for wheelchairs

            •  Use a motor to make it move









































                              Figure 20: A DIY electric merry-go-round model with space for
                                        wheelchairs and a motor to make it move.








                                                                                                            35]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Great job on your design!







          Now let’s go back to the EDP steps.It’s
          time to move to the Create part and add
          this.                                                                                  Name:  Ask
                                                                                                 Project:
                                                                                                           Imagine

                                                                                                   Plan

                                                                                                           Create
                Now I Can                                                                         Improve
                Build a simple circuit to power a motor and make the
                merry-go-round move.                                                                   

                Explain how the motorized merry-go-round works using
                ideas of motion and electricity.                                                       

                Talk about the problems I faced while building and how I solved them.                  
                Design a safe merry-go-round that all kids, including those with
                disabilities, can use.                                                                 
                Use graphs and data to show how fast the merry-go-round moves
                and how safe it is.                                                                    





                 Unit Glossary




                   Keyword                                           Definition



                                         Making sure everyone can use and enjoy something, no
          Accessibility                  matter what they can or cannot do.



                                         They have length and width, but no thickness.
          2D shapes
                                         You can draw them on paper!


                                         They have length, width, and height.
          3D shapes
                                         You can hold them in your hands!


                                         A ramp that goes around in a circle — fun and helpful too
          A spiral ramp                  It makes it easier to go up slowly



          Electricity                    Electricity is a kind of energy that makes things work.




          36]]></page></pages></Search>