<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="48"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[But what happens if a lamp breaks or a component is

                   disconnected?
























                   In a series circuit, if a lamp breaks or a component is disconnected,
                   the circuit is broken, and all the components stop working at the
                   same time.

                   So, Series circuits are useful if you want a warning that one of the
                   components in the circuit has failed. They also use less wiring than
                   parallel circuits.






                   Parallel circuits
                   The components are connected in multiple branches, forming
                   separate paths for the electric current to ﬂow In parallel circuits
                   different components are connected on different branches of the
                   wire.
                   Meaning that the electric current has more than one path to ﬂow
                   in the same circuit.






























           Level 02 - Electricity - Lesson 03]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[What happens if a lamp breaks or a component is

                   disconnected?




























                   In a parallel circuit, if a lamp breaks or a component is
                   disconnected from one parallel wire, the components on different
                   branches keep working.
                   So, Parallel circuits are useful if you want components to continue
                   to work, even if one component has failed. This is why our homes
                   are wired up with parallel circuits.







                       https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RQ3djos_LY8



                                                                                        Scan Here!







                   Workshop








                       You can practice on this link:
                       https://phet.colorado.edu/sims/html/circuit-construction-ki
                       t-dc/latest/circuit-construction-kit-dc_en.html
                                                                                        Scan Here!









           Level 02 - Electricity - Lesson 03]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[level

                                                                                                02

                 LESSON 4                                                                  Electricity






                OHM’S LAW













































































           Level 02 - Electricity - Lesson 04]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Have you ever thought about how to calculate the

                   current owing in the circuit?





























                   Ohm’s law is one of the most popular and important laws that
                   helps us deﬁne the relationship between the most basic elements
                   of power which are voltage, current, and resistance.





                   Resistance

                   Resistance (R) is a measure of the opposition to current ﬂow in an
                   electrical circuit.
                   Measured in ohms.



                   Current

                   Current is the ﬂow of electric charge carriers such as electrons.
                   Electrical current ﬂows from negative to positive points.
                   Measured in ampere (A).



                   Voltage

                   Voltage is the pressure from an electric circuit’s power source that
                   pushes energized electrons (current) through a running loop,
                   allowing them to perform work like illuminating a light.
                   It is measured in Volt.












           Level 02 - Electricity - Lesson 04]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[What is Ohm’s law?


                   Ohm’s law states that the current through a conductor between
                   two points is directly proportional to the voltage across the two
                   points. Ohm’s law formula is written as;








                   V     I
                   Therefore, V = RI where R is a
                   constant called resistance.

                   R depends on the dimensions of the
                   conductor, and on the material of the
                   conductor. Its unit is Ohm (Ω).










                   Ohm’s Law formula

                   Ohm’s law can be demonstrated in a mathematical form:




                                                      V = IR








































           Level 02 - Electricity - Lesson 04]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Where:



                    Quantity     Ohm's Law      Unit of measure    Role in circuits
                                 symbol         (abbreviation)

                    Voltage           V         Volt (V)           Pressure that triggers electron ﬂow

                    Current           I         Ampere, amp (A)    Rate of electron ﬂow


                    Resistance        R         Ohm (Ω)            Flow inhibitor




                   If two of these values are known, you can use Ohm's Law to
                   calculate the third. Just modify the pyramid as follows:



















                   Example 1:


                   Voltage (E) and resistance (R) are known, calculate the current.




























                   What is the current in the circuit?

                   I = E/R = 12V/6Ω = 2A.







           Level 02 - Electricity - Lesson 04]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Example 2:

                   Voltage (E) and current (I) are known. Calculate the resistance R.





























                   What is the resistance created by the lamp?

                   R = E/I = 24V/6A = 4Ω







                   Example 3:

                   Current (I) and resistance (R) are known. What is the voltage?



























                   What is the voltage in the circuit?

                   E = I x R = (5A)(8Ω) = 40 V








           Level 02 - Electricity - Lesson 04]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[AVOmeter – Multimeter


























                   AVO meter stands for A – ampere, V – volt, O – ohm meter. It is also
                   known as a multimeter. Avometer or multimeter is a tester that is
                   used to measure electric current, the potential difference between
                   two points in a circuit, and also measures resistance in a circuit.


                   It consists of a display screen, a dial, or buttons to select the type
                   of measurement, and two probes (red and black) that are used to
                   make contact with the electrical component being measured.








                   Measuring Voltage

                   To measure voltage, connect the
                   avometer’s probes to the
                   appropriate points in the circuit.
                   Select the voltage range suitable for
                   the expected measurement and
                   read the displayed value on the
                   avometer’s scale or digital screen.







                   Measuring Current

                   When measuring current, the
                   avometer is placed in series with
                   the circuit.










           Level 02 - Electricity - Lesson 04]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Measuring Resistance

                   To measure resistance, disconnect
                   the component from the circuit or
                   power source. Connect the
                   avometer’s probes to the
                   component’s terminals and set the
                   avometer to the resistance
                   measurement mode. Read the
                   displayed resistance value on the
                   scale or digital screen.











                   Here are the steps to use an Avo meter:




                   1.  Select the type of measurement: The dial or buttons on the Avo
                      meter allow you to select the type of measurement you want to
                      make, such as voltage, current, or resistance.


                   2. Connect the probes: Depending on the type of measurement you
                      are making, you will need to connect the probes to different parts
                      of the circuit. For example, to measure voltage, you would connect
                      the red probe to the positive side of the component being
                      measured and the black probe to the negative side.

                   Note: the black probe is always connected to the com hole of the Avometer.


                   3. Take the measurement: Once the probes are connected, you can
                      take the measurement by reading the value on the display screen.
                      Make sure you are reading the correct units and range.

























           Level 02 - Electricity - Lesson 04]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Some tips to keep in mind while using an Avo meter:


                   •   Always make sure the probes are connected correctly before
                       taking a measurement.
                   •   Be careful not to touch the probes while taking a measurement,
                       as this can cause inaccurate readings or even damage the Avo
                       meter.
                   •   Use the correct range and units for the measurement you are
                       taking to ensure accurate results.
                   •   Always turn off the Avometer after use to conserve the battery.




                   Workshop 1
















































                   Workshop 2




                   Add short circuits
                   workhop for sc.







           Level 02 - Electricity - Lesson 04]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[level

                                                                                                02

                 LESSON 1                                                                  Mechatronics






                GEARS













































































           Level 02 - Mechatronics - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Have you ever wondered how do cars move?


                   When you push the fuel pedal the car moves, when the pedal is
                   pushed harder it moves at a higher speed.

                   Thanks to the gearbox inside the car.























                   What are the gears?
                   Gears are mechanisms that mesh together via teeth and are used
                   to transmit rotary motion from one shaft to another. Geared
                   devices can change the speed, torque, and direction of a power
                   source.


                   Gears are deﬁned by two important items: radius and number of
                   teeth. They are typically mounted, or connected to other parts, via
                   a shaft or base.






















                   When a large gear is connected with a small one, the smaller gear
                   will rotate faster than the bigger one. Turning the big gear slowly
                   will require less energy than it would rotate the small one quickly;
                   so, by using gear, there is saving of energy and making work
                   easier.






           Level 02 - Mechatronics - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Three basics, we should know to understand how gears
                   transmit speed and torque.



                   Rotational velocity
                       is the velocity of an object rotating around an axis.




                   Torque
                       is a rotating force produced by a motor. The more torque
                       the motor produces, the greater is its ability to perform
                       work



                   Power

                       is how rapidly work is accomplished.




                   Power equals rotational velocity multiplied by the torque





                   So, the power-driven to any of
                   the gears is either translated to
                   torque or rotational velocity.

                   when two gears mesh together,
                   power is applied to one of them
                   and thus transmitted to the
                   other.


                   the bigger gear will translate this power to large torque at the
                   expense of the speed (high torque low speed), while the smaller
                   gear will translate such power to high speed and low torque.



                   That's why cars need gearboxes. To begin with, a car needs a huge amount of
                   force and very little speed to get it moving, so the driver uses the biggest gear.

                   Once the car's going, the driver switches to a smaller gear. More of the engine's
                   power switches to making speed and the car goes faster.

                   The driver uses the gearshift to make the engine generate more force or more
                   speed depending on whether hill-climbing power, acceleration from a standstill,
                   or pure speed is needed.








           Level 02 - Mechatronics - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Why do we must press on a clutch before changing gears?


                   In practice, changing gears means meshing different sized gear
                   wheels together, but you can't do that while the gearbox is
                   transmitting power from the engine at high speed.

                   That's why you need to press a car's clutch pedal before changing
                   gears, which disengages the engine's input from the gearbox.



























                The gear-box inside the car has dierent types of gears


                   Spur gears

                   spur gears are a type of cylindrical gear, with shafts that are
                   parallel, and teeth that are straight and oriented parallel to the
                   shafts. They’re the simplest and most common type of gear – easy
                   to manufacture and suitable for a wide range of applications. The
                   spur gears are typically used for lower-speed applications,
                   although they can be used at almost any speed.





























           Level 02 - Mechatronics - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Helical gears

                   Helical gears are one type of cylindrical
                   gear where the teeth are curved
                   compared to spur gears (straight teeth),
                   properly designed helical gears can
                   have a larger total contact ratio which
                   can improve vibration and noise.





                   Worm gear


                   A worm gear is a gear consisting of a
                   shaft with a spiral thread that engages
                   with and drives a toothed wheel.


                   It changes the rotational movement by
                   90 degrees.





                   Bevel gear

                   Bevel gears are gears where the axes of
                   the two shafts intersect.


                   Bevel gears are most often mounted on
                   shafts that are 90 degrees apart but can
                   be designed to work at other angles as
                   well.




                   Rack and pinion gears

                   A rack and pinion are a type of linear
                   actuator that comprises a circular gear
                   engaging a linear gear, which operates
                   to translate rotational motion into linear
                   motion.


                   Driving the pinion into rotation causes
                   the rack to be driven linearly. Driving
                   the rack linearly will cause the pinion to
                   be driven into a rotation.



                                                                             https://www.youtube.
                                                                             com/watch?v=edZnq
                                                                             d638-w
                                                                                                  Scan Here!


           Level 02 - Mechatronics - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Idler gear

                   An idler-wheel is a gear that serves only to transmit rotation from
                   one shaft to another, in applications where it is undesirable to
                   connect them directly. Also, it is placed between a driving and a
                   driven gear to transfer motion without change of direction or gear
                   ratio

































                                       https://mechanicalbase.com/what-is-idl
                                       er-gear-why-it-is-important/

                                                                          Scan Here!



                   A gear train can include two gears or more. Gears in between the
                   drive gear and the driven gear are called passive gears.
































           Level 02 - Mechatronics - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[level

                                                                                                02

                 LESSON 2                                                                  Mechatronics








                PULLEY & BELTS











































































           Level 02 - Mechatronics - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[What Is Pulley?


                   Pulleys are simply a collection of one or more wheels over which
                   you loop a rope to make it easier to lift things. Pulley is used
                   singles or in combination to transmit energy & motion.
                   For example, instead of pushing a load up, you can attach it to a
                   rope and pulley above you and pulldown to move it up.





















                   Mechanical advantage of pulley

                   Using multiple pulleys decreases the amount of force necessary to
                   move an object by increasing the amount of rope used to raise the
                   object. The mechanical advantage (MA) of a pulley system is equal
                   to the number of ropes supporting the movable load.












































           Level 02 - Mechatronics - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Types of pulleys






                       Fixed pulley

                       It is stationary, meaning that it
                       cannot be moved. A ﬁxed pulley is
                       used to redirect the force in a rope
                       A ﬁxed pulley has a mechanical
                       advantage of 1.









                       Movable pulley

                       It has an axle that is "free" to
                       move in space. A movable pulley is
                       used to transform forces. A
                       movable pulley has a mechanical
                       advantage of 2. That is, if one end
                       of the rope is anchored, pulling on
                       the other end of the rope will
                       apply a doubled force to the
                       object attached to the pulley.











                       Compound pulley

                       it is a combination ﬁxed and
                       movable pulley system.













                Remember gears are also used to transmit power








           Level 02 - Mechatronics - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[What is the dierence between gears and pulleys?






                    A gear is a toothed machine part,
                    such as a wheel, that meshes with
                    another toothed part to transmit
                    motion or to change speed or
                    direction.





                    However, they are not suitable
                    when shafts are distant, they
                    require lubrication due to the
                    friction that occurs during contact
                    between the teeth. Gears have no
                    ﬂexibility.
                    A pulley is a wheel with a grooved
                    rim in which a rope can run in
                    order to change the direction or
                    point of application of a force
                    applied to the rope







                    They are suitable for transmitting power between 2 different shafts
                    when pulleys are attached to chains or belts. The pulley system is
                    much ﬂexible than the gear system.

































           Level 02 - Mechatronics - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Pulley and belt





                    The belt drive can also be used to change the speed of rotation,
                    either up or down, by using different sized pulleys.


                    Belt drives transfer movement from one rotating pulley to
                    another, each held on a shaft. Shafts and pulley wheels can be
                    made out of any material, whereas pulley belts are generally
                    made from a soft, ﬂexible material such as rubber.































                    In a pulley system, the belt can either drive the pulleys normally
                    in one direction or the belt may be cross belt , so that the
                    direction of the driven shaft is reversed.

































           Level 02 - Mechatronics - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Idler pulley


                    The idler pulley is a common part that's found on the majority of
                    the vehicles on the road. Its primary function is to provide tension
                    and guide the engine drive belt.




                   Real-life applications on pulleys



                   • Elevator
                      Elevators work via a powerful electronic pulley system. Elevators
                      make use of a system of several pulleys and counterweights to
                      provide the lift system with both power and safety.







                       https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B6usgjKMXz0


                                                                                        Scan Here!







                   Have you ever seen a Lat pulldown machine in the gymnastic center?

                   • Lat pull down























                      Lat pulldown machine is simply a pulley connected to a rope the
                      rope is connected to weights from a side and to handle from the
                      other side.








           Level 02 - Mechatronics - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Pulleys with belts in cars


                    There are several belts in a car system. The serpentine is one of
                    the important belts in a car The motor makes the serpentine belt
                    spin. Serpentine belt I connected to several pulleys that are
                    responsible for running car devices.

                    When the serpentine belt spins, it powers all the engine devices
                    including, the power steering pump, water pump, alternator, and
                    air conditioning as well.





































                    Note: An alternator is a device that converts mechanical energy into AC electrical energy.































           Level 02 - Mechatronics - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[level

                                                                                                02

                 LESSON 1                                                                     Arduino






                ARDUINO






                BOARDS





































































           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Have you ever played with a remote-controlled car or
                   robot or used a remote control to change the channel on
                   a TV?



                   An Arduino board is like a special kind of remote control
                   that you can program to do all sorts of things! What kind
                   of cool gadgets or machines would you like to be able to
                   control with your own custom-made  remote?"



                   The Main Idea


                   With Arduino, you can build robots, make music, create games,
                   and much more. It is a fun way to learn about electronics and
                   programming, and it can help you turn your ideas into real things
                   that you can see and touch.

                   Arduino is a tool that helps people create electronic devices that
                   can do different things. It is a microprocessor “controller “ like a
                   computer that can read information from the world around it via
                   sensors  like a temperature sensor and then do something in
                   response, like switch on an Ac or enable a ﬁre ﬁghting system.













































           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Arduino consists of two parts; a printed circuit board and
                   a program that tells the Arduino what to do.



                   On the printed circuit board you can attach dierent
                   types of sensors then control them through writing and
                   uploading a code in a software program called 'Arduino
                   IDE'   Arduino’s development environment.





                                                     Arduino








                           1. Arduino board                                2. Arduino IDE





















                       Sensors and switches are                      Program the board to take its
                     connected to the controller to                inputs and make decisions based
                           give it information                       on the information it receives.






























           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[1. Arduino board



                   What's on the board?

                   There are many varieties of Arduino boards that can be used for
                   different purposes. Some boards look a bit different from the one
                   below, but most Arduino boards have the majority of these
                   components in common:

































                   Power (USB / Barrel Jack)


                   Every Arduino board needs a way to be connected to a power
                   source. The Arduino UNO can be powered from a USB cable
                   coming from your computer or a power supply that is terminated
                   in a barrel jack.

                   The USB connection is also how you will load code onto your
                   Arduino board.






                   NOTE
                   Do NOT use a power supply greater than 20 Volts as you will overpower (and
                   thereby destroy) you’re Arduino. The recommended voltage for most Arduino
                   models is between 6 and 12 Volts.












           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Pins     (Digital, Analog, 5V& 3.3V, GND)


                   The pins on your Arduino are the places where you connect wires
                   to construct a circuit.




                   Digital:

                   •  Across from the analog pins are the digital pins (0 through 13
                      on the UNO). These pins can be used for both digital input (like
                      telling if a button is pushed) and digital output (like powering
                      an LED).


                   Analog

                   •  The area of pins under the ‘Analog In’ label (A0 through A5 on
                      the UNO) is Analog In pins. These pins can read the signal
                      from an analog sensor (like a temperature sensor) and convert
                      it into a digital value that we can read.



                   5V & 3.3V
                   •  As you might guess, the 5V pin supplies 5 volts of power, and
                      the 3.3V pin supplies 3.3 volts of power. Most of the simple
                      components used with the Arduino run off of 5 or 3.3 volts.



                   GND
                   •  Short for ‘Ground’. There are several GND pins on the Arduino,
                      any of which can be used to ground your circuit.









                  Reset Button


                   The Arduino has a reset button. Pushing it will temporarily
                   connect the reset pin to ground and restart any code that is
                   loaded on the Arduino.

















           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[2. Arduino IDE



                   Selecting Arduino board

                   Before you start, select an Arduino board because different boards
                   have different features and capabilities that may be necessary for
                   a particular project.












































































           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[COM port


                   The COM port   allows communication between the
                   microcontroller on the Arduino board and the Arduino IDE. Before
                   uploading the code, the com port must be selected ﬁrst.



































                  Start coding


                   The coding screen is divided into two blocks. The setup is
                   considered as the preparation block, while the loop is considered
                   as the execution block. It is shown below:



































           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[NOTE
                   Programming statements end with a semicolon.






                  Blinking Led Code         (Beginner level)


                   How can you make an alarm system with ﬂashing lights every
                   second without manually pressing on the switch every second?



                   1.  Open the Arduino IDE on your computer.

                   2.  Connect your Arduino board to your computer using a
                       USB cable.


                   3.  Select the correct board type and port in the "Tools"
                       menu of the IDE.

                   4.  In the "File" menu, select "New" to create a new sketch.










           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Type the following code into the new sketch window:



                                                                   pinMode() function is a built-in
                    void setup() {                                 function in that is used to conﬁgure
                                                                   the mode of a speciﬁc pin on the
                    pinMode(13, OUTPUT);                           Arduino board.
                    }
                    void loop() {                                  digitalWrite() is an in-built function
                    digitalWrite(13,HIGH);                         in the Arduino. It is used to write a
                                                                   HIGH or LOW value to a digital pin
                    delay(1000);
                    digitalWrite(13,LOW);

                    delay(1000);                                   The delay() function in Arduino is
                    }                                              used to pause the program for a
                                                                   speciﬁed amount of time, speciﬁed
                                                                   in milliseconds.



                   This code will turn on and off the built-in LED on the Arduino
                   board in a one-second interval.





                   After writing the code:

                   1.  Verify the code by clicking on the "Verify" button or
                       selecting "Sketch" > "Verify/Compile" from the menu.
                       Make sure there are no errors in the code.

                   2.  Upload the code to the Arduino board by clicking on the
                       "Upload" button.


                   3.  Once the code is uploaded, the built-in LED on the
                       Arduino board should start blinking in a one-second
                       interval.






























           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Blinking led     (intermediate level)



                   Materials Needed:

                       •   Arduino board and USB cable
                       •   Breadboard
                       •   LED
                       •   Jumper wires
                       •   Resistor



































                  Challenge      (advanced level)


                   Now, let’s apply what we’ve learned to make a trafﬁc light.

































           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[level

                                                                                                02

                 LESSON 2                                                                     Arduino







                RING THE BELL












































































           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[How do computers store values?


                  How computers remember our passwords every time we
                  entre it?




                   Imagine we have a set of drawers. Each
                   drawer contains different objects of the
                   same type. This is the same as variables.
                   Thus, we name a 'Variable'(the drawer)
                   then store a value (the object) in it.







                  The Main Idea
                   In a computer program, a variable is a container that has a name
                   and stores information which can be changed or reused over and
                   over again. It uses computer memory to store these variables.























































           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[For Example


                   In a game, the current score (variable) of the player is stored; we
                   would add 1 to the variable whenever the player gains a point, and
                   subtract a point if he loses.


                   To assign a variable as the score;

                   Type of variable     name = value
                                int          score = 100.





                   What is int? What are the variable types?

                        “Int” is a data type used in computer programming to represent
                        integer. An integer is a whole number that can be positive,
                        negative, or zero.

                   We have many data types, these are the types of data that the
                   programming world use and understand to help the program know
                   what to do with the variable, let's know some of them.





                   Data types


                   Integer – int:                                      Float – ﬂoat:

                   It holds only whole numbers                         Numeric data type for
                   (-500 ,0 ,770). As the example                      numbers with fractions
                   of the score value mentioned                        (-77.5,77.8).
                   before.
                                                                       >> ﬂoat x = -0.99;
                   >> int x= 7;





























           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[Character – char:                                  String – string:

                   Holds only a single letter as                      Sequence of characters,
                   ('a', 'r', 't').                                   digits, or symbols—always
                                                                      treated as text ( "hello",
                   >> char x= 'b';                                    "+39503d").


                                                                      >> string x= "Jermy";
























                   Where do we create the variables?

                   They are preferred to be created before the setup function, so that
                   all the functions in the program could see the variable, this is called
                   global variable deﬁned in global scope.










                                                                   Global Variable





















                   Now that we have learned variables and its types, let's know what
                   we will control today!







           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[Ring the bell code (beginner level)

                   Can you provide an Arduino code that makes a bell ring when a
                   push button is pressed?


                   1.  Open the Arduino IDE on your computer.
                   2. Connect your Arduino board to your computer using a USB cable.
                   3. Select the correct board type and port in the "Tools" menu of the IDE.
                   4. In the "File" menu, select "New" to create a new sketch.



                   Sketch the code:
                   Initialize the variables in the global scope, where the entire
                   program will see and use these variables. Two variables are
                   declared; one for the buzzer and one for the pushbutton. The values
                   5 &13 refer to the pins connected in it.


                   int buzzer = 13;
                   int pushbutton=5;





                   In the Setup function, we will set our components as input or
                   output – buzzer and pushbutton.



                   void setup() {                               Buzzer is written in the pin number
                     pinMode(buzzer, OUTPUT);                   because it is declared in the global
                     pinMode(pushbutton,INPUT);                 scope that buzzer = 13,
                   }                                            Same for pushbutton =5.









                   In the loop function, the Arduino wants to know if the button is
                   pressed or not, so it has to read an input through a function called
                   digitalRead()- Reads an input from a deﬁned pin. The value
                   returned from the variable “reading” is either 0 or 1- LOW or HIGH.




                   void loop() {                                Then declare a variable that reads
                   int reading =                                the value each loop this is called
                   digitalRead(pushbutton);                     local scope, where this value is not
                                                                seen in the other functions.











           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[Start to compare and ask is the button clicked or not? If it is clicked
                   then the buzzer must beep if it is not then the buzzer remains
                   silent.


                   This is called if statement – it is one of the conditional statements
                   in programming.


                       if ( reading=w1)
                     {
                       digitalWrite( buzzer,HIGH);
                     }
                     else {
                          digitalWrite( buzzer,LOW);
                     }
                   }




                   After writing the code

                    1.  Verify the code by clicking on the "Verify" button or selecting
                       "Sketch" > "Verify/Compile" from the menu. Make sure there are
                       no errors in the code.


                    2.  Connect the circuit as follows:

                       Materials Needed:
                       •  Arduino board and USB cable.
                       •  Breadboard.
                       •  Buzzer.
                       •  Pushbutton.
                       •  Jumper wires.
                       •  Resistor.

                    3.  Upload the code to the Arduino board by clicking on the
                        "Upload" button.


                    4.  Once the code is uploaded, try to press on the pushbutton now.




                    Challenge:   Open the door


                    Can you add a motor to your circuit so that after pressing the
                    push button the motor rotates to open the door?


                    Hint: a motor is a digital Output component.






           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[level

                                                                                                02

                 LESSON 3                                                                     Arduino







                SWITCH CASE




                & SERIAL READ






































































           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 03]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[A)  SWITCH CASE


                   A switch case is a conditional statement that allows a program to
                   evaluate a variable or expression and select one of several
                   different code paths to execute based on the value of that variable
                   or expression.


                   Switch case statement is similar to “if-else “statement but can be
                   more efﬁcient and easier to read for certain cases,  we use it if we
                   have several conditions as “switch” is the conditional statement
                   and “case” is  the  comparative statement were:

                      If it’s TRUE-> the statement of this case is going to be executed
                      then break out of the whole “switch case” statement


                      And if it’s FALSE -> we’ll move to the next case to be compared
                      and so on until whole cases are covered

                      If the whole cases were false and none of the cases’ statements
                      are executed then the execution is going to take place in the
                      “default” statement which doesn’t have a “break”
                      We might have as much cases as we want depending on the
                      project that we work on.














































           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 03]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[Beginner level      (Even and odd detection)


                   The following code is an example on switch case that detects even
                   and odd numbers. If the number saved is even a green LED will be
                   ON and if a the saved number is odd then a red LED will be ON




                   Sketch the code


                   int redled=13;                           We will assign an integer variable that has
                   int greenled=11;                         no value to store the remainder of division
                                                            in it.
                   void setup()                             PS: remember when we said 'Variable'(the
                   {                                        drawer) then store a value (the object) in it,
                   pinMode(redled,OUTPUT);                  here we assigned an empty drawer to store
                   pinMode(greenled,OUTPUT);                any integer object in it.
                   Serial.begin(9600);
                   }
                   void loop()
                   {
                     int b;
                     int num=10;


                     if (num%2=w0)
                     {                                      The percentage (%) sign is used here to
                       b=0;                                 check the remainder of dividing num by 2
                     }                                      then store it in variable b.
                                                            If num is even then the remainder is 0 so
                     else if (num%2~w0)                     b=0. If num is odd then the remainder is a
                     {                                      positive value so b = a positive value.
                        b=num%2;
                     }




































           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 03]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[switch(b)                                Since we can predict the speciﬁc values of b
                   {case 0:                                 from the previous mathematical operations,
                                                            we used the switch case to check the value
                      Serial.print(num);                    of b


                      Serial.println(" is an
                   even value" );
                                                            In case b is equal to zero then num is an
                   digitalWrite(greenled,HIGH               even number. SO a green LED is on, and the
                   );                                       value of num is printed
                      delay (100);

                   digitalWrite(greenled,LOW)
                   ;                                        Break is used to break out (exit) from the
                    break;                                  switch case loop once the case is satisﬁed










                    default :                               In case that none of the previous
                      Serial.print(num);                    mentioned cases has occurred then there’s
                      Serial.println(" is an                a default sequence of instructions should
                   odd value" );                            be executed. According to our workshop in
                                                            case that our num is not even value then it’s
                                                            an odd value.
                   digitalWrite(redled,HIGH);
                      delay (100);

                   digitalWrite(redled,LOW);
                     break;
                    }
                   }































           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 03]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[After sketching the code


                    1.  Verify the code.

                    2. Connect the circuit as follows.
                          Materials Needed:
                          •   Arduino board and USB cable.
                          •   Breadboard.
                          •   2 Resistors.
                          •   RED LED.
                          •   GREEN LED.

                    3. Upload the code to the Arduino board.






























                    Now try to store odd value in num and upload the code again and
                    observe what will happen.
































           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 03]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[A)  Serial.read


                   •  It’s a function of the serial communication library that allows
                      reading data that a user can enter to the serial monitor on
                      Arduino IDE.


                   This is how it works:
                   •  When a user enter a data, this data goes to a receive buffer that
                      accepts all of the entered data waiting to be read.



















                                  BUFFER



                   •  Since we’ve known that the entered data may wait a bit of time
                      in the buffer to be read and processed, you might think what
                      happen if the buffer is already busy with data and cannot
                      accept any further information?


                   •  As an answer of that question there’s another function in the
                      serial communication library that called Serial.availabe() that
                      checks the number of currently stored data in the buffer.


                   •  For example if there are 12 characters are stored in the buffer so
                      “Serial.available” will return 12.


























           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 03]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[Intermediate level       (Controlable trac light)


                   We will control the sequence of lighting of 3 LEDS ON and OFF by
                   a speciﬁc data that we will enter in the serial monitor.
                   If we entered letter ”y” a yellow LED is ON, If we entered letter ”g”
                   a Green LED is ON, and If we entered letter ”r” a red LED is ON.


                   Sketch the code


                   int ledr= 2;                             We will assign an empty integer variable
                   int ledg=3;                              (input) that has no value, to store the data
                                                            that we input in serial monitor in it.
                   int ledy= 4;
                   int input;

                   void setup()
                   {
                     Serial.begin(9600);
                     pinMode(ledr, OUTPUT);
                     pinMode(ledg, OUTPUT);
                     pinMode(ledy, OUTPUT);
                   }




                                                                      First we should check if there’s
                   Serial.begin(9600);                                any available space in the serial
                     pinMode(ledr, OUTPUT);                           buffer. If the available space is
                     pinMode(ledg, OUTPUT);                           more than zero then we can
                                                                      input our data.
                     pinMode(ledy, OUTPUT);
                   }
                   void loop()
                                                                      Now let the serial monitor read
                   {                                                  the data that we input through it
                     if (Serial.available() > 0)                      then store the data in the
                     {                                                variable input.
                       input = Serial.read();


                       switch (input)                                 Since we know the speciﬁc
                       {                                              values of input, we will test it
                         case 'y':                                    through switch case.
                           digitalWrite(ledy, HIGH);
                           delay(500);
                          digitalWrite(ledy, LOW);                    In case input =y: Turn yellow LED
                           break;                                     ON for while then OFF.
















           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 03]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[case 'g':                                          In case input =g: Turn green LED
                           digitalWrite(ledg, HIGH);                  ON for while then OFF.
                          delay(500);
                          digitalWrite(ledg, LOW);
                           break;
                                                                      In case input =r: Turn red LED ON
                         case 'r':                                    for while then OFF.
                           digitalWrite(ledr, HIGH);
                          delay(500);
                          digitalWrite(ledr, LOW);
                           break;





                                                                      As a default if none of the
                        default:                                      previous cases is occurred then
                           digitalWrite(ledy, LOW);                   turn all the LEDS OFF
                           digitalWrite(ledg, LOW);
                           digitalWrite(ledr, LOW);
                           break;
                       }
                     }                                                Don’t forget to close all of the
                                                                      loops brackets:
                   }                                                  Switch loop, if condition, then
                                                                      the void loop.











                   After sketching the code


                    1.  Verify the code.

                    2. Connect the circuit as follows.
                        Materials Needed:
                        •  Arduino board and USB cable.
                        •  Breadboard.
                        •  3 Resistors 220 ohm.
                        •  Red, Green, and Yellow LEDS.
















           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 03]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Connection:


                          component         Position                         connection

                          Arduino                                            GND  pin with negative pole
                                                                             in breadboard.


                          Red LED           Put RED LED in pins 18 and       Cathode with a 220 ohm
                                            19 on breadboard                 resistor.
                                                                             Anode with pin2 in arduino.

                                                                             Cathode with a 220 ohm
                          Green LED         Put Green LED in pins 15 and     resistor.
                                            16                               Anode with pin 3 in arduino.

                                                                             Cathode with a 220 ohm
                          Yellow LED        Put Yellow LED in pins 18 and    resistor.
                                            19                               Anode with pin 4 in arduino.

                          Resistors                                          Connect the other terminal
                                                                             of resistor with the negative
                                                                             pole in the breadboard





                    3.  Upload the code to the Arduino board.







                   Advanced level       (Color mixer)


                   Can you make a color mixer that when you enter two colors it
                   mixes them up and give you the result.

                   HINT: you can use RGB to mix up colors





























           Level 02 - Arduino - Lesson 03]]></page></pages></Search>