<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="40"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[NEW EDDITION]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[All rights reserved  no part of this book may be reproduced,
                                stored in a retrieval system, or transmitted in any form or by
                                any means, electronic, mechanical, photocopying, recording or
                                otherwise, without prior written permission of the publishers.]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Index














                level            01             level            02             level            03



                Electricity                     Electricity                     Electricity

                 Lesson 1                       Lesson 1                        Lesson 1
                 Lesson 2                       Lesson 2                        Lesson 2
                 Lesson 3                       Lesson 3                        Lesson 3
                 Lesson 4                       Lesson 4





                Mechatronics                    Mechatronics                    Mechatronics


                 Session 1                      Session 1                       Session 1
                 Session 2                      Session 2                       Session 2





                Design      [Tinker CAD]        Arduino                         Arduino


                 Lesson 1                       Lesson 1                        Lesson 1
                 Lesson 2                       Lesson 2                        Lesson 2
                 Lesson 3                       Lesson 3                        Lesson 3
                 Lesson 4                                                       Lesson 4
                 Lesson 5]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[level

                                                                                                01

                 LESSON 1                                                                  Electricity






                ELECTRICITY





                & CIRCUITS






































































           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 01                                                                 01]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Can you imagine a world where we don't
                          have electricity, no light or switches to

                          turn on, no computers to turn on, no hot
                          water and way more?

                          Electricity is a big oart of our lives, and
                          sometimes we don't enen realize it.


                          let's take a look at what

                          electricty is.




























































                                                           01

           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[What is Electricty?



                   It is a fundamental form of energy observable in positive and
                   negative forms occurs naturally ( as in lightning) or is produced and
                   that is expressed in terms of electric current ow.

                   Electricity is a secondary source od energy, which means it must be
                   created from other forms of energy. With technology, electricity
                   can be generated from dierent sources of energy.


















                                                      Source
                                                           of

                                                      energy
                                                                                      Non-
                     Renewable
                                                                                 renewable
                        energy
                                                                                    energy












                                  Solar Energy                       Fossil Fuel Oil

                                                                                             Coal
                                               Biomass Energy
                  Hydropower Energy


                                    Energy                                      Energy
                                  The fuel of life                             The fuel of life

                                                                 Nuclear
                                                                                           Natural Gas

                     Geothermal Energy   Wind Energy
                  RENEWABLE ENERGY                                    NON-RENEWABLE ENERGY







           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Electric Circuit






                   Can you observe this

                   circuit and explain why the
                   lamp doesn't work?






                   Let's make a simple circuit to know what is a closed circuit.



                   1.  Connect one end of the bulb to the
                       negative end of one battery ( "-" )



                   2.  Attach the other end of the bulb to
                       the positive end of the battery ( "+" )



                       Now what happens?


                       Batteries supply electricity. When they’re connected
                       properly, they ( Power ) things like a ﬂashlight, an alarm
                       clock, a radio... even a robot !





                   WHY DIDN'T THE LIGHT BULB LIGHT UP WHEN YOU CONNECTED IT TO
                   ONE END OF THE BATTERY WITH A BULB?




























           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[What can we do with the electric power …
                   look around you and think.


                   We need a power source that will motivate the ﬂow of the current
                   in the circuit.




                   We can provide a power source in the electric circuit from a battery.



                   Battery

                       A battery converts chemical energy into
                       electrical energy. It is used in a circuit to
                       power other components.
                       Batteries are connected to several
                       components to build an electric circuit.



                   LED
                       It is a component that makes light when
                       electricity ﬂows through it.



                   Wires
                       Jumper wires have connector pins at
                       each end, wires are conductors as they
                       are made of copper which is good
                       conductor of electricity.


                   Resistance

                       A resistor limits the electrical current
                       that ﬂows through a circuit. Resistors
                       are useful as they protect components
                       from burning out.






                   Electrical components change the electrical energy to another form
                   of energy as resistance changes electric energy into thermal energy.










           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Workshop



                   We need a battery, wires, resistors, and LED. Connect them on the
                   smart pad.



                   Steps:


                   1.  Connect the battery's positive end
                      with the LED's positive end (the
                      taller side)



                   2.  Connect the LED's negative end
                      (the shorter side) to a resistor's
                      terminal.


                   3.  Connect the other terminal of the
                      resistor to the battery's negative
                      end.


                   4.  Connect smartpad with your power
                      source using power cable and see
                      what happens.



                   Change the positions of the resistor and the LED with each other
                   and see what happens.



                   What if we want to lighten three LEDs together, can you make it?

































           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[LET'S CONNECT USING OTHER

                   COMPONENTS.




                   Buzzer

                       A buzzer or beeper is an audio
                       signaling device that produces sound
                       when current ﬂows through it.



                   Push-button/ switch

                       Push-buttons and switches work on a
                       simple electric mechanism to activate or
                       deactivate the circuit When pressed.













                   We need a battery, wires, resistors, and LED. Connect them
                   on the smart pad.

                       Connect a buzzer, switch and a resister to close the circuit.

                       The expected output is hearing beeping voice of the buzzer
                       turning the switch on.



































           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[WHO


                   Am I ?








                   Yasmine Yehia


                   From  Egypt,  her  scientiﬁc  research  ultimately  is  to  increase
                   biodiesel fuel in generating electricity.


                   She is the youngest female scientist (used to attend STEM school).
                   Back in  2015,  Yasmine  landed  ﬁrst  place  globally  in  the  "Intel
                   Science  and  Engineering  Competition,  "in  the  Earth  and
                   Environmental Sciences category, with her project entitled
                   "The Potential Strength of Rice Straw."

                   Yasmine's project was around improving cleaning & clearing water
                   sources ﬁrstly, then she shifting it to solving electricity problem and
                   reducing  air  pollution.  She  used  biological  treatments  to  help
                   purifying  water  and  heating  it  by  burning  rice  straw  The
                   competition.







































           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[level

                                                                                                01

                 LESSON 2                                                                  Electricity






                ELECTRICITY





                & ITS TYPES






































































           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Electricity is one of the nest inventions

                        in our lives. Everything and anything that

                        we see runs on one or the other form of
                        electricity.



                        But can you guess the dierence between
                        these two pictures?

















                        There  are  two  main  types  of  electricity,  Static  Electricity,
                        generated by rubbing two or more objects causing to build
                        up friction, Dynamic Electricity, generated by the ﬂow of
                        electrical charge through a conductor across an electrical
                        ﬁeld.





                        Static electricity:

                        is  commonly  experienced  during  dry  weather  or  in
                        environments with low humidity.
                        It  can  be  generated  by  various  means,  such  as  friction
                        between  two  materials,  rubbing  objects  together,  or
                        through the movement of certain materials, like clothing
                        against the skin.





















                                                           01

           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Workshop 1



                   In this workshop we will need:

                    1.  A piece of hard rubber/ Small pieces of paper
                    2.  A glass rod or a plastic ruler rubbed with a cloth.

                   Steps


                      Rub the ruler with the cloth Static electricity will be
                      generated.

                      Bring the charged ruler near to rubber if paper pieces and
                      observe what happens.





















                   Workshop 2



                   When two objects – such as your hair and the balloon –
                   rub together,generates a type of electricity called static
                   electricity.


                    1.  Supercharge Your Balloon With Static Electricity.
                    2.  Put Your Electriﬁed Balloon to Small paper pieces and see
                       What Floats.




                 Dynamic electricity:
                    is a type of electricity that continuously ﬂow from one point
                    to another. The ﬂow of electricity is similar to the ﬂow of a ﬂowing
                    river, so dynamic electricity is called electric current.









           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[level

                                                                                                01

                 LESSON 3                                                                  Electricity






                CONDUCTORS





                & INSULATORS






































































           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 03]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[First let's watch this video…


                       https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PZhe7NOLVhA

                                                                                        Scan Here!




                   1-Conductors



                   Materials that allow electricity to pass through them easily are
                   called electrical conductors.


                   Examples of these materials:

                   1. Metals, such as iron, steel, copper, and aluminum.
                   2. Water also conducts electricity, which is why electrical objects
                      should not be used near water.


                   Examples of metal used in conductors:

                   Electrical objects use metal parts to conduct electricity, such as:

                   1. The copper wires inside electrical leads.
                   2. The metal pins in plugs.
                   3. The metal wire ﬁlaments in light bulbs.



























                                                     In a simple electrical circuit, copper wire is used
                                                     to carry electricity from the energy source
                                                     (such as a battery) to an electrical component
                                                     (such as a lamp, motor, or bell).






                                                           01

           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 03]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[2-insulators




                   Materials that do not allow electricity to pass through them are
                   called electrical insulators.



                   Examples of these materials:

                   1. Plastic.
                   2. Rubber.
                   3. Wood.
                   4. Glass.
                   5. Air is also an insulator.







































                   •   Most electrical objects are made using insulators to keep them safe. Plugs, for
                       example, have plastic cases. Electrical wires are wrapped in plastic, which is
                       ﬂexible as well as insulating.

                   •   The copper wires used in simple electrical circuits are coated in plastic. This
                       prevents electricity from ﬂowing out of the circuit













                                                           01

           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 03]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Workshop



                   Did you know that there are dierent types of  play
                   dough?!



                   There are two types of play dough but what is the
                   difference ?


                   1. Conductive play dough(clayronics) :
                   allow electricity to ﬂow through circuit.


                   2.   Insulating play dough:
                   electricity can't pass through the circuit.









                   But how do we use it to make a circuit?





                       Let's watch this video..

                       https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VcdqBmFETNw

                                                                                        Scan Here!




                   Ok, we need ..
                       Conductive play dough.
                       Leds.
                       Battery.





























           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 03]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[level

                                                                                                01

                 LESSON 4                                                                  Electricity






                MAKE





                A BATTERY






































































           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 04]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Can you imagine a world where all
                          appliances had to be plugged in?


                          Imagine all your toys that


                          move with a wire connected to

                          them.


































































                                                           01

           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 04]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[A battery is a device that converts chemical energy contained
                   within its active materials directly into electric using an
                   electrochemical oxidation-reduction (redox) reaction.

                   This type of reaction involves the transfer of electrons from one
                   material to another via an electric circuit.








































                   A chemical reaction between the metals and the electrolyte frees
                   more electrons in one metal than it does in the other.

                   The metal that frees more electrons develops a positive charge,
                   and the other metal develops a negative charge.



























                                                           01

           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 04]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Workshop


                   Make a battery out of copper coins.



                   Equipment:
                   1. Copper coins.

                   2. Vinegar.
                   3. Foil and cardboard.


                   Steps:

                   1. Clean the coins by soaking them in           (salt and vinegar) .
                   2. Dry them with a paper towel.

                   3. Cut circles of the clipboard in size of the coins.
                   4. Soak them in vinegar.
                   5. Take some foil and fold it over several times. Draw a circle with the
                       size of the coin. Cut it out.

                   6. Place down a coin put it on top of one of the cardboard discs then
                       add one piece of foil.
                   7. Add another coin on top and keep repeating the process.
                   8. You need to be careful that the foil doesn’t fold down the side and

                       contact any other layers.
                   9. Check the voltage using the AVO meter.
                   10. Fix all the layers using a strip of tape.
                   11. Connect one terminal of a wire to the lower coin and another one

                       to the upper coin.
                   12. Connect the other terminals with a LED, and you will ﬁnd out that
                       the LED will turn on.




























           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Watch this video.


                       https://youtu.be/vIHfUJu3aKo?si=udaW-zjd04DTWN2n

                                                                                        Scan Here!



                   The cardboard soaked in vinegar water serves as
                   the electrolyte between the two terminals.


                   NASA  is  always  working  to  make  ﬂight  safer,  more
                   convenient and more environmentally friendly. Airplanes
                   powered by electricity rather than by burning fuel
                   produce  much  fewer  harmful  emissions,  which  helps

                   protect the environment. This type of propulsion is known
                   as electriﬁed aircraft propulsion.



                   One of NASA’s newest experimental airplanes is the X-57
                   (Maxwell).  This  airplane  is  completely  powered  by
                   batteries.  This  airplane  was  built  to  learn  more  about
                   electriﬁed  aircraft  propulsion.  But,  it  is  just  the  start!
                   Using  what  it  learns  from  the  X-57, NASA is working to
                   build larger passenger-carrying airplanes that are at least
                   partially powered by electricity. The goal is to help reduce
                   emissions drastically over the next 20 years.




































                                                           01

           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 04]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Workshop



                   Assemble a simple battery at home.






















                   Equipment:

                   1. Copper and zinc plates.
                   2. Wires with clamps       (crocodiles) .
                   3. AVO meter.
                   4. LED.
                   5. Plastic cups.
                   6. Sodium chloride.
                   7. Hot water.




                   Steps:

                   A.  Use crocodile clip wires to connect some copper and zinc plates.

                   B.  To prepare a table salt solution:
                       1.  Dissolve 100g of salt in 1L of hot water.
                       2. Pour the solution into cups and lower the “wired” plates into them.
                       3. It is important that each cup contains both a zinc plate and a copper plate.
                       4. Connect a LED, and it will turn on.





                       Watch this video.


                       https://youtu.be/IrgyesPSmSI?si=mI8owbYxkF1WQAEX

                                                                                        Scan Here!


                   In our battery, the zinc plates act as anodes, and the copper plates
                   act as cathodes.







           Level 01 - Electricity - Lesson 04]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[level

                                                                                                01

                 LESSON 1                                                                  Mechatronics






                MECHANICS





                In these lessons you will learn some basic
                concepts of mechanical engineering.




































































           Level 01 - Mechatronics - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Screw & Nut


                   A screw is a special kind of inclined plane. It's basically an inclined
                   plane wrapped around a pole. Screws can be used to lift things or
                   to hold them together.


                   Examples of the screw simple machine include :

                      • swivel chairs.
                      • jar lids.
                      • screws.




                       Watch a video

                       https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e9oGNB1gHt
                       c&list=PL786ED3CB23AE24E8&index=2

                                                                                        Scan Here!





















































           Level 01 - Mechatronics - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Wheel


                   A wheel is most commonly deﬁned as a solid disc or as a circular
                   ring with spokes, designed to turn around a smaller axle (a rod)
                   passing through its center. The wheel and attached axle both turn
                   at the same speed.



                   Wheels and axles are found in many machines where there is a need
                   to control the direction of movement and turning force, such as :


                      • Bicycles.
                      • roller skates.
                      • vehicles.
                                                      Watch a video
                      • helicopters.
                      • shing reels.                 https://www.youtube.com/wat
                      • trolleys.                     ch?v=ByLXZCP4ixc&t=156s
                      • push-chairs.                                                    Scan Here!





















































           Level 01 - Mechatronics - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Wedge


                   A wedge is a simple machine used to split material. It gets thinner
                   at one end that is used to split material such as wood. A knife is an
                   example of a wedge.




                      Watch a video                               Watch a video


                      https://www.youtube.                        https://www.youtube.
                      com/watch?v=aoXnh                           com/watch?v=jtk2V0
                      yY5RTk&t=101s           Scan Here!          M6k3M&t=420s           Scan Here!

















                   Gears


                   A gear is most commonly deﬁned as a toothed wheel; the teeth of a
                   gear prevent slipping. When one gear is engaged with another
                   gear they are said to mesh. When a set of gears work together, they
                   transmit movement and force.


                   Gears are found in many machines where there is a need to control
                   the speed of rotary movement and turning force. Examples include
                   cars, bicycles, old-fashioned egg beaters, tin openers and
                   grandfather clocks.









                      Watch a video

                      https://www.youtube.
                      com/watch?v=aoXnh
                      yY5RTk&t=101s           Scan Here!









           Level 01 - Mechatronics - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Gear train


                   A gear train includes at least two gears that work together to
                   increase torque, increase speed, or change direction. A gear train
                   includes a driver gear and a driven gear. Power is applied directly to
                   the driver gear which causes it to rotate.



























                   Gears Example


                   A lower, easier gear, with the smaller chain ring up front and a
                   larger cog in the back, lets you accelerate faster. This helps you get
                   started from a stop, or when you’re climbing a steep hill. The
                   higher, harder gear (big chain ring, small cog) helps you increase
                   your top speed

































           Level 01 - Mechatronics - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[SIMPLE MACHINES WORKSHEET




                   Which simple machine best represents the object shown?





















                   which simple machine best represents the object shown?























                   which simple machine best represents the object shown?






























           Level 01 - Mechatronics - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[level

                                                                                                01

                 LESSON 2                                                                  Mechatronics




                 INTRODUCTION TO
                MECHANICS





                In these lessons you will learn some basic
                concepts of mechanical engineering.




































































           Level 01 - Mechatronics - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[What Is Force?


                   Have you ever been in the middle of enjoying a scrumptious piece
                   of food, and just as it enters your mouth...splat, it slips out of your
                   hands and falls on the ﬂoor? If so, then you've experienced force.

                   Force happens all around us, all of the time. Force is a push or a pull
                   of an object that causes the object to speed up, slow down, or stay
                   in one place. In other words, a force is what causes an object to
                   move. Friction and gravity are two types of forces that inﬂuence
                   how an object moves. Let's learn more about them.





                      Watch a video

                      https://www.youtube.
                      com/watch?v=7_9fMF
                      Gfy9w                   Scan Here!





                   Push and Pull Forces
                   A push is the force that moves an object away from something, like
                   when you push a plate of Brussels sprouts away in disgust. We use
                   the force of push when we kick a soccer ball, press the gas peddle
                   of a car, push our chair in, and press the buttons on a phone.


                   A push and a pull are
                   opposite forces,
                   meaning they move
                   objects in different
                   directions. Therefore, a
                   pull is the force of
                   bringing an object
                   closer. We use the force                                                   Ball changes direction
                   of a pull when we move
                   our bowl of ice cream
                   closer to us, open a
                   door, or climb up a
                   rope.











           Level 01 - Mechatronics - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[The Force of Friction


                   Friction is the force that acts to slow an object down. Imagine
                   trying to ride your bike through sand. Just thinking about this can
                   make your legs burn from all the hard work. That is because the
                   sand is a type of friction. In other words, it's a force working against
                   your legs as they push against the peddles.






                      Watch a video


                      https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PNDRIicw4E0
                                                                                         Scan Here!



























































           Level 01 - Mechatronics - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[The Force of Gravity


                   Gravity is the pulling of an object towards Earth's center. When a
                   ball is thrown up in the air, it slows down and falls back to the
                   ground. That is because gravity pulls the ball back towards the
                   earth.





                      Watch a video


                      https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ed7rg7MuuEQ
                                                                                     Scan Here!




                   Everything on Earth is
                   inﬂuenced by the force of
                   gravity.























                   Homework



                   Push and Pull Forces in Your Home
                   Consider the objects in your home and ﬁnd ﬁve objects that you
                   exert a push force on and ﬁve objects you exert a pull force on, for
                   a total of ten objects. If a push and a pull force can be exerted on a
                   speciﬁc object you may only use it as an example of push or pull
                   force, not both. If you are having trouble ﬁnding ten objects in
                   your home, consider places and objects around your home as well,
                   for example the park.









           Level 01 - Mechatronics - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Simple machines



                   (pulley – inclined plane – wheel - lever – screw)

                   We use simple machines every day – when we open a door, turn
                   on a tap, open a tin, or ride a bike. Simple machines make it easy
                   for us to do work.




                   Pulley

                   Pulleys are made by looping a rope over one or more wheels. They
                   are often used to lift heavy objects: pulling down on one end of the
                   rope creates an upward pull at the other end.






                      Watch a video

                      https://www.youtube.c
                      om/watch?v=hjFMZek
                      hoXU&list=PL786ED3C
                      B23AE24E8&index=4       Scan Here!





                   Inclined plane

                   An inclined plane is one of the six types of simple machines. It's
                   exactly what it sounds like - it is a plane (a ﬂat surface) that is
                   inclined, or slanted, at an acute angle. Inclined planes connect a
                   lower level to a higher level; they make work easier.

                   Inclined planes have been around for thousands of years. They
                   were even used to make the building of the ancient pyramids
                   easier! Today, inclined planes continue to be a big part of our
                   world.







                      Watch a video

                      https://www.youtube.c
                      om/watch?v=ByLXZCP
                      4ixc&t=122s
                                              Scan Here!







           Level 01 - Mechatronics - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[Lever


                   A lever is most commonly deﬁned as a rod or arm that tilts around
                   a pivot, also called a fulcrum, to produce useful motion. The load is
                   moved by the effort (a push or pull) used to make the lever tilt
                   about the pivot.


                   Levers are found in many machines, such as wheelbarrows, oars,
                   rakes, nutcrackers, tweezers, screwdrivers, snow shovels,
                   hammers, bottle openers, light switches, staplers, crowbars,
                   scissors and see-saws.






                      Watch a video


                      https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D23IZxYaLHs&list=PL7
                      86ED3CB23AE24E8&index=2
                                                                                       Scan Here!




















































           Level 01 - Mechatronics - Lesson 02]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[level

                                                                                                01

                 LESSON 1                                                                    Design
                                                                                             [Tinker CAD]





                INTRODUCTION TO 3D


                DESIGN AND MODELING



                CONCEPTS



































































           Level 01 - Design  [Tinker CAD]  - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[Are you a fan of dget toys games? Do
                          you like to know how to make your own

                          using 3D printers?
                          dget toys are recognized as more than

                          just ‘toys’ – they are helpful for people
                          dealing with anxiety, stress, or boredom.

                          You can design any dget toy by
                          understanding  3D modeling, Design

                          using CAD and Print using 3D printers.



























































                                                           01

           Level 01 - Design  [Tinker CAD]  - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[The main Idea



                   3D modeling is the process of creating a digital 3D representation
                   of an object. This can be done using a variety of software
                   programs, such as TinkerCAD, SolidWorks, and Fusion.


                   Once a 3D model is created, it can be used for a variety of
                   purposes, such as:


                      Computer-aided design (CAD):
                      3D models can be used to create CAD models, which are used in
                      engineering and manufacturing to design and prototype new
                      products.



                      3D printing:
                      3D printing is the process of creating a physical object from a
                      digital 3D model.



                      Virtual reality (VR) and augmented reality (AR):
                      3D models can be used to create immersive VR and AR
                      experiences. This can be used for a variety of applications, such as
                      gaming, training, and education.








































           Level 01 - Design  [Tinker CAD]  - Lesson 01]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[3D modeling is a challenging process, but it is also a very
                   rewarding one. With the right tools and skills, you can create
                   anything you can imagine.


                   Let’s start with Computer-aided


                   design (CAD)





                    First

                    You have a set of 2D and 3D shapes can you recognize the
                    difference.

                    The main difference between 2D and 3D is the number of
                    dimensions they have. 2D objects have two dimensions, length
                    and width, while 3D objects have three dimensions, length, width,
                    and height. This means that 2D objects can only be represented
                    on a ﬂat surface, while 3D objects can be represented in a
                    three-dimensional space.
























                    Second

                    You can design any 3D shapes using Tinker CAD software.

                    Autodesk’s Tinkercad app is probably the easiest, most accessible
                    and most fun 3D modeling application for creating your ﬁrst 3D
                    print. No previous 3D modeling experience needed and best of all:
                    this 3D design app is totally free.











           Level 01 - Design  [Tinker CAD]  - Lesson 01]]></page></pages></Search>