<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="14"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Theme 1



               [Insert Theme Name]





               Learning Outcomes



               By the end of this theme, students will be able to:

                   1. [Outcome1]
                   2. [Outcome 2]
                   3. [Outcome 3]]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[UNIT 01: [Name of the unit]


               Chapter 01: [Name of the chapter]

               Lesson01: [Name of the lesson]


               Time Frame: [Specify Duration]










                       LessonObjectives





                                                                             Answers of exercises















              Challenge questions of the

                              lesson.















                                                                            Answers of exercises




                           ESL Relation]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[1. Engage (The Hook)
            Objective:  Capture students’  attention  and stimulate  curiosity  about famous  monuments.
            •Teacher Role:
                   •   Start with  a hook activity:  Show images  or videos  of iconic  landmarks  (e.g., Eiffel
                       Tower, Pyramids  of Giza,  or a landmark  from  the students’  country)  without  giving  them
                       too much  context.
                          •   Ask students:  “What do these monuments have in common? Why are they famous
                              around the world?”
                   •   Introduce  key questions to make them  think:
                          •   “What makes these landmarks stand out?”
                          •   “Why do you think people travel from all over the world to see them?”
                          •   “What do you think makes a monument stable and visually appealing?”
                          •   “Can you guess how these structures have remained standing for centuries?”
            •Student Role:
                   •   Participate  actively by answering  the questions  and discussing  the monuments.
                   •   Share ideas on why  these landmarks  are iconic  (e.g., size,  design,  historical  significance).
                   •   Think  critically about the structure  and design  of the monuments  and how they  appeal to
                       people.
            •Strategy:
                   •   Visual Engagement:  Show striking  images  of famous  monuments  (perhaps  including
                       monuments  from  the students'  own country  to make it more relatable).
                   •   Incorporate  a brief video clip:  For example,  a short time-lapse  video showing  tourists
                       visiting  the Eiffel  Tower or the Pyramids  of Giza,  which  emphasizes  their  cultural
                       significance  and global  recognition.
                   •   Use Questions to Generate Curiosity:  These  thought-provoking  questions  help  students
                       start thinking  about the importance  and impact  of these monuments.  They  are likely  to
                       have their  own thoughts  on why  these structures  are famous,  helping  to deepen their
                       interest.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[2. Explore



           Teacher Role:

           1.Introduction  to Monument  Design:
                  1.   Begin  by showing  visual aids (images  or videos)  of famous  monuments  such  as the Eiffel
                       Tower, Pyramids  of Giza,  and Colosseum.
                  2.   Prompt  questions to focus on the design:
                         1. "What shapes do you see in these structures?"
                         2. "How do these shapes contribute to the monument's stability?"
                         3. "What makes these monuments visually appealing?"
           2.Guide Students to Identify  Basic Shapes:
                  1.   Explain  that every  monument,  no matter  how complex,  is made up of basic shapes.
                  2.   Example:
                         1. The Eiffel Tower uses triangles  and long  beams (rectangular  prisms).
                         2. The Pyramids use squares and triangles.
                  3.   Task: Have students  observe and list the basic shapes they  notice  in  the monument  images.
           3.Hands-On  Exploration  with  Shapes:
                  1.   Provide  students  with  materials  (such as LEGO blocks, paper, or digital  design tools).
                  2.   Explain  the task: "Now, it’s your turn to create a monument using only basic shapes. You can
                       use blocks, cut out paper shapes, or try a digital design tool."
                  3.   Guide the activity by encouraging  students  to focus  on combining  shapes (such  as cubes,
                       cylinders,  and triangles)  to form  a structure  that looks stable  and balanced.
           4.Discuss Balance and Symmetry:
                  1.   Explain how symmetry  (both vertical  and horizontal)  is essential  in creating  visually
                       appealing  and stable monuments.
                  2.   Encourage  students to consider how they  arrange  their  shapes to create balance  in  their
                       designs.


           Student Role:
           1.Observe and Identify Shapes in Famous Monuments:
                  1.   Look at images or videos of famous  monuments  and identify  the basic shapes used in  their
                       construction  (triangles,  squares, cylinders,  etc.).
                  2.   List or sketchthe shapes they observe in  their  notebooks or on a worksheet.
                  3.   Collaborate  with  peers to discuss  what shapes each monument  is composed of and share
                       findings.
           2.Create Monument  Designs Using Basic Shapes:
                  1.   Use materials provided (building  blocks, paper, digital  tools) to create a monument of their
                       own using  the basic shapes.
                         1. Example:  Using  paper or cardboard, students  might  cut out triangles,  squares, and
                             circles  to create a pyramid,  tower, or other structure.
                         2. If using  digital  tools,  students  can design  a monument  by combining  geometric  shapes
                             like  cubes, cylinders,  and pyramids.
           3.Ensure Stability  and Balance:
                  1.   Arrange  the shapes in  a way that creates a stable structure.
                  2.   Consider symmetry:  Are the shapes balanced  on both sides? Is the structure  visually
                       appealing?]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Strategy:
           1.Visual Exploration:
                  1.   Use images, videos, or virtual  tours of famous  monuments  to help  students  observe the
                       shapes and features  of iconic  structures.
                  2.   Interactive discussion: After  showing  the visual  aids, engage  the class  in a conversation  about
                       how different  shapes and features  contribute  to the monument's  visual  appeal and stability.
           2.Hands-On  Building:
                  1.   Physical Models: Use LEGO bricks, cardboard,  straws, or play-doh to let students  build
                       simple  models  using  basic shapes.
                  2.   Digital Tools: If available,  use tools like  Tinkercad or Google Drawings for students  to
                       design  digital  models  of their  monuments.
           3.Balance and Symmetry  Focus:
                  1.   Model balance by showing  students  how some structures  are more stable  because of their
                       symmetrical  design  (e.g., the balance  in the structure  of the Eiffel  Tower or the symmetry  of
                       the Pyramids  of Giza).
                  2.   After  creating  their  designs,  ask students  to assess their  own structures:  “Is your monument
                       balanced? Does it stand on its own?”



           Sample Activities for the Explore Phase:
           1.Monument Shape Identification:
                  1.   Show an image  of the Eiffel Tower and ask:
                       "What basic shapes do you see?"
                       (Expected  Answer:  Triangles,  beams, rectangles).
                       Student Activity:  List  or draw the shapes they identify.
           2.Hands-On  Monument Creation:
                  1.   Provide  building  blocks or cardboard  shapes and ask students  to build  a simple monument
                       (e.g., a small  tower or pyramid)  using  only  the shapes they identified  in the previous  activity.
                         1. Use blocks to form  a stable structure that mimics  a famous  monument.
                         2. If using  digital  tools,  have them  design  a monument  by arranging  geometric  shapes in  a
                             3D modeling  tool.
           3.Quick Symmetry  Challenge:
                  1.   Ask students  to arrange  their  shapes in a symmetrical  design to ensure  balance.  Check for
                       stability:  Does their  design  stand on its own, or does it tip over?

           Materials Needed:
           •Visual aids: Images/videos  of famous  monuments  (Eiffel  Tower, Pyramids,  etc.)
           •Building  materials:  LEGO bricks, wooden blocks, paper, cardboard
           •Digital tools (if  applicable):  Tinkercad,  Google  Drawings
           •Worksheets: Monument  shape identification  worksheet,  design  challenge  worksheet]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[3. Explain


           Teacher Role:
           1.Introduce  Architectural  Design Principles:
                  1.   Article Introduction:
                         1. Introduce  the article  "What Are the Principles of Architectural Design?" and briefly
                             explain  that it covers important  design  principles  that architects  use when  designing
                             buildings  and monuments.
                         2. Key principles  to highlight:
                                1. Balance: Symmetry  and equilibrium  in design.
                                2. Proportion:  Correct sizing  and relationship  between different  elements.
                                3. Unity:  Creating  harmony  between different  parts of the design.
                                4. Rhythm:  The visual  flow  created by the repetition  of elements.
                                5. Contrast:  Using  differences  in  size,  color, texture  to create visual  interest.
                         3. Show the Video:
                                1. Use the video  "The Importance of Proportion and Balance in Architecture" to
                                    visually  demonstrate  these principles  through  real-world  examples,  such as the
                                    Parthenon  or other famous  monuments.
                                2. Highlight  how these principles  make structures  both stable and visually
                                    appealing.
           2.Guide the Article Reading:
                  1.   Pre-reading  questions:
                         1. "What do you think balance and proportion mean in architectural design?"
                         2. "How do these principles apply to what we’ve learned about monuments?"
                  2.   Allow  students  time  to read or review  the article  (either  as homework  or in  class, depending  on
                       your class structure).
           3.Facilitate Discussion:
                  1.   After  reading  the article  and watching  the video, encourage  students  to discuss  the principles.
                  2.   Ask guiding  questions:
                         1. "Can you think of any monuments that use the principle of balance?"
                         2. "How do you see proportion being used in structures like the Eiffel Tower or the Great
                             Wall of China?"
           4.Summarize  Key Concepts:
                  1.   Help students  synthesize  the principles  learned.  Provide  a brief  summary  of each principle  on
                       the board or in  a digital  presentation.
                  2.   Example:  "Balance  in architecture  is not just about making  structures  look good; it also ensures
                       they  are stable  and safe."]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Student Role:
          1.Engage with  the Article:
                 1.  Read the article "What Are the Principles of Architectural Design?" (either  individually  or in
                     groups)  to understand  the key principles  of design.
                 2.  As they read, students  should  focus  on identifying  each design  principle  mentioned  in the
                     article.
                        1. Activity:  Highlight  or take notes on the principles  of balance,  proportion,  unity,  rhythm,
                            and contrast.
          2.Watch and Analyze the Video:
                 1.  Watch the video about the importance  of balance  and proportion  in  architecture.
                 2.  While  watching,  students  should:
                        1. Identify examples of balance and proportion in  the structures  shown  in the video.
                        2. Take notes on how architects use these principles  in real-world  structures.
          3.Discuss and Reflect:
                 1.  Participate  in a class  discussion  about how these principles  apply to famous  landmarks.
                 2.  Share insights:  "I think the Eiffel Tower uses symmetry and balance because..."
                 3.  Compare  with  previous learning:  Reflect  on the monuments  they’ve  seen earlier  and identify
                     how the principles  apply.
          4.Create Visual Notes or Diagrams:
                 1.  Draw simple  sketches or diagrams of famous  monuments,  labeling  where  each design
                     principle  is applied.
                 2.  Optional:  Use a Venn  diagram  or chart to compare  different  monuments  in terms  of balance,
                     proportion,  etc.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Strategy to Make This Task Interesting:
          1.Interactive Learning:
                 1.  Active Viewing:  Encourage  students  to take notes or answer quick  questions  while  watching
                     the video. For instance:  "How does the video show the importance of balance in the
                     Parthenon?"
                 2.  Group  Work:  After  reading  the article,  have students  discuss in small groups the principles
                     and how they relate  to a monument  they  are familiar  with.  This  encourages  collaboration  and
                     deeper engagement.
          2.Visual Examples:
                 1.  Use real-world  examples of iconic  landmarks  to illustrate  how each design  principle  is
                     applied.
                 2.  Show the video for visual  learners  and explain  key principles  in  a way that students  can relate
                     to what  they already  know about structures.
          3.Hands-On  Activity:
                 1.  Design Practice:  After  explaining  the principles,  encourage  students  to think  about how they
                     can apply  balance,  proportion,  and unity  to their  own monument  designs.
                 2.  Use simple  diagrams  or sketches: Students  can draw their  monuments  and label  which  design
                     principles  they  used.
          4.Technology Integration:
                 1.  Use a digital tool like  Google  Drawings  or Tinkercad for students  to create and modify  digital
                     models  of their  monuments,  applying  the principles  they've  learned.]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[5. Evaluate




          Teacher Role:
          1.Introduce  the Challenge:
                 1.  Explain  the task:
                     "Now that you’ve learned the key architectural principles, your next task is to investigate and
                     analyze buildings or monuments that didn't follow these principles. Specifically,  you’ll focus on
                     how the lack of symmetry, proportion, or balance affected the structure."
                 2.  Provide Examples:
                        1. Introduce  some famous  examples  where architectural  principles  were overlooked:
                               1. The Leaning Tower of Pisa: A case of imbalance  and proportion  issues.
                               2. The Millennium  Dome (London):  Known for structural  issues  related  to balance.
                               3. The Sydney Opera House: Discuss  the challenges  it faced in  terms of proportion
                                   and balance  during  its construction.
          2.Presentation Guidelines:
                 1.  Explain  the structure  of the presentation:
                        1. Overview of the Building:  Name, location,  and purpose of the building.
                        2. Architectural  Principles:  Identify  which  principle(s)  were violated  (symmetry,
                            proportion,  balance).
                        3. Consequences of the Violation:  How did the failure  to follow  these principles  affect  the
                            building’s  design,  functionality,  and stability?
                        4. Visuals: Include  images  or diagrams  to show where the principles  were ignored.
          3.Provide Resources:
                 1.  Suggest  students  use resources  like  online  research  (e.g., websites,  articles,  images)  to find
                     examples  of buildings  that failed  to follow  architectural  principles.
                 2.  Provide a rubric for the presentation  to clarify  expectations  (organization,  content,  clarity,
                     visuals,  etc.).
          4.Allow  Time for Research and Creation:
                 1.  Allocate  time  in  class or as homework  for students  to conduct research,  organize  their  findings,
                     and prepare their  presentation.
                 2.  Allow  students  to choose whether  they  want to present  using  PowerPoint,  Google Slides, or
                     any other preferred  format.
          5.Q&A Session:
                 1.  After  students  present,  facilitate  a Q&A sessionwhere peers can ask questions  and offer
                     feedback. This  can help further  deepen the understanding  of how principles  affect  architectural
                     design.]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Student Role:

          1.Research and Select a Building:
                 1.  Identify a famous building or monument  that failed  to follow  key architectural  principles.
                 2.  Gather  relevant  information  and visual  examples.  Look for buildings  that are known  for issues  in
                     symmetry, proportion,  or balance.
          2.Create a Presentation:
                 1.  Develop a short presentation (3-5 slides)  based on the following:
                        1. Introduction:  Brief  overview  of the building  or monument.
                        2. Architectural  Principles  Violated:  Explain  how symmetry,  proportion,  or balance  were
                            not properly  followed.
                        3. Consequences of Failure:  Discuss  the impact  of these failures  on the building's
                            appearance, functionality,  and overall  success.
                        4. Visual Evidence:  Include  images  of the building  to highlight  the issues  and principles
                            involved.
          3.Present Findings:
                 1.  Present the findings  to the class  in an organized,  clear, and engaging  manner.
                 2.  Use visuals  and diagrams  to support the analysis  and ensure  a comprehensive  understanding  of
                     how the violation  of architectural  principles  affected  the building.












          Websites for Famous Buildings and Failures:
          1.The Leaning Tower of Pisa - History and Design
                 1.  Website: https://www.history.com/topics/landmarks/leaning-tower-of-pisa
                 2.  An article  from  History.com  detailing  the history,  design  flaws,  and engineering  challenges  of
                     the Leaning  Tower of Pisa.
          2.The Sydney Opera House - Design and Challenges
                 1.  Website: https://www.sydneyoperahouse.com/about-us/our-story.html
                 2.  The official  Sydney  Opera House website  offers  insights  into  the design  and the initial
                     struggles  the project faced, including  issues  with  balance  and proportion.
          3.The Millennium  Dome (London)  - Design Issues
                 1.  Website: https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-45323668
                 2.  This  BBC article  discusses  the architectural  challenges  and the reasons why  the Millennium
                     Dome faced criticism,  including  issues  related  to proportion  and design  choices.
          4.The Pyramids  of Giza - Stability  and Proportion
                 1.  Website: https://www.history.com/topics/ancient-history/the-egyptian-pyramids
                 2.  This  article  explains  the principles  of symmetry,  proportion,  and balance  used in  the design  of
                     the Pyramids,  providing  a great example  of how ancient  structures  adhered to these principles.]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Strategy to Make This Task Interesting:
        1.Use of Real-World  Examples:
                1.  By focusing  on real-world  buildings  that faced challenges  due to architectural  missteps,  students
                    can see the practical  consequences  of violating  design  principles.
                2.  The Leaning Tower of Pisa is a particularly  interesting  example,  as it has become a famous
                    tourist  attraction  despite its flaws.
        2.Interactive Learning:
                1.  After  the presentation,  encourage  an open class discussion:  "Why do you think these principles
                    were ignored in the first place? What could have been done differently?"
                2.  Let students  debate if  the buildings  would  still  be iconic  if  these design  flaws  were corrected.
        3.Creativity in Presentation:
                1.  Allow  students  to get creative  with  how they present  their  findings.  They  can include  sketches,
                    videos, or even 3D models (if  available)  to illustrate  the failure  of principles  in a more
                    interactive  way.
        4.Peer Review:
                1.  After  each presentation,  students  can  review and comment on their  peers' work, giving  feedback
                    on what was effective  and suggesting  areas of improvement.





                      Rubric for Presentation on Famous Buildings with Architectural Flaws
                 Criteria            3 - Excellent           2 - Satisfactory     1 - Needs Improvement

              Building         Presents 3 or more         Presents 2 famous       Presents only 1 building
              Selection        famous buildings with      buildings with          or buildings without clear
                               clear architectural flaws  architectural flaws     flaws


              Explanation of   Clearly explains           Explains some           Minimal or incorrect
              Principles       symmetry, proportion, and  principles but may lack   explanation of
                               balance in simple terms    clarity                 architectural principles

              Identification of  Accurately points out    Identifies some flaws   Fails to identify clear
              Flaws            specific flaws in each     but may lack detail     flaws or makes incorrect
                               building's design                                  statements

              Visual Aids      Uses clear, helpful        Uses some visuals, but  Uses no visuals or
                               pictures or drawings to    they may not clearly    irrelevant images
                               show building flaws        show flaws

              Presentation     Speaks clearly and         Speaks clearly most of   Difficult to understand or
              Style            engages the audience       the time, some          not engaging
                               throughout                 engagement

              Time             Stays within the given     Goes slightly over or   Significantly too short or
              Management       time limit                 under time limit        too long]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Lesson Plan


               1. Engage

                      Teacher Role:
                       [Describe teacher's responsibilities, e.g., facilitating discussions, asking questions.]
                      Expected From Students:
                       [Describe student activities, e.g., participating in discussions, sharing ideas.]
                      Parts of the books included.
                      Intro Story:
                       Use engaging strategies to grab students’ attention. (List strategies teachers can use to
                       deliver this part, including the name of the strategy and how to implement it.)
                      Story Reflection:
                           o   Questions
                          o   Suggested answers
                          o   (List strategies teachers can use to deliver this part, including the name of the
                              strategy and how to implement it.)





               2. Think

                      Questions and Possible Answers
                      Brainstorm Web:
                       [Provide space for ideas and connections.]
                      (List strategies teachers can use to deliver this part, including the name of the strategy
                       and how to implement it.)





               3. Explore


                      Teacher Role:
                       [Describe teacher guidance during activities.]
                      Expected From Students:
                       [Describe student tasks, e.g., hands-on participation.]
                      Parts of the books included.
                      Activity - Do It:
                          o   Materials Needed
                          o   Step-by-Step Instructions
                          o   Reflection Questions]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[4. Explain


                      Teacher Role:
                       [Explain concepts, guide discussions, etc.]
                      Expected From Students:
                       [Engage actively, share observations, etc.]
                      Parts of the books included.
                      Watch It:
                          o   Pre-Watching: Set a purpose.
                          o   During Watching: Active engagement.
                          o   Post-Watching: Discussion and reflection.
                          o   (List strategies teachers can use to deliver this part, including the name of the
                              strategy and how to implement it.)
                      ReadAbout It:
                          o   Pre-Reading: Discussion.
                          o   During Reading: Engagement.
                          o   Post-Reading: Summarize and reflect.
                          o   (List strategies teachers can use to deliver this part, including the name of the
                              strategy and how to implement it.)




               5. Elaborate


                      Teacher Role:
                       [Encourage creativity and application of knowledge.]
                      Expected From Students:
                       [Create models, circuits, experiments, or code.]
                      Parts of the books included.
                      Assessment:
                      Focus (answer the questions and list some strategies to apply while answering them.)
                      Practice.
                          o   Materials Needed
                          o   Step-by-Step Instructions
                          o   Reflection Questions
                      Challenge: Left for the students to be made at home.





               6. Evaluate

                      Teacher Role:
                       [Facilitate assessments and provide feedback.]]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[   Expected From Students:
                       [Answer questions, demonstrate understanding, make projects.]
                      Parts of the books included.


                              Showcase: Evaluate the students work in the main project and add a rubric so
                              teachers can follow .

                Relation to Standards:
                   [Link to relevant educational standards.]]]></page></pages></Search>