<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="5"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Unit




                2






          Lesson


                1






          Innovators in Action


          Surviving Dust Storms.











                                         Ready, Set, Learn!



                                         You need to know

                                           •  What an LDR (Light Dependent Resistor) is.

                                           •  How to write simple Arduino code and connect
                                              components (like the LDR) to an Arduino board to read
                                              data from sensors.
                                         You will be able to:

                                           •  Explore the concept of energy conservation in biology,
                                              such as hibernation or dormancy, and apply these
                                              principles to design a rover that can survive harsh
                                              conditions like dust storms on Mars.

                                           •  Understand the principles of light intensity and how
                                              it changes during Martian dust storms, affecting rover
                                              operation and energy conservation.

                                           •  Program the rover to automatically enter "storm mode" by
                                              integrating light sensors (LDR) with Arduino, enabling the
                                              rover to conserve energy during Martian dust storms.








                                                                                                            27]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Let’s

            Think!



          How do animals like bears and frogs survive harsh winters?



































          What does "energy conservation" mean in the animal world, and how could that concept
          be applied to a rover on Mars?











































          28]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Explorer’s

            Toolkit




                DIY Lab

          Work in teams to answer questions about how animals save energy in harsh conditions.

          Use your knowledge (and tools) wisely to survive the challenge!

          Connect what you learn to how a Mars rover survives dust storms.
          Rules:

          The teacher asks a question about
          animals’ energy-saving strategies.
          If stuck, you may use one tool:

            •  AI Search
            •  Hint from Teacher

            •  Replace the Question

          Correct answers = points. The team with the most
          points wins!

          After the Competition reflect on the following:

          How could the rover charge its battery?










          How can the idea of energy conservation, similar to how animals conserve energy, help
          the rover survive a dust storm on Mars?












               Dig Deeper

          Click on the link to learn more about light intensity and how it changes
          during Martian dust storms, affecting rover operation and energy conservation.

                https://www.nasa.gov/solar-system/nasas-insight-sees-power-levels-
                stabilize-after-dust-storm/










                                                                                                            29]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Hey friends
                                                  let’s wrap up!




          How can energy conservation in biology and light
          intensity changes help design a Mars rover?

          Energy Conservation in Biology: Animals like bears
          and frogs survive harsh conditions through hibernation
          or dormancy. These processes help them conserve
          energy during cold or resource-scarce periods.
          Similarly, engineers can apply this concept to Mars
          rovers, designing them to "hibernate" or reduce activity
          during dust storms, conserving energy for critical tasks.

          Light Intensity During Dust Storms: Mars experiences frequent dust storms that reduce
          light intensity. This decreases the rover's ability to charge its solar panels. Engineers
          use this knowledge to create systems that conserve energy during low-light conditions,
          ensuring the rover can survive and function during extended dust storms.



            Assessment






                   Apprentice

          Assist the rover in collecting sunlight and charging its battery. Connect a solar panel to the
          charging module and integrate it into your rover’s design.








































          30]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Builder

          To help the rover save energy during a sandstorm, attach an LDR (light sensor) to the rover.
          Code it so that when the sensor detects low light, it sends a signal to the Arduino to pause
          all rover functions.




































                                               Well done on your
                                                   design so far!






          Now, let’s return to the steps of the Engineering
          Design Process.


          It’s time to move into the improve phase.







                Now I Can

                Explore the concept of energy conservation in biology, such as hibernation
                or dormancy, and apply these principles to design a rover that can
                survive harsh conditions like dust storms on Mars.                                     
                Understand the principles of light intensity and how it changes during
                Martian dust storms, affecting rover operation and energy conservation.                

                Program the rover to automatically enter "storm mode" by integrating light
                sensors (LDR) with Arduino, enabling the rover to conserve energy during
                Martian dust storms.                                                                   



                                                                                                            31]]></page></pages></Search>