<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="4"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Grade 7


                                                        Theme 2


                                              Unite 2: ( intermediate )


                                             Ch.1 : Mechanics Domain


        How can we use wheels and axles to create a moving car that requires minimal

        effort?


        To make a car with wheels and axles that moves easily:



            ●  Reduce friction: Use smooth materials, lubrication, and bearings.
            ●  Bigger wheels: Larger wheels roll farther with each turn.
            ●  Lighten up: A lighter car needs less force to move.

        Do It :


        You have three cars. Form a team of three and begin your race, paying attention

        to how the wheels and design of each car impact its movement.














        How to make the 1  car :
                                 st

        We will need :


            1) 4 bottle caps

            2) Stick for the axels

            3) Cardboard piece ( 5 x 10 )

            4) Balloon and strew
            5) Glue gun sticks and glue gun]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Steps :


            1) Add the bottle caps to the sticks to make the wheels and axels

            2) Glue the wheels and axels to the cardboard piece

            3) Blow up a balloon and stick the strew to it
            4) Stick it to the cardboard


        Now you will observe


        Car 1 :


            ●  Wheels: Small, hard (likely plastic cap ) – inefficient rolling, especially on uneven
               surfaces.

            ●  Design: Simple, lightweight frame; high center of gravity (balloon).
            ●  Movement: Slow, unstable, prone to tipping (especially during turns/on bumps) due to

               high center of gravity and friction from small wheels.

        Car 2 :


            ●  Wheels: rubber tires – better grip and smoother rolling.
            ●  Design: Smooth to the ground  – reduced air resistance and improved high-speed
               stability.
            ●  Movement: Likely fastest and most stable; efficient movement and good handling.


        Car 3 :


                                                                                        st
            ●  Wheels: largest wheels, rubber tires. They look wider than the 1  car wheels, which
               might offer more stability.
            ●  Design: Boxy shape, possibly heavier than the other two. The flat front will create more
               air resistance.
            ●  Predicted Movement: Likely a middle ground between the other two. The wider wheels

               should provide decent stability, but the boxy design will create more drag, slowing it
               down. It might be more robust than the 1  car though.
                                                               st
            Watch it :



            https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dM6AtIy60gQ


            Read this :



            https://www.evanshalshaw.com/blog/the-history-of-cars/]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Materials:


            ●  Laser-cut wooden base (design pre-made with motor mounts )
            ●   plastic wheels
            ●  DC motors
            ●  Wiring (for connecting motors to power)
            ●  Power source (battery pack or power supply)
            ●  Switch (to turn the motors on and off)
            ●  Fasteners (screws, glue)


        Tools:


            ●  Laser cutting machine (for the base and potentially motor mounts)

        Steps:


            1.  Design the Base (using CAD software):
                   o  Design the car base in CAD software.
                   o  Include:

                          ▪  Precise axle holes (as before).]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[▪  Mounting points for the DC motors. These could be slots, holes for screws,
                              or a designated area for gluing.
                          ▪  Consider space for the battery pack and switch.
            2.  Design Motor Mounts (if needed):
                   o  If you're not directly mounting the motors to the base, design motor mounts in
                       CAD software. These should securely hold the motors and allow for easy

                       attachment to the base.
            3.  Laser Cutting/3D Printing:
                   o  Laser cut the wooden base and any laser-cut motor mounts.
                   o  If you designed 3D printed mounts, print them now.
            4.  Connect Wheels to Motors:
                   o  This is where the power gets transferred! There are a few ways to do this:
                          ▪  Direct Drive: Attach the wheels directly to the motor shafts (if the shafts

                              are the right size).
                          ▪  Gears: Use gears to change the speed and torque of the motors.
                          ▪  Couplers: Use flexible or rigid couplers to connect the motor shafts to the

                              axles.
            5.  Wiring:
                   o  Connect the motors to the power source (battery pack) using wires.
                   o  Include a switch in the circuit to control the power flow.
                   o  Make sure the wiring is neat and secure to prevent shorts or disconnections.





        Key Considerations for Motorized Cars:

            ●  Motor Selection: Choose motors with the appropriate voltage, RPM (revolutions per

               minute), and torque (turning force) for your car's size and desired speed.
            ●  Gear Ratios (if using gears): The gear ratio will affect the speed and torque of the car. A
               higher gear ratio will result in lower speed but higher torque, and vice versa.
            ●  Power Source: Choose a battery pack or power supply that provides the correct voltage
               and current for the motors.
            ●  Wiring and Connections: Ensure all wiring connections are secure and insulated to
               prevent shorts.
            ●  Motor Control: For more advanced control, you could use a motor driver circuit or

               microcontroller to control the speed and direction of the motors.]]></page></pages></Search>