<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="8"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Unit




                2






           Lesson


                2






          Innovators in Action


          Shielding from the Red



          Danger.






                                         Ready, Set, Learn!



                                         You Need to Know

                                            •  How temperature sensors (e.g., thermistors or
                                              thermocouples) work and how they can be used to
                                              measure temperature changes.

                                            •  How to program the rover to make decisions based on
                                              sensor data.

                                            •  The basic structure of coding with "if-else" statements,
                                              loops, and conditionals.

                                         You will be able to:

                                            •  Recognise the biological impact of radiation on living
                                              organisms, including its role in DNA damage and cell
                                              health.
                                            •  Understand the relationship between temperature and
                                              radiation on Mars and how it affects rover behaviour.

                                            •  Code the rover to reroute when the temperature reaches
                                              dangerous levels, based on the data from the temperature
                                              sensor.






          32]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Let’s

            Think!



          Why is it important for the rover to avoid areas with high radiation, and how can this
          help us determine which regions on Mars might be unsafe for humans to live in?










































            Explorer’s

            Toolkit




                DIY Lab


            •  Radiation on Mars can harm DNA and damage cell health.
            •  Astronauts need rovers to explore the surface and mark areas of high radiation.

            •  Today, you will act like scientists testing shields and detectors to find out which areas
               are safe or unsafe.
          You have three identical yeast–sugar mixtures labeled: Control, UV-30s, and UV-120s.
          Each mixture is placed in a sealed bottle covered with a balloon or plastic wrap and kept
          in a warm environment. Every 15 minutes for one hour, measure the circumference of each
          balloon (in centimeters) to monitor gas production.










                                                                                                            33]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Time (min)              Control (cm)             UV-30s (cm)              UV-120s (cm)



          0



          15



          30


          45


          60


          Analysis Questions:
          Which sample produced the largest amount of gas (biggest balloon), and what does this
          indicate?










          How did increasing the length of UV exposure affect the yeast’s ability to grow and
          carry out respiration?











          Using scientific vocabulary, explain how radiation can cause DNA damage and impact
          overall cell health.































          34]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[CER











                                                         i
                      Claim                                                       Reasoning





                                                  Evidence




































































                                                                                                            35]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Screen Lessons

          Click on the link to learn more about the relation between temperature and radiation.
                https://youtu.be/je-qc7sxYzU?si=NCYdoq7oE-zNFxyf


               Dig Deeper

          Click on the link to learn more about temperature sensor and how it works.
                https://atlas-scientific.com/blog/how-do-temperature-sensors-
                work/?srsltid=AfmBOor_kwBsl6RP0y3k7-0K5HoSnMTyIA-
                cf4BSomhgSVcKWjPGySwv






























                                                   Hey friends
                                                  let’s wrap up!




          Radiation is powerful energy that can harm living
          organisms. It can damage DNA, which is like the
          “instruction book” inside every cell. When DNA is
          damaged, cells may not grow properly, may stop
          working, or even die. This is why astronauts need
          protection from high radiation on Mars.

            •  Radiation carries energy. When radiation (like
               sunlight or cosmic rays) hits a surface, it can
               transfer energy and cause the material to heat up.

            •  Areas with higher radiation often show higher temperature readings, while shaded or
               protected areas tend to be cooler.
            •  On Mars, radiation is not always visible, but its effect can often be noticed in the
               temperature changes of the rover’s surroundings and equipment.








          36]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Assessment






                   Apprentice

          Q1 (Multiple Choice):

          Which of the following is NOT a place where temperature sensors are commonly used?

            A.  Ovens
            B.  Refrigerators

            C.  Smartphones

            D.  Paint brushes
          Which sensor might a Mars Rover use to record the Martian environment?

            A.  Thermistor
            B.  Barometer

            C.  Gyroscope
            D.  Compass




          Q2 (Complete the sentence):
          Radiation can cause materials to ..................... faster, which affects their temperature.

          Q3 (Open-ended):

          Explain why cars have temperature sensors inside their engines.











          How could temperature sensors help astronauts when they build shelters on Mars?


























                                                                                                            37]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Builder

          Now, attach the temperature sensor to your rover, program it, and view the readings on the
          serial monitor.



























                   Mastermind

          Imagine your rover took these readings in 1 day:

          Morning: –60 °C, radiation high
          Afternoon: –20 °C, radiation medium

          Night: –70 °C, radiation low
          Question: Which time of day would be the safest for astronauts to explore outside?
          Why?










































          38]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Showcase

          Upgrade your code and Code the rover to reroute when the temperature reaches
          dangerous levels, based on the data from the temperature sensor.

































                                         Great job till now!







          Now that you're done Let’s go back to the EDP
          steps and add this to improve part.
                                                                                                 Name:
                                                                                                 Name:
                                                                                                 Project:
                                                                                                 Project:
                                                                                                  Ask Ask
                                                                                                           Imagine
                                                                                                           Imagine
                                                                                                   Plan
                                                                                                   Plan
                                                                                                            Create
                                                                                                           Create
                                                                                                  Improve
                                                                                                  Improve
                Now I Can
                Recognize how radiation affects living organisms and explain its role
                in DNA damage and overall cell health.                                                 

                Understand how temperature and radiation are connected on Mars
                and describe how these factors influence rover behavior.                               
                Write and apply code so the rover can automatically change its path
                when the temperature sensor detects dangerous levels.                                  













                                                                                                            39]]></page></pages></Search>