<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="6"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Unit




              2






         Lesson


              1






        Innovators in Action


        Up & Down for Everyone!











                                       Ready, Set, Learn!



                                       You will be able to:

                                          •  Design a seesaw that allows children who use
                                             wheelchairs to play safely.

                                          •  Explore and describe how force and motion affect how the
                                             seesaw moves.
                                          •  Use addition and subtraction up to 20 to balance different
                                             weights on each side.

                                          •  Measure and compare objects to help create a balanced
                                             design.
                                          •  Choose strong and safe materials for building their
                                             seesaw.
                                          •  Observe how pushes and pulls make the seesaw move.

                                          •  Use words like fast, slow, up, and down to describe
                                             movement.












                                                                                                            37]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Adam: “The seesaw is hard to use. How can we make it easier for Khaled?”


          Laila: “Maybe we can change something so we don’t have to push so much.”

          Khaled: “Can we find a way to help it go up and down, even if one side is heavier?”

          Ms. Sara: “Great ideas! What can we do to help it move more easily and safely for
          everyone?”

          Adam: “We can make the middle part stronger or change how it moves.”

          Laila: “And we can make sure there’s a big, safe space so Khaled can use it too.”

          Ms. Sara: “Wonderful thinking! Let’s work together to build a seesaw that’s fun and safe for
          all kids!”

            Let’s


            Think!


          1 .  Which of these makes the seesaw move faster?


                 A gentle push/pull
                 A big push/pull

                 No push/pull
                                                                        Figure 21: Inclusive merry-go-round.


          38]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[2 .  How can you tell if both sides of the seesaw
             are the same?

                 One side is up high

                 Both sides are flat and even
                 One side is touching the ground






                                                                        Figure 22: A boy and a girl playing
                                                                        together on a seesaw.
          3 .  Which material is best for a strong and safe seesaw?


                 Paper
                 Wood

                 cardboard


            Explorer’s

            Toolkit




                DIY Lab

          Try this fun activity Put play dough on each side of the seesaw and see how it moves.






























                     Figure 23: A simple DIY seesaw made with a stick and play dough balls on each
                                               side to show how it moves.












                                                                                                            39]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[CER











                                                         i
                      Claim                                                       Reasoning





                                                  Evidence

           When I add more play                 How many pieces of                  The side with more
           dough to one side, the               play dough did you                  pieces of play dough
           seesaw will:                         need on the right side              went:

                  Go up and down               to make it move?                           Up

                  Stay still                          1                                  Down
                  Move side to side                   2                           When more pieces of
                                                       3                           play dough are added,
                                                       4                           the seesaw moves:

                                                       5 or more                          Faster

                                                What did the seesaw                        Slower
                                                do when it moved?                          Stays the same

                                                       Moved fast

                                                       Moved slow



































          40]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Screen Lessons

           Let’s click the link and explore how things move with pushes and
           pulls—let’s learn something new together!
                https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Se_e5h9vtms



                                                  Hey flriends
                                                  let’s wrap up!




            •  A force is what we use to push or pull the
               seesaw.
            •  When we pull one side down, the other side
               goes up.

            •  When we push down, we make the seesaw
               move the other way.
            •  The seesaw also moves differently depending
               on how heavy the objects are—heavier objects
               need more force to lift!

























                                  Figure 24: A boy showing two actions — pulling a box
                                             with a rope and pushing a block.



            Assessment






                   Apprentice

          Let’s play a game together to learn how a seesaw balances.
                https://www.proprofsgames.com/seesaw-logic/






                                                                                                            41]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Showcase

          Let’s build a seesaw that is strong, wide, and easy to use. We will make sure there’s space
          for a wheelchair so all our friends can play together safely.
























                                     Figure 25: A wide and strong seesaw designed
                                    with space for a wheelchair so all friends can play
                                                     together safely.






                              Great job on your design!






          Now let’s go back to the EDP steps. It’s
          time to move to the Create part and add
          this                                                                                   Name:
                                                                                                 Project:
                                                                                                  Ask
                                                                                                           Imagine
                                                                                                   Plan

                                                                                                           Create
                                                                                                  Improve
                Now I Can

                Design a seesaw that allows children who use wheelchairs to play safely.   
                Explore and describe how force and motion affect how the seesaw moves.  

                Use addition and subtraction up to 20 to balance different weights
                on each side.                                                                          

                Measure and compare objects to help create a balanced design.                          
                Choose strong and safe materials for building their seesaw.                            

                Observe how pushes and pulls make the seesaw move.                                     
                Use words like fast, slow, up, and down to describe movement.                          




          42]]></page></pages></Search>