<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="1"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Theme 2                                            Climate Guardians







                 By the end of the theme
                 By the end of the theme


                Students will be able to:
                 Students will be able to:





                           Dene global warming and explain its main causes, including the role of
                           human activities such as burning fossil fuels and deforestation.

                           Describe the greenhouse eect and its contribution to global warming,
                           using key terms like "carbon dioxide" and "greenhouse gases."
                           Identify the environmental impacts of global warming, including rising
                           temperatures, melting glaciers, and changing weather patterns.

                           Explore and suggest solutions to reduce global warming, such as
                           conserving energy, planting trees, and using renewable resources.


                           Recognize the importance of global action and how individual eorts
                           contribute to addressing climate change.

                           Design and sketch a prototype for a climate change mitigation device,
                           then create a 3D digital model using Tinkercad.
                           Integrate sensors like water level, temperature, or humidity sensors into
                           the device and explain their functions and signicance.

                           Collect and interpret sensor data to understand environmental changes,
                           such as shifts in temperature and humidity, and propose actionable
                           responses.

                           Program sensors using basic coding principles to enable automated
                           responses and alerts, such as warnings for abnormal environmental
                           readings.

                           Connect a temperature sensor to a Bluetooth module and program it to
                           wirelessly transmit data to a mobile application interface.


                           Develop a basic mobile app to display sensor data, demonstrating the
                           principles of wireless data communication and its practical applications.

                           Create a basic webpage using HTML to raise awareness about climate
                           change, incorporating tags for headings, paragraphs, lists, and images.
                           Format and enhance the webpage using simple HTML tags.










                                                         02]]></page></pages></Search>