<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="30"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[1]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Theme-01

               Eco-Bots



               By the end of the theme students will be able to:



                      Identify the key components of an ecosystem, including biotic
                       and abiotic factors.

                      Explain the interactions and interdependence between the

                       components of an ecosystem.

                      Recognize the various types of pollution (e.g., plastic, chemical,

                       noise) that can negatively impact ecosystems.

                      Analyse the effects of different pollutants on the health and

                       balance of ecosystems.
                      Discuss the importance of protecting and preserving

                       ecosystems to maintain biodiversity and ecological

                       sustainability.

                      Investigate the physical and mechanical properties of different

                       materials, including density.

                      Determine the suitability of various materials for constructing

                       objects based on their properties.
                      Explain the relationship between an object's density and its

                       ability to float or sink in water.

                      Understand the principles of buoyancy and how they relate to

                       the design of floating objects.

                      Analyse the factors that contribute to an object's stability and

                       ability to float, such as weight and surface area.

                      Apply the principles of buoyancy and weight vs. surface area to
                       design and optimize a floating device.












                                                            2]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[UNIT 01 [Beginner]
            Chapter 01: Mechanics

            LESSON 01: Eco-Bots.

            Time frame: 75 mins





               Introduction story

                      section



               Begin the lesson by sharing the story. You can use various engaging strategies to grab students'
               attention, ignite their curiosity, and link the story to the lesson's goals.


               1. Preview with a Hook

                      Strategy: Begin with an intriguing question, a striking image, or a captivating excerpt
                       from the story to spark curiosity.
                      Purpose: This strategy aims to capture students' interest immediately, connecting
                       them emotionally or intellectually to the story before it begins. It builds excitement
                       and creates a desire to find out what happens next.
                      How to Implement:
                          o  Start by identifying a compelling moment, question, or visual related to the
                              story. For example, if the story involves a sea turtle in distress, ask, “What
                              would you do if you found a sea turtle with a plastic bottle cap caught around
                              its neck?”
                          o  Alternatively, display a powerful image (e.g., a photo of a turtle affected by
                              plastic pollution) and invite students to think about how they would respond in
                              this situation.
                          o  Lead a brief discussion based on their responses, then connect their ideas to
                              the theme of the story. For example, explain, “Today’s story is about a sea
                              turtle facing a difficult situation. Let’s find out what happens next.”




               2. Make Predictions


                      Strategy: Show the cover, title, and perhaps the first line of the story, and ask
                       students to predict what they think the story will be about.
                      Purpose: Making predictions activates students' prior knowledge and sets a purpose
                       for reading, encouraging them to engage with the story actively to see if their
                       predictions are correct.
                      How to Implement:







                                                            3]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[o  Begin by showing the cover of the book and reading the title out loud. Ask,
                              “What do you think this story might be about based on the title and the cover
                              image?”
                          o  Share the first line of the story if it hints at the theme or conflict, and ask
                              students to expand on their predictions.
                          o  Encourage students to share different predictions and jot down some of their
                              ideas on the board. This way, they’ll be curious to see which predictions are
                              accurate as they read.




               3. Set the Scene with a Visual


                      Strategy: Show a picture or play a short audio clip related to the setting or theme of
                       the story.
                      Purpose: Visuals and sounds can help students build mental images, immersing them
                       in the world of the story even before reading. This strategy creates anticipation and
                       establishes a sense of place or mood for the story.
                      How to Implement:
                          o  Select a visual (e.g., an image of a forest, beach, or bustling city street) or
                              audio (e.g., ocean waves, forest sounds) that relates to the setting of the story.
                          o  Share the visual or play the audio for a few moments, then ask students, “What
                              do you imagine this place is like? How would it feel to be there?”
                          o  After a brief discussion, connect this sensory experience to the story’s opening
                              scene, setting the stage for students to enter the story's world with vivid
                              expectations.


           Story Reflection


               Purpose of Reflection: This reflection section encourages students to think critically about
               the story and its connection to the lesson objectives.

               Questions Answers:

               What was wrong with Shelly the turtle when Adam found her?

               c) She was choking on a plastic cap.

               What did Adam and his family do after helping Shelly?


               c) They made it their mission to pick up as much plastic and litter as they could find.

               How to Implement:

               1. Think-Pair-Share


                      Example Question: What was wrong with Shelly the turtle when Adam found her?
                      How to Implement:









                                                            4]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[o  Ask students to think individually about possible reasons why Shelly might be
                              in trouble, based on the story context or what they know about threats to sea
                              turtles.
                          o  Have students pair up and share their ideas. This gives them a chance to
                              predict what might be wrong with Shelly before discussing the actual problem
                              of plastic pollution.
                          o  Invite pairs to share their answers with the class and discuss the concept of
                              pollution and how it affects marine animals.




               2. Role-Playing Responses


                      Example Question: What did Adam and his family do after helping Shelly?
                      How to Implement:
                          o  Have students take turns role-playing as Adam, his family members, or even
                              Shelly the turtle. Ask them to act out what they might do after saving a turtle
                              from pollution.
                          o  Encourage students to think about how they would feel after helping Shelly
                              and whether they would take any actions to prevent similar situations in the
                              future.
                          o  After role-playing, discuss the importance of small actions like picking up
                              litter and how Adam’s family made it their mission to help protect the
                              environment.




               3. Text Evidence Challenge

                      Example Question: What was wrong with Shelly the turtle when Adam found her?
                      How to Implement:
                          o  Challenge students to find specific lines or words in the story that describe
                              Shelly’s problem. For example, they could underline or highlight the phrase
                              “choking on a plastic cap” or similar descriptions.
                          o  Ask students to explain how this evidence shows the problem Shelly faced and
                              why plastic pollution is dangerous for wildlife.
                          o  Discuss how using text evidence helps them understand the story’s message
                              about environmental responsibility.




               4. Open-Ended Questioning


                      Example Question: Why do you think Adam and his family decided to make picking
                       up litter their mission?
                      How to Implement:
                          o  Ask students to think about why Adam and his family might feel strongly
                              about picking up litter after saving Shelly. Encourage them to consider how
                              personal experiences can motivate people to take action.






                                                            5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[o  Allow students to share different reasons they think Adam’s family became
                              more environmentally conscious.
                          o  Emphasize the idea that witnessing a problem firsthand can inspire action,
                              encouraging students to consider what they might do to help in similar
                              situations.




                Let’s Think





                   1.  Question: Based on the image, it appears to depict a significant amount of
                       marine waste and debris floating in the ocean. Think what might be
                       causing this problem of marine waste in the sea?














                      Possible Answers:
                          o  People littering on beaches or in rivers, which carry trash into the ocean.
                          o  Ships dumping waste in the ocean.
                          o  Plastic products that don’t decompose, like bottles and bags, ending up in the
                              water.
                          o  Lack of recycling or proper waste disposal methods.
                          o
                      Strategy:  Brainstorm Web
                          o  How to Implement: Begin by drawing a web diagram on the board with
                              "Causes of Marine Waste" in the center. Ask students to brainstorm possible
                              causes and add them as branches. Let them work in pairs to think of as many
                              ideas as they can, then share with the class.
                          o  This visual organization will help students connect their thoughts and see the
                              bigger picture of pollution sources.
                          o  Engagement Tip: Use fun, colored markers or stickers to make the web
                              visually appealing. Consider adding an element of competition by seeing how
                              many unique answers each group can come up with.


               Question 2: Imagine Yourself Swimming in a Beautiful Coral Reef. What
               Would You Expect to See?

               Possible Answers:








                                                            6]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[1.  Fish or marine animals swimming near plastic waste: Students might envision how
                       marine life interacts with pollution.
                   2.  Plastic bottles, bags, and other trash floating on the water’s surface: They could
                       picture the direct impact of waste on the ocean's surface.
                   3.  Dirty water or polluted areas around the waste: Students may consider how
                       pollution affects water quality.
                   4.  Fewer plants or coral in areas with a lot of trash: They might recognize the
                       detrimental effects on marine ecosystems.

               Strategy: Draw What You See


                      How to Implement: Provide students with blank paper and colored pencils or
                       markers. Instruct them to draw what they envision seeing underwater near a coral reef
                       that is polluted with plastic waste. Encourage them to include marine life, trash, and
                       the overall state of the water.
                      Engagement Tip: Display the completed drawings around the classroom, creating a
                       “pollution gallery.” This will not only showcase their creativity but also serve as a
                       visual reminder of the effects of pollution on marine life. After displaying their work,
                       engage the class in a discussion about how pollution impacts marine ecosystems,
                       using the students’ artwork as a conversation starter.

               3. Question: In your opinion, how can we make less waste?


                      Possible Answers:
                          o  Use reusable bags, bottles, and containers instead of single-use plastic.
                          o  Recycle more and encourage others to do so.
                          o  Organize or participate in beach clean-up events.
                          o  Educate others about the importance of reducing waste.
                      Strategy: Action Plan Posters
                          o  How to Implement: Ask students to work in small groups to create posters
                              with practical steps for reducing waste. Each group can focus on one main
                              idea (like recycling or avoiding plastic), then illustrate and write simple
                              actions everyone can follow.
                          o  Engagement Tip: Offer fun materials like stickers, glitter, or stamps to
                              decorate the posters. Hold a mini "poster fair" where groups present their ideas
                              to the class and vote on the best waste-reduction strategy.


                  Explore



               The concept of STEAM scouts is built around exploration, trial, and error. This
               section is divided into three parts: a "Do It" activity where students can
               experiment with the new concept firsthand, followed by a discovery phase
               where they uncover the scientific principles behind it.











                                                            7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Do it



               Sorting Materials:



               Objective: Students will explore and understand the properties of different materials
               (organic, plastic, and metal) through hands-on sorting activities, fostering their observation,
               classification, and critical thinking skills.





               Activity Overview

               Materials Needed:


                      Three labeled pots or bins (Organic, Plastic, Metal)
                      A list of materials for sorting, which may include:
                          o  Food scraps (e.g., fruit peel, vegetable scraps)
                          o  Plastic items (e.g., plastic bottle, plastic fork, plastic wrap)
                          o  Metal items (e.g., aluminum can, metal spoon, paperclip)
                      Worksheet for recording observations (optional)
                      Markers or labels for identifying pots
                      A timer (optional)




               Step-by-Step Activity Instructions


                   1.  Preparation:
                          o  Set up three pots or bins labelled Organic, Plastic, and Metal. Ensure they are clearly
                              visible to all students.
                          o  Gather various materials to sort, ensuring a good mix for each category. Place these
                              materials on a table or a large surface accessible to students.
                   2.  Introduction:
                          o  Explain the purpose of the activity to students. Discuss what they will be doing:
                              sorting different materials into the correct pots based on their properties.
                          o  Introduce the concept of recycling and the importance of knowing the difference
                              between types of materials.
                   3.  "Do It" Activity :
                          o  Sorting Instructions:
                                    Distribute the list of materials to each student or group.
                                    Instruct students to pick up items from the table and decide which pot they
                                     belong to.
                                    As they sort, encourage them to discuss with peers why they think an item
                                     fits into a specific category.







                                                            8]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Remind them that they can experiment and try different sorting methods,
                                     such as grouping similar items together.
                   4.  Discovery Phase:
                          o  Once sorting is complete, review each pot as a class.
                                    Ask students to share their reasoning behind their sorting choices.
                                    Discuss the properties of each material and its classification:
                                            Organic: Biodegradable, comes from living organisms.
                                            Plastic: Synthetic, made from petroleum-based products, often non-
                                            biodegradable.
                                            Metal: Conductive, typically recyclable.
                          o  Highlight any discrepancies in sorting and encourage a discussion on why certain
                              items may have been misclassified.
                   5.  Reflection :
                          o  Have students write down one new thing they learned about materials during the
                              sorting activity.





               Teaching Strategy

                      Inquiry-Based Learning:
                          o  This activity encourages students to ask questions and explore the properties of
                              materials through hands-on experience.
                          o  By allowing students to engage in discussion, they can develop critical thinking and
                              reasoning skills.
                      Collaboration:
                          o  Encourage students to work in pairs or small groups. Collaboration fosters
                              communication skills and helps students learn from each other.
                      Active Learning:
                          o  Engaging students in physical sorting and discussion promotes active participation,
                              which enhances retention and understanding of scientific concepts.
                      Formative Assessment:
                          o  The reflections and group discussions serve as informal assessments of student
                              understanding, allowing teachers to gauge learning outcomes and clarify concepts as
                              needed.

                    Watch it




               https:��www.youtube.com�watch?v=MnCbTTTi7ic

                   Before Watching –  Set a Purpose.


                      Preview Questions: Introduce a few questions related to the video content, like
                       "What types of materials do you see in the video?" or "How do people sort these
                       materials in real life?" This primes students to watch actively for answers.
                      Vocabulary Preview: Go over any key terms students might encounter (e.g.,
                       "biodegradable," "recycling," "landfill"). This helps them understand the video better
                       and builds anticipation for learning.






                                                            9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[During the Video –  Active Engagement Techniques.

                      Watch & Pause (Chunking): Divide the video into short segments by pausing after
                       key points. Ask questions like, “What did you learn about plastic materials here?” or
                       “Why is sorting materials important?” This keeps students thinking and discussing,
                       rather than passively watching.
                      Note-Taking Worksheet: Give students a simple worksheet with sections for each
                       type of material (organic, plastic, metal). As they watch, they can jot down examples
                       of each material type mentioned in the video.
                      Whisper Partners: Occasionally, pause and have students discuss a question briefly
                       with their neighbor. For example, after a segment on plastic waste, you could ask,
                       “How is plastic affecting the environment? Turn to your partner and discuss.” This
                       keeps them actively processing information.
                      Hand Signals for Key Points: Tell students to give a silent hand signal (like a
                       thumbs up) whenever they see something important or interesting. This keeps them
                       attentive and provides an opportunity to review what caught their attention.

                   Post-Viewing Activities –  Discussion and Reflection.


                      Quick Group Discussion: Immediately after the video, hold a brief class discussion.
                       Ask, “What was something new you learned?” or “Which material do you think is the
                       most harmful to the environment?” This provides an outlet for their ideas and
                       interpretations.
                      Exit Ticket Reflection: Have students write a quick reflection or "exit ticket"
                       describing one action they can take to reduce waste at home, based on what they
                       learned.
                      Creative Follow-Up (Optional): Have students illustrate or design a poster on one of
                       the materials and ways to manage its waste effectively. This reinforces concepts and
                       lets them creatively express their understanding.


                   Read about it



               https:��kids.nationalgeographic.com�nature�kids-vs-plastic�article�pollution-1


               Strategies for an Engaging "Read" Activity:

                   Pre-Reading Discussion.


                      Introduction and Background Knowledge: Start with a quick discussion about
                       pollution and plastic waste to activate prior knowledge. Ask, “What do you already
                       know about pollution and its effects?” or “Where have you seen plastic pollution in
                       your daily life?” This primes them to connect with the article’s topic.
                      Prediction Activity: Before reading, show students a few images from the article and
                       ask them to predict what problems with plastic pollution might be discussed. This
                       creates curiosity and sets a purpose for reading.


                   During Reading –  Active Engagement Techniques







                                                           10]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA["Stop and Jot" Notes: Have students pause after each section to quickly jot down a
                       one-sentence summary or a “wow” fact. For example, after reading about the impact
                       of plastic on animals, they might note, “Animals mistake plastic for food, which can
                       make them sick.”
                      Questioning Strategy: Encourage students to write one question in the margin of
                       each section. Questions could be, “Why is plastic so harmful?” or “What can I do to
                       reduce plastic at home?” These questions can be shared in a group discussion
                       afterward.
                      Buddy Reading: Pair students and assign each partner a paragraph or section to read
                       aloud. Partners can then take turns asking each other questions about what they read
                       or sharing one interesting fact they found in their section.


                   Post-Reading Activities –  Reflection and Discussion

                      Summarize and Share: Ask students to summarize the article by writing down the
                       main problem (plastic pollution) and one major solution or action they can take. This
                       helps them consolidate their understanding.
                      Think-Pair-Share: Have students think of one key fact or surprising detail from the
                       article, then pair up and discuss with a partner before sharing with the whole class.
                       This builds confidence and reinforces information.
                      Exit Ticket Reflection: On a sticky note or index card, have students write one
                       personal action they can take to reduce plastic use, based on the article. Collect these
                       and post them as a class “Pledge Wall” to reinforce commitment to small, impactful
                       actions.

              Assessment



                Focus








































                                                           11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Litter Dropped at the                          Plastic bottles
                                                    beach

                                                 Poorly Managed        Toxic chemicals
               1-Ingestion of Plastics and         Industries
               Micro plastics

               2- Habitat Destruction
                                                Shipping Materials       Lost Cargo          Fuel and Oil
               3- Loss of Biodiversity
                                                 lost overboard                                Drums
               4- Chemical Contamination

              Practice


               https:��www.youtube.com�watch?v=0iRTszLhD5M.


               Activity: Building a Paper Pyramid for the Marine Ecosystem

               Objective: Students will construct a 3D pyramid to represent elements of the marine
               ecosystem, helping them visually organize and better understand different components of this
               ecosystem.

               Materials Needed:


                      Cardboard
                      Glue gun and glue sticks
                      Printed paper with images or facts about the marine ecosystem
                      Scissors
                      Ruler
                      Pencil



               Steps


                   1.  Cutting the Triangles:
                          o  Using the cardboard, measure and cut out 8 triangles, each with dimensions of
                              19 cm (height) by 7.5 cm (base).
                   2.  Cutting the Square Base:
                          o  Measure and cut a square with dimensions of 17.5 cm by 17.5 cm. This will
                              serve as the base of the pyramid.
                   3.  Creating the Pyramid Sides:
                          o  Take two of the triangles and glue them together along their edges so that they
                              face each other. Repeat this for the other triangles, creating four pairs in total.
                   4.  Assembling the Pyramid:
                          o  Glue the pairs of triangles together to form the sides of the pyramid. Once
                              assembled, glue the entire structure onto the square base.
                   5.  Adding Printed Paper:





                                                           12]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[o  Place images or information about different marine ecosystem elements on
                              each face of the pyramid, such as fish, coral reefs, marine plants, and water
                              pollution effects.




               Teacher's Strategies


                      Hands-On Learning: This activity is hands-on, engaging students in a tactile project
                       that reinforces their understanding of the marine ecosystem. By building the pyramid,
                       students actively participate and are more likely to retain information.
                      Visual Aids for Reinforcement: Using printed images or facts about marine life on
                       each face of the pyramid provides visual aids, which help students connect the
                       structural sides of the pyramid to specific parts of the marine ecosystem.
                      Collaboration and Peer Support: Students can work in small groups, supporting
                       each other with measuring, cutting, and assembling. This promotes teamwork, as well
                       as communication and problem-solving skills.
                      Reflection and Discussion: After constructing the pyramid, students can discuss
                       what each side represents and explain why each part of the ecosystem is important.
                       This reflection helps reinforce learning and allows students to share insights with their
                       peers.
                      Real-World Connections: By connecting the physical pyramid with elements of the
                       marine ecosystem, students see how different parts of an ecosystem work together,
                       encouraging them to think about the relationships within ecosystems and the
                       importance of protecting marine life.


                 Challenge


               This activity is an optional extension, intended to be introduced to students as a bonus task they can
               work on independently if they wish. It is not required to be completed during the session.






























                                                           13]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[UNIT 01 [Beginner]

          Chapter 01: Mechanics

          LESSON 02: Engineering Design Process.


          Time frame: 15mins


               Story



               Apply the same strategies used in Part 1 of the story.


            Story Reflection


               Understanding the Role of Environmental Engineers


               Overview:
               Environmental engineers help to protect and improve the environment by applying scientific
               principles to solve ecological challenges. Their work is essential in maintaining clean air,
               water, and soil, which directly impacts human health and ecosystems.

               Objectives:


                      Help students understand the importance of environmental engineering in
                       safeguarding natural resources.
                      Enable students to identify key projects and methods used by environmental
                       engineers.
                      Inspire students to think about careers in environmental science and engineering.

               https:��www.youtube.com�watch?v=T2xFDIdjX88


                  Engineering Design Process




               Quickly review the phases of the Engineering Design Process, then encourage students to focus on
               the Ask and Brainstorming stages until they settle on a project idea. Remind them that there are no
               right or wrong answers for this step—it's all about exploring possibilities�








                  What solutions can we explore to                Building a water floater to collect waste.
                  address pollution in marine ecosystems?













                                                           14]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[You will revisit the Engineering Design Process throughout the entire project.
            UNIT 01 [Beginner]
            Chapter 01: Mechanics

            LESSON 03: Design Your Floater.


            Time frame: 45 mins



               Stepping Stone.
               You need to know ..                            You will be able to..
               Basic Principles of Engineering Design process.   Build Waste floater.
               Types of Materials.                            Choose the best material and design for floater.
               Definition of Force.                           Define force of bouncy and see its effect on
                                                              floater.

                Story




               Apply the same strategies used in Part 1 of the story.


                Let’s Think




               In the Think section of the teacher guide, students will brainstorm ideas to answer key questions
               about designing a waste-collecting device for water. Here are possible responses and teaching
               strategies to guide this brainstorming session.

               Questions and Possible Answers


                   1.  How does our floater stay above water?
                          o  Possible Answers:
                                    Use lightweight, buoyant materials like plastic or foam.
                                    Design with a wide base to improve stability.
                                    Add air-filled compartments or sealed containers to increase buoyancy.
                   2.  What is our plan for collecting the waste?
                          o  Possible Answers:
                                    Use a net or mesh to scoop waste from the water.
                                    Create a funnel system to direct floating waste into a collection area.
                                    Design a conveyor belt or rotating mechanism to gather waste
                                     efficiently.
                   3.  What method will we use to make it move in the water? Will it be manual or
                       electric?
                          o  Possible Answers:
                                    Attach paddles or small propellers powered by solar energy or
                                     batteries.
                                    Design a hand-operated paddle or lever system.





                                                           15]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Consider attaching it to a remote-controlled motor for precision.
                   4.  How will we store the waste we've collected so it can be recycled?
                          o  Possible Answers:
                                    Use detachable compartments that can be emptied easily.
                                    Design a container with sections to separate recyclable and non-
                                     recyclable items.
                                    Include a cover or lid to prevent waste from falling back into the water.




               Teaching Strategies for This Section


                   1.  Guided Brainstorming
                          o  Activity: Lead students through each question, encouraging them to share
                              their ideas. Write ideas on the board to visually map out possibilities.
                          o  Purpose: Helps students feel comfortable sharing different ideas, recognizing
                              there is no single "right" answer, and fostering creativity.
                   2.  Think-Pair-Share
                          o  Activity: Have students think individually, then discuss ideas with a partner
                              before sharing with the class. For each question, ask a few pairs to share their
                              ideas.
                          o  Purpose: Encourages collaborative thinking and allows quieter students to
                              feel more confident before presenting to the group.
                   3.  Visual Brainstorming (Sketching)
                          o  Activity: Ask students to sketch possible designs for each question, especially
                              for flotation or movement ideas. Students can then share their drawings with
                              the class.
                          o  Purpose: Visual thinking helps students conceptualize and communicate ideas
                              they might struggle to explain verbally, enriching the brainstorming process.
                   4.  Question Prompts and Scaffolding
                          o  Activity: For each question, provide additional prompts to guide deeper
                              thinking (e.g., "What materials would float best?" or "How can we power this
                              sustainably?").
                          o  Purpose: Supports critical thinking by encouraging students to consider
                              factors like materials, power sources, and sustainability.
                   5.  Role-Based Ideation
                          o  Activity: Assign each student or group a "role" (e.g., designer, engineer,
                              environmentalist) and have them think from that perspective as they
                              brainstorm.
                          o  Purpose: Fosters empathy and broadens students' viewpoints by helping them
                              consider multiple angles in problem-solving.

















                                                           16]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Explore




                  Do it

               https:��copilot.microsoft.com�


               Assist students in crafting an effective prompt that aligns with the specific eco-bot they envision.

                 Watch it


               https:��www.youtube.com�watch?v=6j2lWCx7QR8


               To help students engage with this video effectively, you can use these strategies:

               1. Visual Comparison Activity


                      Activity: Have students watch the video and observe the real floater’s design. After
                       watching, prompt them to compare it with the eco-bot they imagined earlier.
                      Instructions: Ask students to note similarities and differences between their designs
                       and the real floater, focusing on structure, movement, and waste-collection methods.
                      Purpose: This helps students refine their ideas, see practical engineering applications,
                       and understand how their designs might be improved.


               2. Guided Note-Taking


                      Activity: Before starting the video, provide students with a simple worksheet or list of
                       questions to guide their observation. Include prompts like:
                          o  What are the main parts of the floater?
                          o  How does it move in the water?
                          o  What materials are used?
                          o  How does it collect and store waste?
                      Purpose: This helps students focus on specific elements while watching, reinforcing
                       observation and attention to detail.

               3. Group Discussion and Reflection


                      Activity: After watching the video, organize students into small groups to discuss
                       their observations. Encourage them to share how the real floater’s parts and
                       mechanisms compare with their ideas.
                      Purpose: This promotes critical thinking and allows students to reflect on design
                       feasibility, encouraging collaborative evaluation of ideas.

               4. Parts Identification Exercise


                      Activity: Ask students to write down the main parts of the floater seen in the video
                       and briefly describe each part’s purpose or function.
                      Purpose: This deepens students' understanding of the floater’s components, preparing
                       them to integrate effective parts into their designs.







                                                           17]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Read about it




               Here are several reading strategies to use while students engage with the article about the AI-
               enabled robotic boat:


               1. Previewing the Text


                      Activity: Before reading, have students skim the article to get an overview. They can
                       look at headings, subheadings, images, and captions.
                      Purpose: This prepares students for the content and context, helping them formulate
                       questions or predictions about what they will learn.

               2. Chunking the Text


                      Activity: Divide the article into sections (paragraphs or key ideas) and have students
                       read each chunk separately, summarizing the main idea of each part before moving
                       on.
                      Purpose: This breaks down the reading into manageable parts, making it easier for
                       students to process information and retain key concepts.

               3. Think-Alouds


                      Activity: Model think-alouds by verbalizing your thoughts as you read certain
                       passages. Encourage students to do the same in pairs or small groups, sharing their
                       thoughts on what they are reading.
                      Purpose: This strategy helps students develop comprehension skills by demonstrating
                       how to analyze and reflect on the text as they read.

               4. Graphic Organizers


                      Activity: Provide students with a graphic organizer, such as a Venn diagram or a
                       concept map, to visually map out information as they read.
                      Purpose: Visual aids help students organize their thoughts, clarify relationships
                       between concepts, and synthesize information from the text.


               5. Questioning the Text

                      Activity: Have students generate questions about the content as they read. They can
                       focus on the "who, what, when, where, why, and how" of the article.
                      Purpose: This encourages critical thinking and helps students engage more deeply
                       with the material, leading to better comprehension and retention.

               6. Collaborative Reading


                      Activity: Arrange students into small groups to read the article together, discussing
                       and clarifying sections as they go.
                      Purpose: Collaborative reading allows students to share insights and explanations,
                       which can enhance understanding and build confidence.







                                                           18]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[7. Post-Reading Reflection

                      Activity: After reading, have students write a brief reflection on what they learned,
                       including any surprising facts or ideas they found particularly interesting.
                      Purpose: This encourages students to process the information and articulate their
                       understanding, reinforcing key concepts from the article.

                        Assessment



                 Focus


               Fill in the gaps to complete the floater parts.










                                                                                 Waste Bin



                                                                                       Conveyor belt








               Propeller














               For the question "Fill in the gaps to complete the floater parts," here are some effective
               strategies suitable for Grade 5 students:


               1. Guided Group Activity

                      Activity: Organize students into small groups and provide each group with a
                       worksheet that includes sentences or diagrams with missing parts related to the
                       floater's components. Encourage them to discuss and collaborate to fill in the gaps.
                      Purpose: This promotes teamwork and communication skills while allowing students
                       to learn from one another.






                                                           19]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[2. Visual Aids

                      Activity: Use images or diagrams of a floater, highlighting different parts. As
                       students fill in the gaps, they can refer to these visuals to understand how each part
                       functions.
                      Purpose: Visual aids help reinforce learning and make abstract concepts more
                       concrete.


               3. Think-Pair-Share


                      Activity: Have students first think individually about what goes in the gaps. Then,
                       they can pair up to discuss their thoughts before sharing with the class.
                      Purpose: This encourages independent thinking followed by collaboration, allowing
                       students to refine their ideas before presenting them.

               4. Word Bank


                      Activity: Provide a word bank with key terms related to the floater’s parts. Students
                       can use this bank to help fill in the gaps.
                      Purpose: A word bank offers support, making it easier for students to recall
                       terminology and apply it correctly.


                 Practice



               Encourage students to use their imagination with this question.



              Challenge


               This activity is an optional extension, intended to be introduced to students as a bonus task they can
               work on independently if they wish. It is not required to be completed during the session.

                   EDP




               Return back to the EDP paper and add the design they made and the parts they will add to
               the plan part.

















                                                           20]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[UNIT 01 [Beginner]


           Chapter 01: Mechanics
           LESSON 04: Choose Your Materials.



           Time frame: 45 mins

               Story



               Apply the same strategies used in Part 1 of the story.


              Think and Do it



               Sink or Float Activity


               Objective:

               Students will predict and test whether a variety of materials will sink or float in water.




               Materials Needed:


                      A container filled with water (e.g., a large tub or sink)
                      The following items:
                          o  Plastic bottles
                          o  Metal nails
                          o  Wooden sticks
                          o  Rubber bands
                          o  Foam pieces
                      Paper and pencils for recording observations

               Steps:


                   1.  Introduction to Concepts:
                          o  Begin by discussing the concepts of density with the students. Explain that
                              objects denser than water will sink, while those less dense will float.
                   2.  List of Materials:
                          o  Present the following list of materials to the students:
                                    Plastic bottles
                                    Metal nails
                                    Wooden sticks
                                    Rubber bands
                                    Foam pieces
                   3.  Make Predictions:
                          o  Ask students to predict whether each item will sink or float. Have them write
                              their predictions in a table with two columns: Sink and Float. For example:





                                                           21]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[4.  Testing the Materials:
                          o  Instruct students to carefully place each item into the water one at a time.
                          o  Observe the behavior of each item as they place it in the water.
                   5.  Record Observations:
                          o  Have students record their observations in their tables, marking whether each
                              item sank or floated. For example:

                                   Item      Sink Float
                              Plastic bottles

                              Metal nails
                              Wooden sticks
                              Rubber bands

                              Foam pieces


                   6.  Discussion:
                          o  After testing all materials, hold a class discussion about the results. Ask
                              questions like:
                                    Which items floated? Why do you think that is?
                                    Which items sank? What does that tell us about their density?
                                    Were there any surprises in your predictions vs. the results?
                   7.  Conclusion:
                          o  Summarize the activity by reinforcing the concept and density. Discuss how
                              understanding this concept can help in real-world applications, such as
                              designing boats.



                   Explore



              Watch it



               https:��www.youtube.com�watch?v=2dyCe1GPagE


               To effectively explain the video and engage students, consider these strategies:

                   1.  Pre-Viewing Discussion:
                          o  Start with a brief discussion about the video topic. Ask students what they
                              know about it or their initial thoughts. This activates prior knowledge and
                              builds interest.
                   2.  Set a Purpose:
                          o  Give students specific questions to think about while watching the video. For
                              example, “What are the main points discussed?” or “How does the video relate
                              to our current topic?” This helps focus their attention.
                   3.  Pause for Reflection:









                                                           22]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[o  Pause the video at key moments to discuss what has been shown. Encourage
                              students to share their thoughts and ask questions. This keeps them engaged
                              and allows for deeper understanding.
                   4.  Interactive Elements:
                          o  Incorporate interactive elements, such as polls or quizzes, during or after the
                              video. Tools like Kahoot or Mentimeter can make this fun and engaging.

                 Do it


               Which is the best floater



               Materials Needed:

                      Wood
                      Foam
                      Plastic Bottle
                      PVC


               Steps to Follow:

                   1.  Gather Materials:
                          o  Obtain a transparent water basin or a large clear container.
                          o  Collect the materials you will be testing: wood, foam, plastic bottle, and PVC.
                   2.  Testing Wood:
                          o  Gently place a piece of wood into the water basin.
                          o  Observation: Check whether the wood floats or sinks. Note whether it floats
                              well or partially.
                   3.  Testing Foam:
                          o  Add a piece of foam to the water basin next.
                          o  Observation: Observe how the foam behaves in the water. Determine if it
                              floats easily and whether it stays afloat or sinks.
                   4.  Testing Plastic Bottle:
                          o  Insert an empty plastic bottle into the water basin.
                          o  Observation: Monitor the behavior of the plastic bottle. Note if it floats and if
                              it remains upright or moves around.
                   5.  Testing PVC Material:
                          o  Finally, add the PVC material to the water basin.
                          o  Observation: Observe how the PVC interacts with the water. Check if it
                              floats or sinks and whether it remains afloat easily.


               What to Observe:

                      Floating Ability: Does the material float or sink?
                      Stability: Does the floating material remain stable and upright, or does it tip over?
                      Buoyancy: How effectively does each material support its own weight in the water?

               Results and Analysis:


               After testing each material, compare your observations:





                                                           23]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[1.  Wood:
                          o  Floating Ability: Typically floats because it is less dense than water.
                          o  Stability: Can be stable, but may tip over if not balanced.
                          o  Buoyancy: Good buoyancy; effectively supports its weight.
                   2.  Foam:
                          o  Floating Ability: Floats very well due to its low density.
                          o  Stability: Stays upright and stable, making it ideal for flotation.
                          o  Buoyancy: Excellent buoyancy; supports significant weight without sinking.
                   3.  Plastic Bottle:
                          o  Floating Ability: Floats easily when empty.
                          o  Stability: Can remain upright but may tip over depending on water
                              movement.
                          o  Buoyancy: Good buoyancy; effectively supports its weight.
                   4.  PVC:
                          o  Floating Ability: Generally floats, but buoyancy can vary based on density.
                          o  Stability: Often stable and upright if designed correctly, but shape can affect
                              this.
                          o  Buoyancy: Generally good buoyancy; supports weight but may not be as
                              effective as foam or wood.

               Conclusion:


                      Best Floating Material: Foam floats the best due to its low density and excellent
                       buoyancy.
                      Most Stable Material: Foam is typically the most stable and remains upright easily.
                      Best Buoyancy: Foam also demonstrates the best buoyancy, efficiently supporting
                       weight without sinking.

               Now it’s your turn to decide which material are you going to use?


               Let the students answer this question by themselves according to the results of

               the experiment.

                    EDP


               Return back to the EDP paper and add the materials they are

               going to use to the plan part.



















                                                           24]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[UNIT 01 [Beginner]
           Chapter 01: Mechanics

           LESSON 05: Best Design for Your Floater.



           Time frame: 90 mins



                  Story

               Apply the same strategies used in Part 1 of the story.


                  Think



               1. What Will Make the Floater Float Well?

               Possible Solutions:


                      Use Light Materials: Choose materials that are light and can float, like foam or
                       empty plastic bottles.
                      Good Shape: Make the floater wide and flat at the bottom to help it stay balanced and
                       not tip over.
                      Add Buoyancy: Include items that can hold air, like sealed containers, to help it float
                       better.
                      Even Weight: Make sure the weight on the floater is spread out evenly so it doesn’t
                       sink on one side.

               2. How Much Weight Can It Hold?


               Possible Solutions:


                      Weight Testing: Students can add small weights (like coins or washers) to the floater
                       one by one and see how much it can hold before it sinks.
                      Understanding Buoyancy: Explain that when the floater displaces water, it can hold
                       a certain weight without sinking, and this is called buoyancy.
                      Material Strength: Talk about how strong the materials are and how that affects how
                       much weight the floater can carry.


                  Explore



                Do it















                                                           25]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Materials Needed:

                      Modeling Materials: Use materials like cardboard, foam, or plastic
                       sheets for building prototypes. For a more hands-on approach, you

                       might use blocks of wood or hollow logs if you have access.
                      Weights: Small weights or objects that can be added to test buoyancy.
                      Bathtub or Large Water Container: To test the floaters.
                      Measuring Tools: Ruler or measuring tape for accurate sizing.
                      Design Tools: Pencils, markers, or software for sketching designs
                       (optional).


               Steps to Follow:


                   1.  Create Models of Different Sizes:
                          o  Design Prototypes: Using your chosen materials (cardboard,
                              foam, plastic), create several models of floaters with the same
                              shape but different sizes. For example, if you’re designing a
                              rectangular floater, make a few with varying lengths, widths, and
                              heights.

                          o  Mirror Images: Ensure that each model is symmetrical or has
                              mirror image sides. This helps in assessing how balanced the
                              floater is.
                   2.  Design Considerations:
                          o  Solid vs. Hollow: Consider the difference between a solid block
                              (like a thick piece of wood) and a hollow structure (like a hollow
                              log or a boat hull). A hollow design often provides better
                              buoyancy.

                          o  Adjust Designs: Experiment with different designs. For example,
                              you might compare a solid block with a hollowed-out version of
                              the same size to see how the shape affects floating.
                   3.  Test for Balance and Buoyancy:
                          o  Add Weights: Gradually add different weights to your floaters to
                              test how they handle extra load. This will help determine the best
                              balance between floating high and staying steady.

                          o  Observe Performance: Note how each design performs with
                              added weights. Does it float high or does it sink slightly? Is it
                              stable or does it tip over easily?
                   4.  Test in a Bathtub:
                          o  Place Floaters in Water: Fill a bathtub or large container with
                              water and place each floater model in it.









                                                           26]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[o  Observation: Watch how each model behaves in the water. Check
                              for stability, how much of the floater is above the water, and how
                              it handles additional weights.


               Write Your Observations:

                      Floating Height: Record how high or low each model floats. Does a

                       larger model float higher than a smaller one?
                      Stability: Note if the floater remains steady or tilts. How does it react to
                       different weights?
                      Design Effectiveness: Compare the solid versus hollow designs. Which
                       provides better buoyancy and stability?


               Write Your Conclusion:


                      Best Design: Based on your observations, determine which design is the
                       best. Was a certain size or shape more effective? Did the hollow or solid
                       model perform better?
                      Balance and Buoyancy: Summarize the balance between floating high
                       and staying steady. Which model achieved the best balance?
                      Recommendations: Suggest any improvements or modifications that
                       could enhance the floater's performance. For example, would adjusting

                       the size or shape improve stability?

               This process helps you understand how different designs and materials affect
               buoyancy and stability, providing a practical approach to creating effective

               floaters.

                  Watch it


               https:��www.youtube.com�watch


               1. Previewing the Video


                      Activity: Before starting the video, discuss what buoyancy means and ask students
                       what they already know about floating and sinking. Introduce any key vocabulary
                       they will encounter in the video.
                      Purpose: This sets the context and prepares students to look for specific information
                       while watching.

               2. Guided Viewing












                                                           27]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Activity: Play the video in short segments, pausing at key moments to ask questions
                       and facilitate discussions. For example, pause after demonstrations of buoyancy and
                       ask:
                          o  What did you see happening?
                          o  Why do you think that object floated or sank?
                      Purpose: This encourages students to think critically about what they are watching
                       and helps them process the information.


               3. Interactive Note-Taking

                      Activity: Provide students with a graphic organizer or note-taking guide where they
                       can jot down important points, examples of buoyant and non-buoyant objects, and any
                       questions they have.
                      Purpose: This keeps students engaged and helps them organize their thoughts for
                       later discussion.


               4. Real-World Connections

                      Activity: After watching, ask students to think about real-world examples of
                       buoyancy they’ve seen, such as boats, life jackets, or floating toys. Discuss how
                       understanding buoyancy is important in these contexts.
                      Purpose: Connecting the video content to their everyday experiences enhances
                       understanding and relevance.


               5. Discussion Questions

                      Activity: After viewing, lead a discussion using open-ended questions. For example:
                          o  What surprised you in the video?
                          o  Can you think of other examples of buoyancy in nature?
                          o  How does buoyancy affect our daily lives?
                      Purpose: This encourages deeper thinking and allows students to express their ideas
                       and insights.

               6. Post-Viewing Reflection


                      Activity: Have students write a short reflection or summary of what they learned
                       from the video. They can include a drawing of an object they think would float or sink
                       and explain why.
                      Purpose: Writing helps reinforce learning and allows students to articulate their
                       understanding.

               EDP


               Return back to the EDP paper and add the design you’re going to make in create part.













                                                           28]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Show Case


                https:��youtu.be�kqCRbDLWMh0?si=Xv7CvKnyDQ7rk0W5


               Step 1: The boat body

               Sunboard Instructions:


                   1.  Cut the Foam Shapes

                      Cut a rectangle of foam measuring 40cm in width and 30cm in
                       length.
                      Then cut the top part of it as shown in a picture.
                      Cut out another identical shape.
                      Prepare the following rectangles:
                             Two rectangles measuring 7cm in width and 3cm in height.
                             Two rectangles measuring 25cm in width and 3cm in height.
                             One rectangle measuring 30cm in width and 3cm in height.
                             One rectangle measuring 20cm in width and 3cm in height.




               2.      Assemble the Sunboard

                      Use a glue gun or other suitable adhesive to attach the shapes together according to
                       the provided image.









































                                                           29]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[UNIT 01 [Beginner]
           Chapter 02: Electricity

           LESSON 01: Navigate Your Floater.


           Time frame: 90 mins



               Stepping Stone.
               You need to know ..                            You will be able to..
               How electricity works.                         Identify voltage and current how to measure
                                                              them.
               Basic circuit components (LED- Resistor- Battery-  Create more complicated circuit on a
               Switch).                                       breadboard.
               Connecting circuits on smart pad, and          Control the speed of a motor.
               breadboard.

               Understanding of series and parallel circuits.

                 Story



               Apply the same strategies used in Part 1 of the story.

                 Think


               Think of how series and parallel connections efficient  light bulb brightness. This knowledge will help
               design a safe, efficient classroom lighting system using LEDs, a smart pad, and resistors.

               Procedures:

               1- Divide students into groups of 3to 5 students.

               2- Distribute the smartpads.










               3- Give the needed electric components (LEDs- Wires- Resistors)


               4- Set a specific time for them to apply the circuit.

               Key Guide for the teachers..








                                                           30]]></page></pages></Search>