<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="7"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Unit




                3






           Lesson


                 1






          Beyond Imagination


          Beep & Go! Guiding the Way.











                                         Ready, Set, Learn!



                                         You Need to Know

                                            •  Basic understanding of how to connect a simple circuit
                                               with a battery, wires, and a switch.

                                            •  Basic components of a circuit (e.g., buzzers, push buttons).
                                            •  How to count numbers, especially within a range like 1 to
                                               20.

                                            •  How a push button works (pressing it to complete a
                                               circuit).
                                         You will be able to:


                                            •  Explain how sound can be used to help visually impaired
                                               people navigate safely.
                                            •  Design a simple sound-guided path using buzzers and
                                               push buttons.
                                            •  Use addition and subtraction to calculate distances
                                               between buzzers on the sound-guided path.

                                            •  Describe how community helpers, such as city planners
                                               and engineers, use sound to assist people with visual
                                               impairments.


                                                                                                            49]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Ms. Sara: “Imagine you're at the playground, but you can't see where to go. How can we
          help children who can’t see move around safely?”

          Adam: “Maybe we can use sounds to guide them!”

          Laila: “Like a special beep that tells them where to go!”

          Khaled: “What if they press a button, and it makes a sound to show them the way?”

          Ms. Sara: “That’s a great idea! What can we use to make a sound when someone pushes the
          button?”

          Adam: “A buzzer! It makes a loud beep!”

          Laila: “We can make a path with buttons and buzzers so they can follow the sounds!”

          Ms. Sara: “Great thinking! Let’s design a smart playground with sound-guided paths!”
























          50]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Let’s

            Think!



          How do community helpers use sounds to help people
          who can't see?

          Check all that apply:
                 Buzzers on sidewalks tell us where to go.

                 Flashing lights tell us where to go.

                 Traffic lights make sounds to say when to stop or go.
                 Smartphones can talk to us and guide our way.

                 Beacons in buildings help us find rooms and exits.
                 Talking walls give directions.

                 Loud music plays everywhere to help us hear better.
                 Headsets give directions using sounds.
                                                                              Figure 31: A blind man using a
                 Colorful signs show the way.                                white cane to walk safely with the
                                                                              help of sound signals in the city.
            Explorer’s

            Toolkit





                 DIY Lab

          Hello, young engineers!
          Let’s explore how sound can help someone walk safely
          along a path.

          What to do:

            •  We’ll gently cover your eyes with a soft cloth.
            •  Start at the beginning of the path.

            •  Your partner will press a button to make a sound.
            •  Listen closely… then walk toward the sound!

          Let’s Talk About It:
          1 .  How did the sound help you?


                 It showed me where to go.
                 It made me feel confused.

                 It helped me find the next button.
                 It didn’t help me at all.






                                                                                                            51]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[2 .  What if there were no sounds?

                 I wouldn’t know which way to go.

                 I could still find the path easily.
                 I might get lost.

                 I might walk the wrong way.


                Screen Lessons

          Let’s watch this video to learn more about adding and subtracting. It will help us
          make our road even better.

                https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NHI0ePgwlgU























                                        Figure 32: A girl and a boy learning about adding
                                            and subtracting with fun math symbols.


                                             Hey flriends

                                             let’s wrap up!




          Addition means putting numbers together, and
          subtraction means taking away.

          We use these math skills to help us count steps,
          measure paths, and make our safe sound road
          even smarter!




















          52]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Assessment





                   Apprentice

          Let’s have fun with addition and subtraction by playing this exciting game!
                https://www.abcya.com/games/math_match




























                           Figure 33: Interface of a math game called “Monster Mansion Match.”

                      Builder

           Let’s Plan Our Sound Path!

            •  Choose where you want to build your path.

            •  Think about the best places to put each sound button.


















                                       Figure 34: A colorful playground with a path
                                         for planning sound button placements.

            •  Walk from one button spot to the next — count how many steps you take.











                                                                                                            53]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[•  Add up all your steps to find out how long the full path is.









            •  Take away (subtract) to see how many steps are between each button.











                Showcase

          Now it's time to build our button and buzzer circuit! Let’s put each one in the spots we
          picked during our last activity.

                                               Push Button

                                                                  Buzzer











                    Battery




                     Figure 35: A simple button and buzzer circuit connected to a battery, placed on a
                                                 DIY playground model.






                              Great job on your design!






          Now let’s go back to the EDP steps. It’s
          time to move to the plan part and add
          this.                                                                                  Name:
                                                                                                 Project:
                                                                                                  Ask
                                                                                                           Imagine
                                                                                                   Plan

                                                                                                           Create
                                                                                                  Improve






          54]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Now I Can

                Sound helping visually impaired people move safely.                                    

                Design a sound-guided path with buzzers and push buttons.                              

                Use addition and subtraction to figure out the distances between buzzers.  
                How community helpers, like city planners and engineers, use sound to
                help people with visual impairments.                                                   













































































                                                                                                            55]]></page></pages></Search>