<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="13"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Theme 1



               [Insert Theme Name]




               Learning Outcomes


               By the end of this theme, students will be able to:

                   1.  [Outcome1]
                   2.  [Outcome 2]
                   3.  [Outcome 3]







































































                            "What might happen if the car responds too slowly or erratically to the commands?"
                          (This allows students to think critically about issues like lag or unreliability, which may
                              affect the car’s performance.)
                          Conclude with Evaluative Questions:

                            "How can we ensure that the car responds quickly and reliably, even when it’s far away
                              from the mobile device?"
                          (This question encourages students to apply their understanding of Bluetooth and potential
                              solutions, such as signal strength, interference, or improving the system’s communication
                              protocols.)
                            "What strategies or technologies do you think could improve the reliability of
                              communication between the car and the mobile app?"
                              (This could lead to discussions on optimizing Bluetooth range, using stronger signals, or
                              considering other wireless communication methods like Wi-Fi.)



                       o  Question Wall Strategy:
                          Implementation for the Engage Part of the Lesson:


                          Objective: To encourage students to generate questions and reflections about the problem of
                          making the remote-controlled car respond quickly and reliably, and to explore their thinking
                          as a group


                          Set Up the Question Board:

                          1)Before the lesson begins, set up the board in the classroom where students can write down
                          their questions or thoughts.

                          2) Introduce the Question: How can we make the remote control car respond quickly and
                          reliably to commands sent from the mobile app, even when the car is far away?
                          3) Provide Sticky Notes and Instructions.
                          4) Group Discussion:
                             Divide students into groups and give them time to discuss with each other then let them stick their
                          answers on the board





               3. Explore

                     Teacher Role:
                       Guiding the Exploration:

                       o  Provide clear instructions:
                          Explain the task: "Now, we'll start connecting the components and learning about how to
                          control motor speed using PWM."
                       o  Demonstrate safety practices:
                          Emphasize safety rules regarding electrical components, especially when working with
                          batteries.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Lesson Plan


               1. Engage

                     Teacher Role:

                          o  Activate Prior Knowledge: The teacher should help students connect the project to their
                              existing knowledge and experiences. This can be done by:

                                Asking students to brainstorm ideas about how to control a car remotely
                                Discussing the different components used in the project and their functions
                                Relating the project to other technologies that students are familiar with, such as
                                 video games or remote-controlled toys.

                          o  Use engaging strategies (e.g., showing visuals, asking questions) to spark curiosity.
                          o  Provide support during discussions and encourage diverse viewpoints.
                     Expected From Students:
                          o  Active Participation in Brainstorming: Students should actively contribute ideas about
                              how to control a car remotely. This includes:

                                Offering suggestions, even if they seem unconventional.
                                Building upon each other's ideas.
                                Respectfully considering different viewpoints.
                                Examples: "Maybe we could use a remote control?", "What about a phone app?",
                                 "Could we use signals like radio waves?"
                          o  Connecting to Prior Knowledge: Students should make connections between the project
                              and their existing knowledge of technology
                     Parts of the books included.

























                     Introduction:
                          o  The "Real-World Application" Hook

                                The Hook: Show a short (10 second) video clip of a real-world application of remote-
                                 controlled technology. Example:]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[  A drone delivering a package.
                                 https://youtube.com/shorts/KbYCNYaHphM?si=C2UxZDTAOilyKReg

                                The Preview: Briefly explain that these technologies rely on similar principles to what they
                                 will be learning.
                                The Question: Ask: "What are the advantages of being able to control something remotely,
                                 without physically being there?"
                                Connecting to the Lesson: Explain that they will be designing and building a small-scale
                                 remote-controlled car using Bluetooth, just like some of these real-world examples.
                          o  Show and Tell & Picture Walk:
                                        Bring out the actual components of the robotic car:
                                Arduino Uno
                                (2)Motors
                                L298N Motor Driver
                                Battery
                                Bluetooth Module

                                 Show a simple picture of a basic circuit diagram showing how the components
                                 connect.
                                (Picture Walk): Display larger, clearer images or diagrams of each component.
                                 Briefly explain the function of each one in simple terms, relating it back to the
                                 idea of controlling the car remotely. For example, "The Bluetooth module
                                 receives signals from your phone, telling the Arduino what to do."

                   Reflection:
                       Purpose of Reflection:
                       Encourages critical thinking and helps students connect story themes to lesson objectives.



               2. Think

                     Questions
                       How can we make the remote control car respond qquickly and reliably to commands sent from
                       the mobile app, even when the car is far away?
                     Strategy:
                          o  Scaffold Strategy: Ask scaffolded questions to lead students to a deeper understanding.

                          Begin with Simple Recall Questions:

                            "What components do we use in the car to make it move?"
                          (This helps students recall basic elements like motors, motor drivers, and controllers involved
                              in the car’s movement.)
                            "What do you think Bluetooth is used for in this system?"
                          (This question encourages students to recall how Bluetooth facilitates communication
                              between the car and the mobile phone.)
                          Progress to More Analytical Questions:
                            "Why do you think the car needs to respond quickly to commands from the mobile app?"
                          (This question helps students think about the importance of responsiveness in controlling the
                              car, especially in tasks like navigation or avoiding obstacles.)]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[  "What might happen if the car responds too slowly or erratically to the commands?"
                          (This allows students to think critically about issues like lag or unreliability, which may
                              affect the car’s performance.)
                          Conclude with Evaluative Questions:

                            "How can we ensure that the car responds quickly and reliably, even when it’s far away
                              from the mobile device?"
                          (This question encourages students to apply their understanding of Bluetooth and potential
                              solutions, such as signal strength, interference, or improving the system’s communication
                              protocols.)
                            "What strategies or technologies do you think could improve the reliability of
                              communication between the car and the mobile app?"
                              (This could lead to discussions on optimizing Bluetooth range, using stronger signals, or
                              considering other wireless communication methods like Wi-Fi.)



                       o  Question Wall Strategy:
                          Implementation for the Engage Part of the Lesson:

                          Objective: To encourage students to generate questions and reflections about the problem of
                          making the remote-controlled car respond quickly and reliably, and to explore their thinking
                          as a group

                          Set Up the Question Board:


                          1)Before the lesson begins, set up the board in the classroom where students can write down
                          their questions or thoughts.


                          2) Introduce the Question: How can we make the remote control car respond quickly and
                          reliably to commands sent from the mobile app, even when the car is far away?
                          3) Provide Sticky Notes and Instructions.
                          4) Group Discussion:
                             Divide students into groups and give them time to discuss with each other then let them stick their
                          answers on the board




               3. Explore

                     Teacher Role:
                       Guiding the Exploration:

                       o  Provide clear instructions:
                          Explain the task: "Now, we'll start connecting the components and learning about how to
                          control motor speed using PWM."
                       o  Demonstrate safety practices:
                          Emphasize safety rules regarding electrical components, especially when working with
                          batteries.]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[o  Facilitate connections:
                          Help students connect the motors, motor driver, and battery according to the circuit diagram.
                       o  Play the prepared video on PWM in Arduino.
                          https://youtu.be/7OYLakRyjTc?si=sTPXokQCRRnFqO2U
                       o  Ask guiding questions:
                       "What do you think will happen if we change the PWM values in the Arduino code?"
                       "How can we use PWM to control the speed of the motors?"
                       "What might happen if the PWM value is too high or too low?"
                       o  Encourage experimentation:
                          Encourage students to try different PWM values and observe the motor's behavior.
                        Monitoring and Support:

                       o  Circulate around the classroom: Observe student work and provide individual assistance as
                          needed.
                       o  Encourage collaboration: Foster a collaborative learning environment where students can
                          help each other.


                     Expected From Students:
                       o  Correctly wired circuit with motor, motor driver, and power.
                       o  Notes from the PWM video summarizing the key concepts.
                       o  Understand of how PWM works and how it affects motor speed.
                     Parts of the books included.

























































               4. Explain

                     Teacher Role:
                       Provide Direct Instruction:

                       Introduce the Key Components: The teacher will introduce and explain the function of each
                       component of the robotic car: Arduino Uno, motors, L298N motor driver, Bluetooth module, and
                       the battery.
                              o  Arduino Uno: A microcontroller that acts as the brain of the car, controlling inputs
                                 (e.g., Bluetooth signals) and outputs (e.g., motor movements).
                              o  Motors: The motors allow the car to move by turning the wheels. They are controlled
                                 through the L298N motor driver.
                              o  L298N Motor Driver: This component is responsible for controlling the direction and
                                 speed of the motors based on signals from the Arduino.
                              o  Bluetooth Module: This allows the car to communicate wirelessly with a mobile
                                 device.
                              o  Battery: Powers the car’s electronics and motors.
                       Explain How They Work Together: The teacher will guide students through the flow of
                       information and power:
                              The mobile app sends commands to the Bluetooth module.
                              The Bluetooth module transmits the signal to the Arduino.
                              The Arduino processes the signal and sends appropriate commands to the motor driver.
                              The motor driver controls the motors, which in turn moves the car.


                       Ask students to explain the process in their own words, prompting them with questions
                       like:
                       "How does the mobile app send commands to the car?"
                       "What role does the Arduino play in the communication process?"
                       "How do the motors actually move the car based on the signals they receive?"
                     Parts of the books included.
                   https://youtu.be/7OYLakRyjTc?si=sTPXokQCRRnFqO2U]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[  Activity - Do It:
                            Materials Needed
                              2 motors
                              Arduino
                              Bread board
                              Motor driver
                              Jumpers
                              Battery
                              Bluetooth module

                            Step-by-Step Instructions
                              o  Connection
                              Connection
                                Motor Driver Pinout
                                 •  IN1: Control input for Motor 1 (Pin 2 on Arduino)
                                 •  IN2: Control input for Motor 1 (Pin 3 on Arduino)
                                 •  IN3: Control input for Motor 2 (Pin 4 on Arduino)
                                 •  IN4: Control input for Motor 2 (Pin 5 on Arduino)
                                 •  OUT1: Motor 1 connection (connect to one terminal of the first motor)
                                 •  OUT2: Motor 1 connection (connect to the other terminal of the first motor)
                                 •  OUT3: Motor 2 connection (connect to one terminal of the second motor)
                                 •  OUT4: Motor 2 connection (connect to the other terminal of the second motor)
                                Bluetooth Module to Arduino
                                 •  VCC: 5V (from Arduino)
                                 •  GND: Ground (from Arduino)
                                 •  TX: Bluetooth module transmit pin (connect to Arduino RX)
                                 •  RX: Bluetooth module receive pin (connect to Arduino TX)
                                Connect the 5V and GND of the arduino to + and – of the bread board, so any need
                                 for a connection to the 5V or the GND of the Arduino we connect it to the + and – of
                                 the bread board
                              o  Circuit
































                     Expected From Students:
                       Listen Actively: Pay attention to the teacher's explanation of the components and how they work
                          together in the robotic car.

                   Understand and Describe the Process: Be able to explain how each component (Arduino, motors,
                       motor driver, Bluetooth module, and battery) functions and how they interact to make the car
                       work.

                   Collaborate with Peers: Discuss with classmates to check understanding and share ideas about how
                       the system works.

                   Take Notes: Record important information about the components and their roles, which will help in
                       building and understanding the robotic car.






               5. Elaborate

                     Teacher Role:

                          o  Facilitate hands-on exploration by guiding students in assembling the robotic car.
                          o  Encourage critical thinking and problem-solving as students test and modify the car.
                          o  Support group work by answering questions and helping students troubleshoot.
                          o  Introduce challenges or extensions to deepen learning (e.g., modifying code or testing the
                              car's range).
                     Expected From Students:
                          o  Be able to connect the car with the mobile application
                          o  Actively engage in building, testing, and modifying the car.
                          o  Collaborate with peers to solve problems and troubleshoot.
                          o  Apply knowledge to identify and fix issues in the system.
                     Parts of the books included.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[// Define the motor control pins
               int motor1Pin1 = 2;
               int motor1Pin2 = 3;
               int motor2Pin1 = 4;
               int motor2Pin2 = 5;

               void setup() {
                 // Set motor control pins as outputs
                 pinMode(motor1Pin1, OUTPUT);
                 pinMode(motor1Pin2, OUTPUT);
                 pinMode(motor2Pin1, OUTPUT);
                 pinMode(motor2Pin2, OUTPUT);

                 // Start serial communication for Bluetooth
                 Serial.begin(9600);
               }

               void loop() {
                 // Check if data is available from Bluetooth
                 if (Serial.available()) {
                   char command = Serial.read();

                   // Example commands to control motors
                   if (command == 'F') {   // Move Forward
                     digitalWrite(motor1Pin1, HIGH);
                     digitalWrite(motor1Pin2, LOW);
                     digitalWrite(motor2Pin1, HIGH);
                     digitalWrite(motor2Pin2, LOW);
                   }
                   else if (command == 'B') { // Move Backward
                     digitalWrite(motor1Pin1, LOW);
                     digitalWrite(motor1Pin2, HIGH);
                     digitalWrite(motor2Pin1, LOW);
                     digitalWrite(motor2Pin2, HIGH);
                   }
                   else if (command == 'L') { // Turn Left
                     digitalWrite(motor1Pin1, LOW);
                     digitalWrite(motor1Pin2, HIGH);
                     digitalWrite(motor2Pin1, HIGH);
                     digitalWrite(motor2Pin2, LOW);
                   }
                   else if (command == 'R') { // Turn Right
                     digitalWrite(motor1Pin1, HIGH);
                     digitalWrite(motor1Pin2, LOW);
                     digitalWrite(motor2Pin1, LOW);
                     digitalWrite(motor2Pin2, HIGH);
                   }
                   else if (command == 'S') { // Stop
                     digitalWrite(motor1Pin1, LOW);
                     digitalWrite(motor1Pin2, LOW);
                     digitalWrite(motor2Pin1, LOW);
                     digitalWrite(motor2Pin2, LOW);
                   }
                 }
               }]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[  Reflection Questions]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[4. Explain

                     Teacher Role:
                       Provide Direct Instruction:

                       Introduce the Key Components: The teacher will introduce and explain the function of each
                       component of the robotic car: Arduino Uno, motors, L298N motor driver, Bluetooth module, and
                       the battery.
                              o  Arduino Uno: A microcontroller that acts as the brain of the car, controlling inputs
                                 (e.g., Bluetooth signals) and outputs (e.g., motor movements).
                              o  Motors: The motors allow the car to move by turning the wheels. They are controlled
                                 through the L298N motor driver.
                              o  L298N Motor Driver: This component is responsible for controlling the direction and
                                 speed of the motors based on signals from the Arduino.
                              o  Bluetooth Module: This allows the car to communicate wirelessly with a mobile
                                 device.
                              o  Battery: Powers the car’s electronics and motors.
                       Explain How They Work Together: The teacher will guide students through the flow of
                       information and power:
                              The mobile app sends commands to the Bluetooth module.
                              The Bluetooth module transmits the signal to the Arduino.
                              The Arduino processes the signal and sends appropriate commands to the motor driver.
                              The motor driver controls the motors, which in turn moves the car.


                       Ask students to explain the process in their own words, prompting them with questions
                       like:
                       "How does the mobile app send commands to the car?"
                       "What role does the Arduino play in the communication process?"
                       "How do the motors actually move the car based on the signals they receive?"
                     Parts of the books included.
                   https://youtu.be/7OYLakRyjTc?si=sTPXokQCRRnFqO2U]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[  Expected From Students:
                       Listen Actively: Pay attention to the teacher's explanation of the components and how they work
                          together in the robotic car.

                   Understand and Describe the Process: Be able to explain how each component (Arduino, motors,
                       motor driver, Bluetooth module, and battery) functions and how they interact to make the car
                       work.

                   Collaborate with Peers: Discuss with classmates to check understanding and share ideas about how
                       the system works.

                   Take Notes: Record important information about the components and their roles, which will help in
                       building and understanding the robotic car.





               5. Elaborate

                     Teacher Role:

                          o  Facilitate hands-on exploration by guiding students in assembling the robotic car.
                          o  Encourage critical thinking and problem-solving as students test and modify the car.
                          o  Support group work by answering questions and helping students troubleshoot.
                          o  Introduce challenges or extensions to deepen learning (e.g., modifying code or testing the
                              car's range).
                     Expected From Students:
                          o  Be able to connect the car with the mobile application
                          o  Actively engage in building, testing, and modifying the car.
                          o  Collaborate with peers to solve problems and troubleshoot.
                          o  Apply knowledge to identify and fix issues in the system.
                     Parts of the books included.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[6. Evaluate

                     Teacher Role:

                            Design assessment tasks (e.g., testing the car’s responsiveness or troubleshooting).
                            Ask students some questions to make sure they understand the main objectives of the
                              Lesson
                            Encourage self-assessment and peer review, using rubrics or checklists.
                   o  Parts of the books included.]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>