<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="13"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Unit




                3






           Lesson


                2






          Beyond Imagination


          Find Your Way.













                                       Ready, Set, Learn!


                                       You will be able to:


                                          •  Know what coding is and how it helps characters move and
                                             solve problems.
                                          •  Use mBlock to create and play a simple maze game.

                                          •  Use motion blocks to move characters forward, backward,
                                             left, and right.

                                          •  Understand X and Y directions to guide the character
                                             through the maze.

                                          •  Use costumes to change how the character direction.
                                          •  Add clicking events and sensing blocks to make the game
                                             more fun.

                                          •  Put coding steps in the right order (sequencing).
                                          •  Use algorithms to give the character a list of clear steps.












          56]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Ms. Sara: “Let’s create a fun game to help everyone learn how to find their way around!”

          Adam: “Ooh! We can make a game on our tablets!”

          Laila: “What if it’s a maze?”
          Khaled: “And the player is a kid in a wheelchair trying to find the way out!”

          Ms. Sara: “That’s a brilliant idea! ”


            Let’s

            Think!



          Order the Plant’s Life!
          Which happens first, next, and last?

          Match the steps below with the correct order to show how a plant grows.


















                               Figure 36: Pictures showing the different stages of a plant’s
                                               growth from seed to sprout.

                                                                                                            57]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Hello friends!






          we just learned that to make something work, the
          steps need to happen in the right order. Now, let’s
          find out how we can do the same thing when we
          write code!





            Explorer’s

            Toolkit





                 DIY Lab

           Help Khaled Reach the Merry-Go-Round!

          Khaled wants to go to the merry-go-round in the middle of the maze. Can you help him
          find the way? Let’s use an algorithm — that means a list of steps to follow!

          What to do:

              1. Look closely at the maze.
              2. Use the cut-out arrows (or draw your own) to show Khaled’s moves:

                ↑ Move Forward  ← Turn Left   →Turn Right

              3. Put the arrows in the right order — from START to FINISH.
              4. Glue them in the boxes to show each move.

              5. With your teacher, write the steps down like a story:
                   (for example: Forward, Turn Right, Forward...)

          Now Let’s Add a Fun Challenge!
            •  If Khaled turns Left or Right, mark the arrow
               with an “X”.

            •  If he moves Forward or Backward, mark it with “Y”.
          Steps:

            •

            •
            •

            •



                                                                              Figure 37: Maze activity.


          58]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Screen Lessons

           Click on the link to learn more about Sequencing.
                https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zW3YZdPmCnM























                       Figure 38: A coding activity showing a sequence of arrow commands guiding
                                         a character on a grid to reach a red flag.




                                         Wrap-up Time!





          Sequencing means putting steps in the right
          order.

          Algorithm is a list of steps to solve a problem or
          do something.

            •  The X-axis is a line that goes side to side
               (like when you move left and right).

            •  The Y-axis is a line that goes up and down
               (like when you move up and down).



            Assessment






                   Apprentice

          1 .  What does sequencing mean?

            A.  Jumping up and down

            B.  Putting steps in the right order
            C.  Going left and right

            D.  Moving up and down



                                                                                                            59]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[2 .  What is an algorithm?

            A.  A type of robot
            B.  A list of steps to solve a problem or do something

            C.  A type of dance

            D.  A list of favorite foods
          3 .  Which direction does the X-axis go?

            A.  Up and down

            B.  Side to side (left and right)
            C.  Forward and backward

            D.  Around in a circle


                      Builder




















         Figure 39: Khaled in a wheelchair  Figure 40: A colorful maze used      Figure 41: A merry-go-round
              sprite for coding activity.          as the background.            sprite for the coding project.

            •  Use the maze photo and set it as background

            •  Add Khaled and the merry-go round as sprites

            •  Use costumes to change how the character direction.





















                                                      Figure 43: mBlock costume editor showing Khaled’s
                                                          sprite being edited for movement directions.
                Figure 42: Khaled’s sprite moving
                    through a maze in mBlock.



          60]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Showcase

          Arrange the code to make khaled move, right, left, up and down.





















                                        Figure 44: mBlock screen with movement
                                         blocks to arrange for Khaled’s directions.





                              Great job on your design!







          Now let’s go back to the EDP steps. It’s
          time to moveto the plan part and add
          this.                                                                                  Name:
                                                                                                 Project:
                                                                                                  Ask
                                                                                                           Imagine

                                                                                                   Plan

                                                                                                           Create
                                                                                                  Improve
                Now I Can

                Know what coding is and how it helps characters move and solve problems.       

                Use mBlock to create and play a simple maze game.                                              
                Use motion blocks to move characters forward, backward, left, and right.          

                Understand X and Y directions to guide the character through the maze.                         

                Use costumes to change how the character looks and the direction it faces.         
                Add clicking events and sensing blocks to make the game more fun.                              














                                                                                                            61]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Ms. Sara: “Look what we've built together! What do you think?”

          Adam: “It's amazing! Everyone can play!”

          Laila: “We made a playground that's fair for everyone!”

          khaled: “This is the best playground ever!”

          Ms. Sara: “What did we learn by working together?”

          Adam: “We can solve problems with the Engineering Design Process!”

          Laila: “And everyone deserves to have fun!”






























          62]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Unit Glossary




             Keyword                                           Definition


          Sidewalks           Are paths on the side of the road where people walk safely.

          Sequence            It means putting things in the right order from first to last.


          Sprite              Is a character or object in a computer game or animation.

          The X-axis          Is a line that goes side to side (like when you move left and right).


          The Y-axis          Is a line that goes up and down (like when you move up and down).




                Mission Innovate

          Design an Accessible Public Space.

          Now It’s Your Turn

          Choose a public space—like a crosswalk, park path, school gate, or bus stop—and redesign
          it to make it safe and easy for everyone to use, including people with disabilities.
          Think Critically by Answering These Questions:

            •  What makes it hard for some people to use this space right now?









            •  What changes can you add to help someone in a wheelchair, or with hearing or vision
               difficulties?









            •  How does your design help everyone move safely and independently?









            •  Can you use recycled or simple materials to build your model?










                                                                                                            63]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Project Guidelines



                                                         1



                                                      Choose a Place

                                                      Pick a public area where you think
                                                      changes could help more people access it.




                        2



                     Research

                     Learn what features make places accessible—like
                     ramps, sound signals, wide spaces, or tactile paths.



                                                    3




                                                 Design
                                                 Use creative materials to build a model that
                                                 shows your accessible design idea.




                           4




                        Present

                        Share your model and explain how it helps people
                        with different abilities use the space safely and
                        comfortably.



























          64]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Project Rubric


          What We Look For                  Super!                    Good!                   Not Yet


           Science                                                                   
           Did you think about       I said what is hard      I said one thing that  I did not say what is
           what people need?         for some people          is hard and one          hard or how to help.
                                     and how to help.         way to help.

           Technology                                                                

           Did you use smart         I used smart things      I used one smart         I did not use any
           ideas like sounds,        to help people.          idea.                    smart ideas.
           lights, or signs?

           Engineering                                                               

           Did you build a good      My model is neat         My model works           My model is messy
           model?                    and really helps         but needs a little       or does not show the
                                     people.                  fixing.                  idea.

           Art                                                                       

           Is your design            My model is fun,         My model has some  My model is plain
           creative and              colorful, and looks      color and creativity.    and needs more
           colorful?                 great.                                            work.

           Math                                                                      

           Did you think about       I used math like         I used a little math.    I did not use math in
           size and space?           size and shape in                                 my model.
                                     my model.

           Thinking                                                                  

           Did you answer the        I answered all the       I answered some of  I did not answer the
           questions?                questions with           the questions.           questions.
                                     good ideas.

           Materials                                                                 

           Did you use simple        I used old or simple     I used some helpful      I did not use helpful
           or recycled things?       things in a smart        things.                  materials.
                                     way.

           Talking                                                                   

           Did you talk about        I explained my           I explained a little.    I did not explain my
           your work?                model clearly and                                 work well.
                                     proudly.





                                                                                                            65]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[CER











                                                         i
                      Claim                                                       Reasoning





                                                  Evidence




































































          66]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[My Journal

         Add your success stories of the week






                       Week 1                                              Week 2









































                       Week 3                                              Week 4




































                                                                                                            67]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[My Journal

          Add your success stories of the week






                       Week 5                                               Week 6









































                       Week 7                                               Week 8




































          68]]></page></pages></Search>