<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="2"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[UNIT 01        [ Beginner ]                                                LESSON 01

                  Chapter 01 : Design Domain.                                           Case Scenario.







               Designing and Managing a Tech-Driven Coee Shop


                   Introduction

                   Imagine stepping into a coee shop where technology enhances every
                   aspect of the experience - from a custom-designed coee machine
                   built by you to digital ordering systems and ecient business
                   management strategies. In this project, you will act as an
                   entrepreneur tasked with designing and managing a coee shop. The
                   government has provided space for a new coee shop, but with a
                   twist: instead of purchasing an existing coee machine, you’ll design
                   and build one yourself. Why? Because designing your own machine
                   allows you to create a device that perfectly suits your shop’s unique
                   needs, incorporates innovative features, and reduces dependency on
                   pre-made, often expensive, machines. This project will integrate
                   business strategy with design, electronics, robotics, and programming
                   to build a functional coee shop model from the ground up.




                   Mission

                   Your mission is to create a protable, tech-driven coee shop. You'll
                   integrate business planning with modern technology to ensure
                   operational eciency, excellent customer service, and overall
                   protability.




                   Scenario Context


                   Who: Entrepreneurs responsible for managing their own coee shop.
                   What: Develop a business plan and incorporate innovative technology
                   into the shop’s operations.
                   Where: The space provided by the government, with potential
                   expansion to online platforms.
                   When: Simulate the process of launching a coee shop in a competitive
                   market.
                   Why: To understand how to establish a protable and operationally
                   ecient coee shop, utilizing innovative design and technology
                   solutions.








                                                          03]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Driving Question

                 How can we create a successful coee shop business using innovative
                 technology, design, and nancial planning to ensure protability and
                 customer satisfaction?


                 Objectives/Goals

                 By the end of this project, you will:

                 1.  Use the product development template to dene and document the purpose of a
                     feasibility study for starting a business

                 2.  Utilize Fusion 360 to design essential coee machine components, such as heat
                     distribution systems and water ow mechanisms.

                 3.  Understand circuit design principles for automating water pumps and push-button
                     systems in coee machines.
                 4.  Implement digital inputs/outputs and control logic for automating the water pumps using
                     Arduino.
                 5.  Design functional circuits using Arduino to control water pumps, ensuring they start/stop
                     with appropriate inputs.
                 6.  Understand the dierence between UI (User Interface) and UX (User Experience) design.

                 7.  Explain how UI/UX principles inuence the usability and engagement of a mobile app in a
                     coee shop setting.

                 8.  Use HTML to create the structure of a fully-functional coee shop website, including
                     sections like the homepage, menu, about page, and contact forms.


                 Your Challenge

                 By the end of this project, you’ll have:

                   Developed a complete business plan and feasibility study for a new coee shop, analyzing
                   market opportunities and nancial requirements.

                   Designed key components of a coee machine using Fusion 360 and created an automated
                   water pump system using Arduino.

                   Programmed Arduino circuits to control the coee machine’s water ow with push-button
                   functionality.

                   Created a mobile app or website to manage customer interactions and orders, applying
                   UI/UX design principles for a smooth user experience.
                   Presented your coee shop plan and prototype to a panel, showcasing how your business
                   can successfully operate with a combination of entrepreneurial strategy and technology.

                 Are you ready to build a coee shop model that could become the next big thing in the food
                 and beverage industry? Let’s get started!










                                                         04]]></page></pages></Search>