<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="8"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Unit




                 1






           Lesson


                4






          Spark The Challenge!


          Ramp up the Fun! DIY Spiral



          Park






                                         Ready, Set, Learn!



                                         You will be able to:

                                            •  Use ramps, shapes, and colors to build fun and safe play
                                               areas.

                                            •  Design and build a model of a spiral ramp.
                                            •  Try out different materials to see which ones are strong
                                               and safe.

                                            •  Count and compare objects used in construction projects.
                                            •  Use number lines, charts, and ordinal numbers to plan,
                                               organize, and sequence design elements.























                                                                                                            23]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Adam: “How can Khaled move all around the playground?”

          Laila: “We can make a path!”

          Khaled: “Like a ramp for my wheelchair!”

          Adam: “What if the ramp goes round and round, like a spiral?”

          Ms. Sara: “Great thinking! A spiral ramp can help wheels go up and down slowly.”

          Laila: “We can use cardboard and tape to make one.”

          Adam: “And blocks to hold it up!”

          Ms. Sara: “Yes! Let’s get our things and build a spiral ramp for the playground!”






























          24]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Let’s

            Think!



          Which ramp shape helps a wheelchair go down slowly and safely?




















                              A straight ramp                                 A spiral ramp





















                              A straight ramp                                 A steep ramp


            Explorer’s

            Toolkit




                DIY Lab

           Hello, little engineers! Today, we’re going to help Khaled who

          uses a wheelchair get down a ramp safely and nicely.
          But first—we need to find the best ramp shape and the best
          material to build it with.
















                                                                                                            25]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[You have three different ramp shapes:
















                     Spiral Ramp                         Steep Ramp                     Straight Ramp
          Let’s Try the Ramps!

          1 .  Use the same cardboard to make each ramp.

          2 .  Roll a toy ball down the ramp. Watch what happens!

          Now think about these questions:
            •   Did the ball go fast or slow?

            •   Did it roll nicely or bounce around?

            •   Did it stay safe and not fall off?
          Try all the ramps.

          Which one works best? Pick your favourite!








          Now let’s try three different materials to make the ramp and test how the wheelchair
          moves:

            •  Swimming noodles.
            •  Cardboard.

            •  Aluminium foil.

















                        Cardboard.                       Swimming noodles.                Aluminium foil.
          We’ll use each material to build our ramp and roll the ball again.

          Ask yourself:
            •  Which one helped the wheelchair roll the smoothest?




          26]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[•  Which one is strong and doesn’t bend too much?

            •  Which one felt safest?










                Screen Lessons

          Watch the video to explore and learn something new about ramps together!

                https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3COvm0TtxWg



            Assessment





                   Apprentice

          Draw a line to match the pictures in A with the words in B.
                              (A)                                                 (B)







                                                                                                   A ramp that goes down very fast











                                                                                                A ramp that goes down slowly and

                                                                                                          is easier to climb












                                                                                                A slope that helps people or things

                                                                                                          move up or down









                                                                                                            27]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Hey flriends





          Let's Wrap Up What We have Learned About Ramps!
          Ramps are simple machines that help us move things
          up and down more easily.

          They let us roll or push instead of lifting heavy things.
          We use ramps in many places like playgrounds, roads,
          and buildings to make moving easier and safer.

          A spiral ramp is just a ramp that goes around in a
          circle — fun and helpful too.
          It makes it easier to go up slowly


































                                                      Steep Ramp.


                      Builder

          You’ve already built your playground on Tinkercad—great work!

          Now it’s time to make it real.
          Your teacher will give you a cardboard grid to use as your building space.

          What to do:
          Step 1: Draw a number line from 1–12.

          Step 2: Assign each playground item a number.

          Step 3: Count how many of each item you need.
          Step 4: Decide the order to build them.



          28]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[What will you build first?









          What comes second?








          What’s third?











                      1                         2                        3                        4



                      5                         6                        7                        8




                      9                        10                        11                       12




                Figure 15: Worksheet for planning and building a playground model with numbered items.


                Showcase

          Let’s Build Our Playground!
          Now it’s time to build your playground by yourself!

            •  Start by adding the spiral ramp road.

            •  Then, add the green area.
            •  Put the accessories you made on Tinkercad.

            •  Make sure to leave some space for the other
               road and other parts of the playground.

            •  We will add more equipment later!








                                                                     Figure 16: A DIY playground model made
                                                                     with colored paper, grass mat, and a black
                                                                     spiral ramp road.



                                                                                                            29]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Great job on your design!







          Now that you're done planning, let’s go
          back to the EDP steps.
          It’s time to move to the Create part and                                               Name:
                                                                                                 Project:
          add this.                                                                               Ask
                                                                                                           Imagine

                                                                                                   Plan

                                                                                                           Create
                                                                                                  Improve

                Now I Can

                Build fun and safe play areas using ramps, shapes, and colors.                         

                Make a model of a spiral ramp.                                                         
                Choose strong and safe materials after testing them.                                   

                Count and compare items in my building project.                                        
                Plan and organize my design with number lines, charts, and order words.  


















































          30]]></page></pages></Search>