<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="2"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[UNIT 01        [ Beginner ]                                                LESSON 01

                  Chapter 01 : Design Domain.                                           Case Scenario.







                Tech Time Travellers: Designing a Next-Gen Interactive Museum


                   Introduction

                   Imagine visiting a museum where you control the experience! Instead
                   of just looking at monuments, you can interact with them and steer a
                   high-tech exhibit car that takes you through famous landmarks. The
                   city government, supported by the Ministry of Tourism, is building this
                   high-tech museum to engage residents and tourists alike. Your mission:
                   help design an interactive exhibit that integrates robotics, 3D
                   modeling, and mobile apps to make history come alive!


                   Mission

                   You are the museum tech designer! The Ministry of Tourism seeks
                   innovative ideas to attract tourists and preserve cultural history. Your
                   task is to create an interactive exhibit where visitors can control a
                   mobile museum car using their phones to navigate through replicas of
                   world-famous monuments. You'll design these monuments in 3D, build a
                   robotic car, and develop a mobile app to control it—all while boosting
                   tourism and cultural preservation.


                   Scenario Context

                   Who: The city government and the Ministry of Tourism are teaming up
                   with engineers, architects, and tech experts to create a futuristic,
                   interactive museum.
                   What: Design a mobile, interactive car that moves between exhibits,
                   allowing visitors to explore replicas of famous monuments using a
                   mobile app you’ll develop.
                   Where: The museum will be located in, a city renowned for its cultural
                   heritage, and will showcase global monuments alongside its historical
                   landmarks.
                   When: You have 8 weeks to complete the design and implementation of
                   this exhibit before the museum's grand opening.
                   Why: The goal is to attract tourists by using cutting-edge technology
                   to make cultural history engaging for tech-savvy visitors.












                                                          03]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Driving Question

                 How can we design a high-tech museum exhibit that lets visitors
                 interactively explore iconic monuments using modern technologies like
                 robotics, mobile apps, and 3D modelling?



                 Objectives/Goals

                 1.  Research world-famous monuments and their cultural signicance.


                 2.  Apply 3D modeling techniques to create digital replicas of the
                     monuments, optimizing them for 3D printing.

                 3.  Develop a mobile app that controls a museum car via Bluetooth,
                     allowing visitors to navigate through di erent exhibits.

                 4.  Build a robotic system that powers the car’s movement using
                     motors and Arduino, ensuring safe navigation between exhibits.


                 5.  Integrate mechanics, electronics, and sensors to ensure smooth
                     operation and safety within the exhibit space.

                 6.  Design a promotional website to highlight the museum’s
                     technological features and cultural focus, attracting both local and
                     international tourists.








                 Your Challenge

                 By the end of this project, you’ll have:

                   Designed 3D models of famous landmarks.
                   Built a robotic car that visitors can control.
                   Developed an app to navigate the car around the museum.
                   Created a website to promote the museum’s interactive experience.






















                                                         04]]></page></pages></Search>