<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="1"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Theme 2                                     Food Chain Adventure







                 By the end of the theme
                 By the end of the theme


                Students will be able to:
                 Students will be able to:





                           Identify the main types of muscles in the body (skeletal, smooth,
                           and cardiac) and explain their functions in movement, posture,
                           and bodily functions like breathing and digestion.

                           Describe how muscles and bones work together to facilitate
                           movement through muscle contraction and relaxation.

                           Dierentiate between voluntary and involuntary muscles,
                           providing examples of each and explaining their roles in bodily
                           control and function.


                           Discuss ways to maintain healthy muscles through exercise,
                           proper nutrition, and rest.


                           Describe the lever system in the arm and its components,
                           analyzing how dierent lever types aect range of motion and
                           force.

                           Explain biomechanical eciency in relation to arm movement,
                           understanding how joint structure impacts stability and motion.

                           Balance aesthetics and functionality when designing a prosthetic
                           hand in Tinkercad, considering both appearance and movement
                           capabilities.


                           Connect multiple servos to control various hand parts, such as the
                           elbow, wrist, and ngers, to replicate human movement.


                           Use App Inventor to create simple applications using
                           drag-and-drop coding blocks for easy app design and
                           development.

                           Add voice recognition to an app using App Inventor’s "Speech
                           Recognizer" component and build a user-friendly interface for
                           activation.










                                                          03]]></page></pages></Search>