<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="8"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Unit




                2






           Lesson


                3






          Innovators in Action


          The Gas Hunt.











                                         Ready, Set, Learn!



                                         You Need to Know

                                            •  Atoms, molecules, and simple compounds.

                                            •  Understanding that volcanic activity can release gases.
                                            •  What is a gas sensor and how to use it.

                                            •  How to create a simple table of values (rows/columns) and
                                              basic graphing skills: x-axis, y-axis, plotting points.

                                         You will be able to:

                                            •  Identify common gases found on Mars (CO₂, methane) and
                                              describe their key chemical properties.
                                            •  Explain why high levels of methane may signal volcanic
                                              activity or subsurface processes.

                                            •  Connect and set up a gas sensor with the rover system,
                                              then interpret sensor data to identify potentially
                                              hazardous gas levels.

                                            •  Plot gas concentration values on a scatter plot using
                                              provided tools (Google Sheets).






          40]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Let’s

            Think!



          How can changes in gas concentration and rising temperature levels help us detect the
          presence of a volcano on Mars?












            Explorer’s

            Toolkit




                DIY Lab

          Astronauts on Mars have detected rising temperatures and increased gas levels. Could it be
          a sign of volcanic activity? To find out, you're going to create a chemical reaction on Earth
          that mimics what might happen during a volcanic eruption on Mars!

          Let’s simulate a thermal reaction using a foamy experiment called Elephant Toothpaste!

















































                                                                                                            41]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[CER












                                                         i
                      Claim                                                       Reasoning





                                                  Evidence


            What do you think this             What did you see, feel,           How does your
            reaction tells us about            or measure? Was there             observation help explain
            detecting volcanoes?               foam? Heat?Pressure?              what might be happening
                                                                                 on Mars? Why would
                                                                                 a rover need gas and
                                                                                 temperature sensors?























































          42]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Screen Lessons

          Watch this video to learn more about how gas and temperature changes
          are related to volcanoes.
                https://www.usgs.gov/index.php/media/videos/volcano-monitoring-animation-2-gas-
                monitoring

               Dig Deeper


          Click on the link to learn more about the Martian atmosphere.
                https://marsed.asu.edu/mep/atmosphere



                                                   Hey friends!





          Let’s bring everything together.

          Mars’s atmosphere is mostly CO₂ (95%), with tiny
          amounts of methane and other gases.
            •  CO₂ is stable and cycles with the seasons (forms
               dry ice at poles, then returns as gas).

            •  Methane (CH₄) is rare and breaks down quickly,
               so sudden spikes suggest something active is
               happening.

            •  On Earth, scientists monitor gases above volcanoes to predict activity. Similar methods
               on Mars could reveal volcanic or subsurface processes.

            •  That’s why methane is so important—it could mean geological activity or even signs
               of life.



            Assessment






                   Apprentice

          Q1 (Multiple Choice):
          1 .  What makes up about %95 of Mars’s atmosphere?

            A.  Oxygen

            B.  Methane
            C.  Carbon Dioxide (CO₂)

            D.  Nitrogen






                                                                                                            43]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[2 .  What happens to methane in the Martian atmosphere over time?

            A.  It stays stable forever
            B.  It quickly breaks down due to sunlight and reactions

            C.  It turns into oxygen

            D.  It becomes dry ice
          3 .  Which of the following is a correct use of gas sensors on a Mars rover?

            A.  To measure oxygen in astronauts’ suits

            B.  To detect hazardous gases like methane or CO₂ in the atmosphere
            C.  To track the rover’s wheel speed

            D.  To measure dust levels only

          Q2 (Complete the sentence):
          Methane (CH₄) on Mars is important because ......................... .

          Q3 (Open-ended):

          If your rover’s gas sensor shows high methane levels in a certain area, what could that
          tell scientists about Mars?









                      Builder

          Engineers, get ready to hook up and program the gas sensor to check for harmful gases.
          Once it’s working, mount it on your Mars Rover to help astronauts detect signs of possible
          volcanic activity.





































          44]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Mastermind


          Improve the controller app you created earlier by adding two labels that display the
          readings from the temperature and gas sensors.






































                Showcase

          Get your rover moving and begin gathering information—follow the map to guide your
          journey.

          Explore the Terrain

          Drive your Mars Rover to at least four different spots on the Mars mat.
          Collect Data

          At each spot, use your sensors and the Serial Monitor to measure and record:

            •  Temperature (°C)
            •  Gas concentration (%)

          Write your readings from the Serial Monitor or the mobile app into the table provided
          below.


            Location on Map        Temperature (°C)           Gas Level (%)              Observations

          Point A


          Point B

          Point C


          Point D



                                                                                                            45]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Graph It in Google sheet.

          1 .  Open Google Sheets.
          2 .  Enter your data into columns (Location, Temperature, Gas Level).


          3 .  Insert a line graph or combo chart showing both temperature and gas levels.
          4 .  Label your graph:

            •  Title: “Mars Sensor Readings”

            •  X-Axis: Location
            •  Y-Axis: Temperature and Gas Level

          Answer these questions after you finish:

            •  At which location was the temperature highest?











            •  Where did you detect the most gas?











            •  Do these readings suggest there could be a volcanic area? Why or why not?











            •  What would you recommend the astronauts do next?




























          46]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Great job on your design!







          It’s time to move to the improve part and
          add this.

                                                                                                 Name:
                                                                                                 Project:
                                                                                                  Ask
                                                                                                           Imagine
                                                                                                   Plan

                                                                                                           Create
                Now I Can                                                                         Improve


                Identify the common gases on Mars, such as CO₂ and methane, and
                describe their main chemical properties.                                               
                Explain how spikes in methane levels could indicate volcanic activity
                or subsurface processes on Mars.                                                       

                Connect a gas sensor to the rover, collect data, and interpret the readings
                to detect hazardous gas levels.                                                        
                Organize gas data into a table and create a scatter plot in Google Sheets
                to visualize gas concentrations.                                                       




                Unit Glossary




                   Keyword                                           Definition


                                         The measure of heat or cold in an environment. On Mars,
          Temperature                    temperatures can range from extremely cold to mild
                                         during the day.

                                         Energy emitted as particles or electromagnetic waves.
          Radiation                      Mars has higher radiation levels than Earth due to its thin
                                         atmosphere.

                                         A type of solar radiation that can cause damage to human
          UV Radiation                   DNA and plant cells. Mars lacks a protective magnetic field
                                         like Earth’s.













                                                                                                            47]]></page></pages></Search>