<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="8"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Unit




                1






          Lesson


                1





          Spark The Challenge!



          Play for Everyone!












                                         Ready, Set, Learn!



                                         You will be able to:

                                           •  Talk about ways kids play differently and why some
                                              children may need help to play.

                                           •  Share ideas on how to make play fair and fun for everyone.

                                           •  Show kindness by thinking about what other kids might
                                              need to feel happy and included.
                                           •  Name one or two things that make a playground good for
                                              all children.

                                           •  Look at shapes, colors, and natural things like sand
                                              and plants to see how they make playgrounds fun for
                                              everyone.

                                           •  Measure and compare spaces and materials to find out
                                              which ones are safe and good for play.














           2]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[The sun was shining as

          Ms. Sara’s class arrived at
          the park for their trip. The
          students ran to the
          playground, excited to play.
          Adam and Laila laughed as

          they raced to the jungle
          gym.





























                                                                                Laila looked sad: “Khaled,

                                                                                why aren’t you playing?”

                                                                                Khaled sighed: “I want
                                                                                to… but the ramps are too
                                                                                steep, and I can’t get on the

                                                                                slide.”

                                                                                Adam looked around:
                                                                                “That’s not fair! Everyone
                                                                                should be able to play!”

                                                                                Laila nodded: “We need to
                                                                                fix this. What if we make a

                                                                                playground where everyone
                                                                                can play, even you?”

                                                                                Khaled smiled: “Really?
                                                                                That would be great!”










                                                                                                             3]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Story

            Refllection



          1 .  "How did Khaled feel when he saw other children playing on the slide?"



























                     A.  Sad                      B.  Happy                          C.  Angry

          2 .  "What is the main problem that Adam and Laila notice in the playground?"






















                   A.  The slides are                       B.  Some children can't use all the
                      too tall.                                 equipment.





















                                         C.  The swings are broken.



           4]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Let’s

            Think!



           Let’s Design a Playground!

            •  Look at the photo of the empty playground.
            •  Your teacher will give you pictures of fun things to add—like swings, slides, and trees!

            •  You can also draw your own ideas using crayons or markers. Use your imagination!

          Think about:
            •  What shapes and colors do you want to use?

            •   What natural things could make it better—like sand, water, or plants?

            •   What will make the playground fun, safe, and welcoming for all kids?
            •   Now glue on the pictures—or draw—what you think fits best!

          Helpful tips:

            •  Pick things that are soft, strong, or give shade.
            •  Think about all kids—including kids who use wheelchairs, kids who like to swing, or
               those who need a quiet spot.



























                                        Figure 1: Empty space for the playground.

            Explorer’s

            Toolkit





                DIY Lab

          Look Around the Playground!

          Use this checklist to see how easy and fun the playground is for ALL kids to play, especially
          friends who use wheelchairs or need calm spaces.




                                                                                                             5]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Playground Checklist:

          (Check the boxes when you see these things)
          What to Look For

                 Ramps for wheelchairs

                 Flat paths to walk/roll
                 Quiet space for calm time

                 Bright colors to help kids find  things

                 Swings and slides for all kids
                 Things to touch and hear

                 Shady spots to cool off
                 Easy ways to go up (ramp or stairs)







































                   Figure 2: Children playing together in a colorful playground with slides and swings.
























           6]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Let’s Think and Share!

          Use this CER Diagram to tell your ideas!


                                                      CER












                                                         i
                      Claim                                                       Reasoning





                                                  Evidence


           I think this playground              I saw .........................     It matters because
           is/ is not fair for                  (e.g. ramps, swings                 ...............................
           everyone.                            for wheelchairs)                    (e.g. all kids should

                                                                                    play and feel happy)





















































                                                                                                             7]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Screen Lessons

          Watch the video to learn about things that help all kids play at the
          playground.
                https://ai.invideo.io/watch/yPHVup1oPzE



            Assessment






                   Apprentice

          Circle the playground where some kids can't play.

















             Figure 3: Large playground         Figure 4: Playground with         Figure 5: Blind girl walking
           with blue slides and climbing       yellow and blue slides and       confidently on a tactile path in
                     structures.                      climbing bars.                   the playground.



                      Builder

          Create two paths using classroom items like books,
          blocks, or boxes:

            •  One path should be smooth and wide.

            •  One path should be bumpy or narrow.
          Use a toy car or small toy to go through both paths.

          Which path is easier for the toy to move through?








                                                                                  Figure 6: Two toy cars on
                                                                                  different tracks — one on a
                                                                                  bumpy road and the other on
                                                                                  a smooth road.











           8]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[You are doing a great
                                           job, flriends!






          Now let’s share our ideas and choose what we can
          make to help all kids play.









                Now I Can

                Talk about how kids play in different ways and why some might need help. 

                Share ideas to make play fair and fun for everyone.                                    

                Show kindness by thinking about what other kids need to feel happy and
                included.                                                                              
                Name one or two things that make a playground good for all children.                   

                Look at shapes, colors, and natural things like sand and plants to see
                how they help make playgrounds fun for everyone.                                       
                Measure and compare spaces and materials to find out which ones are
                safe and good for play.                                                                













































                                                                                                             9]]></page></pages></Search>