<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="1"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Driving Question

                 How can we create a successful co ee shop business using innovative
                 technology, design, and  nancial planning to ensure pro tability and
                 customer satisfaction?


                 Objectives/Goals

                 By the end of this project, you will:

                 1.  Use the product development template to de ne and document the purpose of a
                     feasibility study for starting a business

                 2.  Utilize Fusion 360 to design essential co ee machine components, such as heat
                     distribution systems and water  ow mechanisms.

                 3.  Understand circuit design principles for automating water pumps and push-button
                     systems in co ee machines.
                 4.  Implement digital inputs/outputs and control logic for automating the water pumps using
                     Arduino.
                 5.  Design functional circuits using Arduino to control water pumps, ensuring they start/stop
                     with appropriate inputs.
                 6.  Understand the di erence between UI (User Interface) and UX (User Experience) design.

                 7.  Explain how UI/UX principles in uence the usability and engagement of a mobile app in a
                     co ee shop setting.

                 8.  Use HTML to create the structure of a fully-functional co ee shop website, including
                     sections like the homepage, menu, about page, and contact forms.


                 Your Challenge

                 By the end of this project, you’ll have:

                   Developed a complete business plan and feasibility study for a new co ee shop, analyzing
                   market opportunities and  nancial requirements.

                   Designed key components of a co ee machine using Fusion 360 and created an automated
                   water pump system using Arduino.

                   Programmed Arduino circuits to control the co ee machine’s water  ow with push-button
                   functionality.

                   Created a mobile app or website to manage customer interactions and orders, applying
                   UI/UX design principles for a smooth user experience.
                   Presented your co ee shop plan and prototype to a panel, showcasing how your business
                   can successfully operate with a combination of entrepreneurial strategy and technology.

                 Are you ready to build a co ee shop model that could become the next big thing in the food
                 and beverage industry? Let’s get started!










                                                         04]]></page></pages></Search>