<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="4"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[UNIT 02         [ Intermediate  ]                                          LESSON 01

                  Chapter 01 : Robotics Domain.                            Measure the heart rate!






               Stepping Stone:
               Stepping Stone:



                 You need to know…                               You will be able to…


                         What sensors are and their role in             Recognise what is MAX30100 pulse
                         collecting data.                               oximeter, and how it detects heart rate.

                         Microcontrollers like Arduino and how          Understand how to connect the sensor
                         to code them.                                  to an Arduino and display the reading
                                                                        on an LCD screen.
                         How to add LCD for data display.               Write full code to control the pulse
                                                                        oximeter and display the data on both
                                                                        the screen and a connected mobile app.




              They transitioned from simple simulations to more complex models, incorporating pumps and
              controllers to mimic the heart's pumping action and the regulation of blood ow.





              Mrs. Sara:
              "Now, Let’s x the device it
              looks like the heart rate
              sensor is damaged.

              Adam: We have to replace it
              to measure our heart rate










                                                                   How do you think a sensor
               let's                                               can be used to detect
               let's
                                                                   heart rate?


            Think                                                  . ............................................................................................................
            Think
                                                                   . ............................................................................................................

                                                                   . ............................................................................................................






                                                          23]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Explore
               Explore


















                 Connect the  MAX30100 pulse oximeter
                 sensor with the arduino.

                 https://youtu.be/tmeOOL58KLM?si=RsnaRIfN
                 Exuh1Ysf




                                                                                               Scan Here!


                    WATCH IT..













                  Let’s learn more about our
                  MAX30100 pulse oximeter
                  sensor:

                  https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=
                  ciNjo1yBvTE









                  Scan Here!
















                                                          24]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Assessment Exercise









                          Focus
                          Focus




              What does a pulse oximeter sensor measure?

              A) Blood pressure.
              B) Body temperature.
              C) Heart rate and blood oxygen level.
              D) Muscle movement.

              What is the role of an LCD screen in this project?

              A) To display the heart rate reading.
              B) To power the robot.
              C) To control the robot's movements.
              D) To store the heart rate data.

              What is the rst step in building a heart rate monitor with an
              Arduino?

              A) Write the code.
              B) Connect the sensor to the Arduino.
              C) Power on the Arduino.
              D) Calibrate the sensor.








                         Practice
                          Practice




              Write full code to control the pulse oximeter and display the data
              on the screen and add bluetooth module to connect to mobile app.



















                                                          25]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Now let’s go back to our EDP paper
                                        and add this to the create part!












                    NOW I CAN..



                       Write full code to control the pulse oximeter and display the data on
                       both the screen and a connected mobile app.
                       Understand how to connect the sensor to an Arduino and display the
                       reading on an LCD screen.
                       Recognise what is MAX30100 pulse oximeter, and how it detects heart
                       rate.






















































                                                         26]]></page></pages></Search>