<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="8"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Unit




                1






           Lesson


                3






          Spark The Challenge!


          Moving on Mars.











                                         Ready, Set, Learn!



                                         You Need to Know

                                            •  How Arduino works and how to upload simple motor
                                               control codes.
                                            •  Newton’s laws of motion and how they apply to moving
                                               objects.

                                            •  That AI can help machines make decisions based on data
                                               and rules.

                                         You will be able to:

                                            •  Apply Newton’s Laws of Motion to analyze how forces
                                               affect rover movement on Mars’ rocky surface.
                                            •  Identify the types of wheels best suited for navigating
                                               Martian terrain, considering grip, size, and durability.

                                            •  Assemble the key mechanical components of a Mars rover,
                                               including its body, joints, and wheels.
                                            •  Program motors using Arduino to control how the rover
                                               moves forward, turns, and stops.

                                            •  Explore simple pathfinding strategies and simulate how
                                               the rover can make smart choices to avoid obstacles.


                                                                                                            19]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Let’s

            Think!



            •  What happens when a rover tries to move over a rocky hill on Mars?









            •  If the rover stops suddenly, what makes it keep sliding forward or tip over?








            •  How would pushing a rover on Earth feel different from pushing it on Mars?









            Explorer’s

            Toolkit




                DIY Lab



                                                  Hello friends, I am

                                                your friend lab-bot.






          As NASA engineers you must design Mars rovers with
          wheels strong enough to move across rocky, uneven
          ground. You’ll simulate this challenge by testing different
          toy cars with different types of wheels on two types of
          terrain. This will help you decide what kind of wheel
          would be best for a Mars rover.

          You have three cars:
          Car 1: Toy car with plastic or rubber wheels.

          Car 2: Homemade car with bottle cap wheels.

          Car 3: Homemade car with cardboard wheels.







          20]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Test Tracks:

          Smooth Surface (cardboard or wooden board)
          Bumpy Surface (bubble wrap, crumpled paper, or foam mat)

          The Question: Which car is most like a Mars rover and works best on a bumpy surface?











                                                      CER











                                                         i
                      Claim                                                       Reasoning





                                                  Evidence

            Which car worked best               What did you observe               Why do you think that
            on the bumpy surface?               during the test?                   car worked best? How
                                                                                   does this relate to real
                                                                                   Mars rovers?








































                                                                                                            21]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Screen Lessons

                Click on the link to learn more about Mars rover.
                https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UHEB3SRgNik


               Dig Deeper

          Read this article to learn about the first mars rover- Sojourner.
                https://spaceplace.nasa.gov/mars-sojourner/en/



                                                   Hey friends
                                                  let’s wrap up!



          How do Newton’s Laws help design Mars rovers?

          Newton’s First Law (Inertia) tells us that a rover will
          stay still unless something moves it—and once it's
          moving, it won’t stop unless another force acts on it
          (like friction or a rock). Engineers use this law to design
          rovers that stay stable and balanced even on bumpy
          surfaces.

          Newton’s Second Law (F = ma) helps scientists
          calculate how much force is needed for the rover to
          move, turn, or stop. On Mars, the gravity is lower than on Earth, so rovers need just the
          right amount of force to move without slipping or flipping over.
          Newton’s Third Law (Action & Reaction) explains how wheels push against the ground
          and the ground pushes back to move the rover forward. Engineers use this to choose
          wheels that can grip the rocky terrain without sinking into the dust.



            Assessment






                   Apprentice

          Build the circuit for the motors and Bluetooth module, to integrate it into your rover.




















          22]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Builder

          Begin assembling your rover by attaching the wheels to the 3D-printed parts from the
          previous lesson and creating your DIY chassis.






































                   Mastermind

          Build a mobile controller in MIT App Inventor that sends directional commands over
          Bluetooth to your rover. Pair the Bluetooth module with the app, then write Arduino code
          to drive the motors—move forward, turn, and stop on command.







































                                                                                                            23]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Showcase

          It’s time to make your Mars rover smarter! Add an ultrasonic sensor to help it "see"
          obstacles ahead—just like real rovers use sensors to stay safe on rocky Martian terrain.
            •  Connect the ultrasonic sensor to your rover.

            •  Using any generative AI tool write a simple program that allows the rover to detect
               obstacles in its path.
            •  If something is too close, your rover should stop or change direction.

            •  Test how your rover reacts and explore how this sensor helps it make better decisions.



































                                                   AI Challenge





          How can you improve the decision-making of your
          rover using the data from the sensor? What other
          AI-based features might be useful for real Mars
          rovers to explore more efficiently?






















          24]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Great job on
                                              your design!






          Now that you're done Let’s go back to the EDP

          steps and add this to create part.                                                     Name:
                                                                                                 Project:
                                                                                                   Ask
                                                                                                           Imagine
                                                                                                   Plan

                                                                                                            Create
                                                                                                  Improve
                Now I Can

                Apply Newton’s Laws of Motion to understand how forces affect my
                rover’s movement on Mars' rocky surface.                                               

                Identify which types of wheels are best for moving across Mars, based
                on grip, size, and durability.                                                         
                Assemble the main parts of my Mars rover, including the body, joints,
                and wheels.                                                                            

                Program the rover’s motors using Arduino to make it move forward,
                turn, and stop.                                                                        

                Explore basic pathfinding techniques and program the rover to avoid
                obstacles automatically.                                                               










































                                                                                                            25]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Unit Glossary



               Keyword                                            Definition


          Autonomous              Systems that can perform tasks or make decisions on their own
                                  without human control, like Mars rovers navigating the surface
          Systems
                                  using sensors.

                                  The force that pulls objects towards each other. Mars has only
          Gravity
                                  38% of Earth's gravity, so things weigh less on Mars.


          Newton's Laws of        Three principles explaining how objects move: inertia (objects
                                  stay at rest or in motion), force = mass × acceleration, and
          Motion
                                  action-reaction.


          Pathfinding             The process of finding a route or direction to follow, used by
                                  rovers to avoid obstacles and navigate efficiently.

                                  A drawing that represents an object in proportion to its real
          Scale Drawing
                                  size, used to model things like the rover in a manageable way.

                                  A comparison of gravitational forces between two planets.
          Gravity Ratio           Mars' gravity is only 38% of Earth's, meaning objects weigh
                                  much less on Mars.

          AI (Artificial          Technology that allows machines to make decisions based on
          Intelligence)           data, like a rover choosing paths or detecting hazards on Mars.












































          26]]></page></pages></Search>